<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loan Limits on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/loan-limits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Loan Limits on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/loan-limits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debt-to-Income Ratio in Florida: What Loan Officers Actually Calculate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/debt-to-income-ratio-mortgage-qualification-florida-loan-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/debt-to-income-ratio-mortgage-qualification-florida-loan-officers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your debt-to-income ratio (DTI) is the gatekeeper for how much home you can buy. Florida loan officers use it to decide whether your payment fits. The good news: you can often improve DTI in weeks with the right moves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-dti-measures-and-the-simple-math&#34;&gt;What DTI measures (and the simple math)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DTI is the share of your gross monthly income that goes to monthly debts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formula:&lt;/strong&gt; (Total monthly debts ÷ Gross monthly income) × 100&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jumbo Loans vs. Conforming: I Compared Both for My $825K Home Purchase and Here&#39;s What I Learned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/jumbo-loans-vs-conforming-i-compared-both-for-my-825k-home-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/jumbo-loans-vs-conforming-i-compared-both-for-my-825k-home-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started house hunting in Orange County, California in early 2024, I quickly learned that $825,000 was the baseline for single-family homes in decent neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first question:&lt;/strong&gt; Is that a jumbo loan or conforming loan?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The answer:&lt;/strong&gt; In Orange County, the 2024 conforming loan limit is $1,089,300—so my $825,000 purchase qualified as conforming, not jumbo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-2024-conforming-loan-limits&#34;&gt;Understanding the 2024 Conforming Loan Limits&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;standard-vs-high-cost-area-limits&#34;&gt;Standard vs. High-Cost Area Limits&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard conforming limit (2024):&lt;/strong&gt; $766,550 in most U.S. counties&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-nonconforming-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-nonconforming-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the difference between conforming and non-conforming loans is crucial for making the right mortgage decision in 2025. With updated FHFA loan limits and evolving market conditions, borrowers must navigate an increasingly complex landscape to secure the best financing for their specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-conforming-vs-non-conforming-loans&#34;&gt;Defining Conforming vs. Non-Conforming Loans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conforming-loans-government-backed-security&#34;&gt;Conforming Loans: Government-Backed Security&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conforming loans meet specific criteria established by the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) and are eligible for purchase by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Saved $42,000 by Understanding My County&#39;s $1.09M Conforming Limit: Jumbo vs. High-Balance Conforming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/i-saved-42000-by-understanding-my-countys-conforming-limit-jumbo-vs-high-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/i-saved-42000-by-understanding-my-countys-conforming-limit-jumbo-vs-high-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my husband and I were transferred to Seattle for work in early 2024, we started looking at homes in the Eastside suburbs—Bellevue, Redmond, Sammamish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sticker shock was real:&lt;/strong&gt; Entry-level 3-bedroom homes started at $900,000.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming from Ohio where we&amp;rsquo;d owned a nice 4-bedroom home for $320,000, we assumed a $950,000 mortgage would require jumbo financing with all the associated costs—higher rates, larger down payment, deeper reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits: What Middle Credit Score Borrowers Need to Know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) has announced the 2025 conforming loan limits, bringing exciting opportunities for middle credit score borrowers seeking safe, government-backed financing through Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-conforming-loan-limits&#34;&gt;What Are Conforming Loan Limits?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conforming loan limits represent the maximum amount you can borrow through Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac programs while maintaining government-sponsored enterprise (GSE) backing. These limits ensure loans remain within the &amp;ldquo;conforming&amp;rdquo; category, offering borrowers enhanced security and standardized terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Jumbo Loans in 2025: Loan Limits, Rates, and Qualification Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-jumbo-loans-in-2025-loan-limits-rates-and-qualification-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-jumbo-loans-in-2025-loan-limits-rates-and-qualification-strategies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The difference between &lt;strong&gt;conforming loans&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;jumbo loans&lt;/strong&gt; comes down to loan limits—conforming loans stay within FHFA maximums ($766,550 baseline for 2025, up to $1,149,825 in high-cost areas), while jumbo loans exceed these limits. This distinction affects everything: interest rates, qualification requirements, down payment expectations, and long-term costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For buyers in expensive markets or purchasing high-value properties, understanding the conforming vs jumbo boundary is essential for securing the best possible financing terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-non-conforming-how-2025-loan-limits-shape-your-conventional-mortgage-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-non-conforming-how-2025-loan-limits-shape-your-conventional-mortgage-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The distinction between &lt;strong&gt;conforming&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;non-conforming&lt;/strong&gt; loans is fundamental to understanding conventional mortgage financing. Conforming loans meet Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac standards—including staying within FHFA loan limits ($766,550 baseline for 2025, up to $1,149,825 in high-cost areas)—which allows them to be sold to these government-sponsored enterprises. Non-conforming loans either exceed these limits or fail to meet underwriting standards, requiring portfolio lending with stricter requirements and typically higher rates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding whether your loan is conforming or non-conforming affects everything: interest rates, down payment expectations, qualification requirements, and long-term affordability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional Loan Limits 2025: How New Conforming Caps Shape Affordability and Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-how-new-conforming-caps-shape-affordability-and-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-how-new-conforming-caps-shape-affordability-and-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 conventional loan limits—set annually by the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA)—determine the maximum loan amounts that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac will purchase from lenders. For 2025, the &lt;strong&gt;baseline conforming limit is $766,550&lt;/strong&gt; for single-family homes in most counties, with &lt;strong&gt;high-cost areas reaching up to $1,149,825&lt;/strong&gt;. These limits directly impact how much you can borrow at conforming rates, what homes you can afford, and whether you&amp;rsquo;ll need jumbo financing to complete your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional Loan Limits 2025: What You Need to Know Before You Shop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-complete-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-complete-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) announces new conforming loan limits for conventional mortgages. These limits determine the maximum amount you can borrow with a standard conventional loan before you cross into jumbo loan territory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 2025, the baseline conforming loan limit is &lt;strong&gt;$806,500&lt;/strong&gt; for single-family homes in most of the U.S.—up from $766,550 in 2024. But if you&amp;rsquo;re buying in a high-cost area, your limit could be significantly higher.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
