<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conventional on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/conventional/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conventional on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/conventional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Treated Our Rate Lock Like A Fire Drill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Locking a conventional rate felt less like a quiet paperwork step and more like launching a new product. The headline noise, conflicting advice from friends, and lender portal notifications created paralysis. So we treated the lock as a fire drill: three short sprints, repeatable documentation, and clear rules about who could approve changes. By Monday morning we submitted conditions, negotiated a float-down clause, and still had energy left to eat dinner like normal people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lender Fit Scorecard That Saved Our Sanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/lender-fit-scorecard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/lender-fit-scorecard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing a lender for a conventional loan can feel like speed dating with spreadsheets. Everyone says they have the best rates, the friendliest processors, and the fastest turn times. We needed a way to cut through the charm and surface the facts, so we built a lender fit scorecard. The scorecard balances quantitative metrics with soft-skill signals and has become the backbone of every referral meeting we host.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-the-categories-before-filling-in-names&#34;&gt;Build the categories before filling in names&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first mistake we made was letting lenders define the agenda. Now we list the categories before the first call: pricing transparency, communication cadence, underwriting philosophy, appraisal management, and closing flexibility. Under pricing transparency we track whether the lender includes all loan-level price adjustments up front or waits until disclosures. For underwriting philosophy we note how comfortable they are handling compensating factors if appraisals come in light.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
