<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mortgage Education on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/mortgage-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mortgage Education on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:40:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/mortgage-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building A State Resource Atlas For Mortgage Referrals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/usamortgagespecialist/blogs/state-resource-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/usamortgagespecialist/blogs/state-resource-atlas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we first floated the idea of a “state resource atlas” to our referral partners, we pictured a digital binder stuffed with regulations. Nobody was excited about another repository. The breakthrough came when we reframed the atlas as a living briefing that pairs proactive alerts with decision-ready scripts. Today, realtors, financial advisors, unions, and member organizations rely on it to keep conversations factual and brand-safe. Here’s how we built it and how you can adapt the model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Our HR Team Added a Conforming Loan Wellness Benefit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/employer-mortgage-wellness-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/employer-mortgage-wellness-benefit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our company refreshed its financial wellness program, the HR team asked employees what stressed them most. The top answer wasn’t retirement or student loans—it was figuring out how to qualify for a mortgage without getting ripped off. That insight led us to pilot a conforming loan education benefit. After six months, here’s what we learned, what employees loved, and how we measured success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-define-the-problem-accurately&#34;&gt;Step 1: Define the problem accurately&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Employees didn’t just want a “mortgage calculator.” They wanted unbiased guidance on conforming loan limits, debt-to-income ratios, middle credit scores, and when to refinance. We surveyed staff anonymously and discovered three themes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
