<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VA Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/va-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VA Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/va-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VA Loan Credit Score Requirements by Lender: Who Approves 580, 620, and 640&#43; in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-loan-credit-score-requirements-by-lender-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-loan-credit-score-requirements-by-lender-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The VA doesn&amp;rsquo;t set a minimum credit score for VA loans—eligibility depends on military service, not your FICO score. However, &lt;strong&gt;lenders&lt;/strong&gt; impose their own credit score minimums, called overlays, and these vary dramatically. Some VA specialists approve 580 scores while major banks require 640 or higher, meaning your lender choice directly affects whether you qualify.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding which lenders approve your credit profile—and how to strengthen your application if you&amp;rsquo;re borderline—can mean the difference between approval and denial, or between a competitive rate and an expensive one. This guide breaks down VA loan credit score requirements by lender type, explains how manual underwriting works for veterans with middle credit scores, and shows you which compensating factors can overcome lower scores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding VA Lenders for Deployed Service Members: Tips &amp; Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/finding-va-lenders-for-deployed-service-members-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/finding-va-lenders-for-deployed-service-members-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a home while deployed or stationed overseas presents unique challenges—time zone differences, limited communication access, deployment income documentation, and power of attorney requirements. However, thousands of active-duty service members successfully close on VA loans each year while serving abroad, and understanding which lenders specialize in deployment scenarios makes the process significantly smoother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The right VA lender understands how to verify BAH (Basic Allowance for Housing), handle overseas power of attorney, process remote document signing, and work around communication blackouts during training exercises or combat deployments. This guide explains how deployed service members can find VA lenders who specialize in military lending and avoid the delays and frustrations that come from working with lenders unfamiliar with deployment challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Cash-Out Refinance for Veterans: Options, Limits &amp; Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-for-veterans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-for-veterans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VA cash-out refinancing lets veterans and active-duty service members convert home equity into cash while maintaining VA loan benefits—no private mortgage insurance, competitive rates, and funding fee exemptions for disabled veterans. Unlike conventional cash-out refinances that cap loan-to-value at 80%, VA cash-out allows up to &lt;strong&gt;90% LTV&lt;/strong&gt; in most cases, and up to &lt;strong&gt;100% LTV&lt;/strong&gt; with certain lenders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means you can access significantly more equity than conventional or FHA cash-out options while keeping favorable VA loan terms. However, VA cash-out refinancing comes with a 2.15%-3.3% funding fee (waived for disabled veterans), and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to meet credit, income, and residual income requirements. Understanding when VA cash-out makes sense—and when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t—helps you make the right financial decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Claim VA Funding Fee Exemptions: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/how-to-claim-funding-fee-exemption-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/how-to-claim-funding-fee-exemption-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The VA funding fee costs between 1.4% and 3.6% of your loan amount depending on your down payment, loan type, and whether it&amp;rsquo;s your first VA loan use. For a $400,000 purchase with zero down, that&amp;rsquo;s $5,600 to $14,400—a substantial upfront cost that gets rolled into your loan balance and increases your monthly payment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, veterans with service-connected disabilities rated at 10% or higher are &lt;strong&gt;completely exempt&lt;/strong&gt; from the VA funding fee. Surviving spouses of veterans who died in service or from service-connected conditions are also exempt. These exemptions can save thousands of dollars, yet many eligible veterans miss out because they don&amp;rsquo;t know how to claim the exemption or fail to provide the correct documentation to lenders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Loan Entitlement Explained: How Much You Can Borrow and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-entitlement-explained-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-entitlement-explained-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VA loan entitlement confuses many veterans, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most important concepts in VA lending. Entitlement is not a dollar cap on your loan; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s the VA&amp;rsquo;s guarantee to lenders that a portion of the loan will be repaid if you default. That guarantee gives lenders confidence to offer 0% down purchase options and favorable terms to eligible veterans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding your entitlement determines how much you can borrow, whether you need a down payment, and if you can use your VA benefit more than once. Many veterans don&amp;rsquo;t realize their entitlement is reusable or that they can have multiple VA loans simultaneously under the right circumstances. This guide breaks down everything you need to know about VA entitlement in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
