<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Purchase Loan Officers - From Pre-Approval to Home Ownership on Purchase Loan Officers</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/</link><description>Recent content in Purchase Loan Officers - From Pre-Approval to Home Ownership on Purchase Loan Officers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://purchaseloanofficers.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pre-Approval vs Pre-Qualification: Why One Gets You the House and One Doesn't</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification-why-one-gets-you-the-house-and-one-doesnt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification-why-one-gets-you-the-house-and-one-doesnt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started looking for my first home three years ago, I thought getting &amp;ldquo;pre-qualified&amp;rdquo; meant I was ready to make offers. I filled out a five-minute online form, got a number, and started touring homes. Two weeks later, I found the perfect place—and my offer was rejected in favor of a buyer who had &amp;ldquo;pre-approval.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s when I learned the hard lesson: &lt;strong&gt;pre-qualification and pre-approval are not the same thing&lt;/strong&gt;, and in competitive markets, only one of them actually matters to sellers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3% Down vs 20% Down: Which Home Purchase Strategy Actually Saves You Money?</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/3-down-vs-20-down-which-home-purchase-strategy-actually-saves-you-money/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/3-down-vs-20-down-which-home-purchase-strategy-actually-saves-you-money/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For years, the conventional wisdom was simple: save 20% down to avoid PMI and get the best mortgage terms. But here&amp;rsquo;s what nobody tells you—waiting five extra years to save 20% down might cost you more money than just buying now with 3% down and paying PMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned this lesson the hard way when I spent three years religiously saving for a 20% down payment while home prices in my market rose 8% annually. By the time I had my 20% saved, the homes I was looking at cost $80,000 more—and my &amp;ldquo;savings&amp;rdquo; on PMI was wiped out by appreciation I missed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First-Time Home Buyer Programs You've Never Heard Of (But Should)</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/first-time-home-buyer-programs-youve-never-heard-of-but-should/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/first-time-home-buyer-programs-youve-never-heard-of-but-should/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started house hunting as a first-time buyer, everyone told me about FHA loans with 3.5% down. What nobody mentioned were the dozens of other programs offering grants, down payment assistance, and better loan terms than FHA—without the lifetime mortgage insurance penalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered one of these programs completely by accident when a loan officer casually mentioned &amp;ldquo;HomeReady&amp;rdquo; in passing. That single conversation saved me over $40,000 in mortgage insurance costs over the life of my loan compared to FHA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Improved My Credit Score 60 Points in 4 Months—Here's Exactly How</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/i-improved-my-credit-score-60-points-in-4-monthsheres-exactly-how/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/i-improved-my-credit-score-60-points-in-4-monthsheres-exactly-how/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Four months before I planned to apply for a mortgage, I checked my credit score and nearly gave up on buying a home. My middle credit score was 642—not terrible, but not good enough to get decent mortgage rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My loan officer told me bluntly: &amp;ldquo;At 642, you&amp;rsquo;ll pay about 1.5% more in interest than someone with a 720 score. On a $350,000 loan, that&amp;rsquo;s an extra $350 per month—$126,000 over 30 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Understanding Mortgage Rates in 2025: Why Your Rate Isn't Actually 'The Rate'</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/understanding-mortgage-rates-in-2025-why-your-rate-isnt-actually-the-rate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/understanding-mortgage-rates-in-2025-why-your-rate-isnt-actually-the-rate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started shopping for a mortgage last year, I called five different lenders on the same day to compare rates. Every single one gave me a different &amp;ldquo;rate&amp;rdquo;—ranging from 6.25% to 7.125%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was confused. Why would one lender offer me 6.25% while another quoted 7.125% for the exact same loan amount on the exact same day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is that &amp;ldquo;the rate&amp;rdquo; you see advertised or quoted isn&amp;rsquo;t actually the full story. Understanding how mortgage rates really work—APR vs interest rate, points, credits, rate locks, and pricing adjustments—is the difference between overpaying and getting the best deal possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What Nobody Tells You About Closing Costs Until You're Already Under Contract</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/what-nobody-tells-you-about-closing-costs-until-youre-already-under-contract/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/what-nobody-tells-you-about-closing-costs-until-youre-already-under-contract/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Three days before my closing, I got the final Closing Disclosure from my lender. I expected to pay around $8,000 in closing costs based on the Loan Estimate I received weeks earlier. The actual number? &lt;strong&gt;$12,347.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was stunned. Where did the extra $4,347 come from? And why didn&amp;rsquo;t anyone warn me about these costs earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After furiously Googling, calling my lender, and negotiating with vendors, I managed to reduce my closing costs by $2,100—but I still paid more than I expected. Looking back, I realize I could have saved even more if I&amp;rsquo;d known what to look for and what to negotiate from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Much House Can You Really Afford? The 28/36 Rule Explained</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/how-much-house-can-you-really-afford-the-28/36-rule-explained/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/how-much-house-can-you-really-afford-the-28/36-rule-explained/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I got pre-approved for a mortgage, my lender told me I qualified for a $450,000 home. I was thrilled—until I sat down with a spreadsheet and realized that buying a $450,000 home would leave me with $300 per month for groceries, gas, and everything else after paying my mortgage, car loan, student loans, and utilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was approved for way more house than I could comfortably afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the &lt;strong&gt;28/36 rule&lt;/strong&gt; comes in—a simple guideline that helps you figure out what you can actually afford based on your income and debts, not just what a lender will approve you for.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Move-Up Buyers: Should You Sell First or Buy First?</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/move-up-buyers-should-you-sell-first-or-buy-first/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/move-up-buyers-should-you-sell-first-or-buy-first/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I decided to move from our starter home to a larger house three years ago, we faced the classic move-up buyer dilemma: &lt;strong&gt;Should we sell our current home first, or buy our next home first?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selling first meant we&amp;rsquo;d have cash for a down payment and no dual mortgage stress—but we&amp;rsquo;d have to move twice (once to temporary housing, then to the new home) and risk losing our dream home to another buyer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shopping Multiple Lenders Saved Me $47,000—Here's How to Do It Right</title><link>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/shopping-multiple-lenders-saved-me-47000heres-how-to-do-it-right/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchaseloanofficers.com/blogs/shopping-multiple-lenders-saved-me-47000heres-how-to-do-it-right/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started shopping for a mortgage, I made the mistake most first-time buyers make: I went with the first lender who pre-approved me without comparing other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six months later, a coworker casually mentioned he got a 6.25% rate with $1,800 in lender fees on a similar loan. My rate? 6.875% with $4,200 in lender fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did the math and nearly threw up. My &amp;ldquo;convenient&amp;rdquo; decision to go with my bank without shopping around was going to cost me &lt;strong&gt;$47,000 over the life of the loan&lt;/strong&gt;—$230 per month in unnecessary interest and fees.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>