<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Draw Schedule on FHA 203(k) Mortgages</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/tags/draw-schedule/</link><description>Recent content in Draw Schedule on FHA 203(k) Mortgages</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fha203kmortgages.com/tags/draw-schedule/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Paired Credit Moves With Every FHA 203(k) Draw</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/how-i-paired-credit-moves-with-every-fha-203k-draw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/how-i-paired-credit-moves-with-every-fha-203k-draw/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) file almost derailed before demo day because I underestimated how every trip to the hardware store would show up on my credit reports. I had the cash to cover purchases, but lenders only see balances—if utilization spikes between draws, approvals wobble. I avoided disaster by aligning each credit move with the draw schedule, then documenting it inside MiddleCreditScore.com so the lender could see my logic. Here is the playbook that kept my middle score steady while the rehab charged forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>We Turned HUD Consultant Check-Ins into Weekly Office Hours</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/we-turned-hud-consultant-check-ins-into-weekly-office-hours/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:10:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/we-turned-hud-consultant-check-ins-into-weekly-office-hours/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) felt chaotic until we turned random phone calls into structured “office hours” with the HUD consultant. Every Thursday at 4:00 p.m. we hop on a 30-minute video call, camera on, scopes open. It sounds small, but since launching the ritual we have had zero surprise inspection fails, zero missing invoices, and just one change-order dispute (which we resolved live). If you’re about to start a rehab, here’s a blueprint you can copy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>