<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rate Strategy on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/rate-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rate Strategy on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/rate-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rate Locking Strategy - How Texas Loan Officers Time Your Lock for Maximum Savings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texasloanofficers/blogs/rate-locking-strategy-texas-loan-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texasloanofficers/blogs/rate-locking-strategy-texas-loan-officers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rate-locking-strategy---how-texas-loan-officers-time-your-lock-for-maximum-savings&#34;&gt;Rate Locking Strategy - How Texas Loan Officers Time Your Lock for Maximum Savings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A rate lock is a lender agreement freezing your interest rate for 30-45 days during underwriting. Once locked, daily market rate changes don&amp;rsquo;t affect your mortgage—you keep your locked rate regardless of market movement. Understanding rate locks and timing your lock strategically can save $10,000-$30,000 in total interest costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-rate-lock&#34;&gt;What Is a Rate Lock?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you apply for a mortgage, lenders quote &amp;ldquo;floating rates&amp;rdquo;—rates that change daily based on market conditions. A rate lock freezes your quoted rate for a specified period (typically 30-45 days).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Our Non-QM Term Sheet Lab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingmortgagerates/blogs/non-qm-term-sheet-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingmortgagerates/blogs/non-qm-term-sheet-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our “term sheet lab” started as a Google Doc. We needed a place to compare DSCR, bank statement, and 1099 programs without losing track of who said what. Over time the doc evolved into a structured workflow with live calculators, escalation notes, and stakeholder-ready narratives. The format matters less than the discipline; when everyone reads from the same playbook, approvals arrive faster and negotiations feel calmer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gather-the-raw-ingredients&#34;&gt;Gather the raw ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lab opens with raw data: lender name, contact, timestamp, and documentation type. We stack the quotes vertically instead of side-by-side because it forces us to read each assumption slowly. Loan amount, amortization schedule, interest-only periods, prepay language, and reserve expectations appear under each lender’s header. By the time we finish typing, we already understand which quote deserves deeper analysis and which one misread the file from the start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage Broker Rate Lock Strategies for Refinancing in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-rate-lock-strategies-refinancing-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-rate-lock-strategies-refinancing-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched a homeowner lock his refinance rate at 6.25% on Monday. By Friday, rates had dropped to 5.875%. He was stuck with the higher rate and lost $63 per month ($22,680 over the loan life) because he locked too early without understanding market timing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, another borrower floated her rate for two weeks waiting for a better entry point. Rates jumped 0.5% during that time. She ended up locking at 6.75% when she could have had 6.25%—costing her $91 monthly ($32,760 over life).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
