<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lender Selection on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/lender-selection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lender Selection on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/lender-selection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Lender Fit Scorecard That Saved Our Sanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/lender-fit-scorecard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/lender-fit-scorecard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing a lender for a conventional loan can feel like speed dating with spreadsheets. Everyone says they have the best rates, the friendliest processors, and the fastest turn times. We needed a way to cut through the charm and surface the facts, so we built a lender fit scorecard. The scorecard balances quantitative metrics with soft-skill signals and has become the backbone of every referral meeting we host.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-the-categories-before-filling-in-names&#34;&gt;Build the categories before filling in names&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first mistake we made was letting lenders define the agenda. Now we list the categories before the first call: pricing transparency, communication cadence, underwriting philosophy, appraisal management, and closing flexibility. Under pricing transparency we track whether the lender includes all loan-level price adjustments up front or waits until disclosures. For underwriting philosophy we note how comfortable they are handling compensating factors if appraisals come in light.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Mortgage Lenders: Complete 2025 Guide to Finding the Best Rates and Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/how-to-compare-mortgage-lenders-2025-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/how-to-compare-mortgage-lenders-2025-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend called me last week, excited about buying his first home. &amp;ldquo;I got pre-approved!&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;My bank offered 6.625% on a 30-year conventional loan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I asked if he&amp;rsquo;d compared rates with other lenders. Silence. Then: &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I was supposed to. I just figured my bank would give me a good deal since I&amp;rsquo;ve been with them 15 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two days later, after comparing four additional lenders, he had offers ranging from 6.625% (his bank) down to 5.875% (a mortgage broker accessing wholesale pricing). That 0.75% difference saves him $163 per month—$58,680 over the 30-year loan. All because he spent three hours comparing lenders instead of accepting the first offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
