<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VA Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/va-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VA Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/va-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide 2025: From 0% to 20% and Everything Between</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-time-homebuyer-down-payment-guide-how-much-you-really-need-to-buy&#34;&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide: How Much You Really Need to Buy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest myth keeping renters from becoming homeowners? The belief that you need 20% down to buy a house. Here&amp;rsquo;s reality: over 70% of first-time buyers put down less than 10%, and many successful buyers put down as little as 0-3.5%. Understanding your real down payment options—and how to maximize them—can help you buy years sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Loan Credit Score Requirements by Lender: Who Approves 580, 620, and 640&#43; in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-loan-credit-score-requirements-by-lender-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-loan-credit-score-requirements-by-lender-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The VA doesn&amp;rsquo;t set a minimum credit score for VA loans—eligibility depends on military service, not your FICO score. However, &lt;strong&gt;lenders&lt;/strong&gt; impose their own credit score minimums, called overlays, and these vary dramatically. Some VA specialists approve 580 scores while major banks require 640 or higher, meaning your lender choice directly affects whether you qualify.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding which lenders approve your credit profile—and how to strengthen your application if you&amp;rsquo;re borderline—can mean the difference between approval and denial, or between a competitive rate and an expensive one. This guide breaks down VA loan credit score requirements by lender type, explains how manual underwriting works for veterans with middle credit scores, and shows you which compensating factors can overcome lower scores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Loan Entitlement Explained: How Much You Can Borrow and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-entitlement-explained-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-entitlement-explained-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VA loan entitlement confuses many veterans, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most important concepts in VA lending. Entitlement is not a dollar cap on your loan; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s the VA&amp;rsquo;s guarantee to lenders that a portion of the loan will be repaid if you default. That guarantee gives lenders confidence to offer 0% down purchase options and favorable terms to eligible veterans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding your entitlement determines how much you can borrow, whether you need a down payment, and if you can use your VA benefit more than once. Many veterans don&amp;rsquo;t realize their entitlement is reusable or that they can have multiple VA loans simultaneously under the right circumstances. This guide breaks down everything you need to know about VA entitlement in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA 0% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Compared Both for My $340,000 Military Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/va-0-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-compared-both-for-my-340000-military-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/va-0-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-compared-both-for-my-340000-military-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m active duty Air Force with 8 years of service, and when I started house hunting in September 2024, I assumed my VA loan benefit was automatically the best option. Zero down payment, no PMI, favorable rates for military—what could be better than that?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I ran the actual numbers comparing VA 0% down versus conventional 5% down for my $340,000 home purchase in San Antonio, and the results surprised me. VA saved me money in some scenarios but not others, depending on how long I planned to keep the home and whether I factored in opportunity cost of the down payment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
