<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Financial Strategy on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/financial-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Financial Strategy on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/financial-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using HELOC for Debt Consolidation in 2025: When It Makes Sense vs When It&#39;s a Trap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/helocloanofficers/blogs/heloc-for-debt-consolidation-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/helocloanofficers/blogs/heloc-for-debt-consolidation-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using your home equity to consolidate high-interest debt sounds appealing—trade 18%-24% credit card rates for 8%-10% HELOC rates and save thousands in interest. But debt consolidation through HELOCs creates serious risks that financial marketers downplay: you&amp;rsquo;re converting unsecured debt into secured debt backed by your home, making strategic mistakes potentially catastrophic rather than merely expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-heloc-debt-consolidation-appeal-real-interest-savings&#34;&gt;The HELOC Debt Consolidation Appeal: Real Interest Savings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The math behind HELOC debt consolidation is undeniably compelling for borrowers carrying substantial high-interest debt. Variable HELOC rates between 8%-11% drastically undercut typical credit card APRs of 18%-24%, creating immediate monthly payment relief and long-term interest savings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Had 3.5% Mortgage Rate—Here&#39;s Why I DIDN&#39;T Use Cash-Out Refi for Debt Consolidation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefimortgage/blogs/i-had-3-5-percent-mortgage-rate-why-i-didnt-use-cash-out-refi-for-debt-consolidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefimortgage/blogs/i-had-3-5-percent-mortgage-rate-why-i-didnt-use-cash-out-refi-for-debt-consolidation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have $48,000 in high-interest credit card debt at an average 21% APR costing me $10,080/year in interest. My home has $145,000 in equity. Cash-out refinance seems like the perfect debt consolidation solution, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; At least for my situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have a 3.5% mortgage rate on $265,000 borrowed in 2020. Replacing that with a 6.75% cash-out refi to consolidate debt would cost me $67,000 more in total interest over the life of the loan compared to using a HELOC at 9.5%.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
