<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rate Strategy on Conforming Home Rates</title><link>https://conforminghomerates.com/categories/rate-strategy/</link><description>Recent content in Rate Strategy on Conforming Home Rates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:05:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conforminghomerates.com/categories/rate-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Calm-Down Calendar That Tamed My Volatile Rate Week</title><link>https://conforminghomerates.com/blogs/the-calm-down-calendar-that-tamed-my-volatile-rate-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:05:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomerates.com/blogs/the-calm-down-calendar-that-tamed-my-volatile-rate-week/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday, the bond market woke up cranky and my floating conforming rate followed suit. We were two weeks from closing, juggling inspection repairs, and still waiting on the last employment verification. Watching pricing alerts pop up every hour felt like standing on a dock while waves crashed from every direction. Instead of doom-scrolling, I built what I now call my “calm-down calendar”—a living schedule that organized every conversation, document, and decision against the exact thresholds that would trigger a lock. The calendar turned five chaotic days into a manageable sprint. Here is how it unfolded.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Saturday Points-vs-Credits War Room</title><link>https://conforminghomerates.com/blogs/my-saturday-points-vs-credits-war-room/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:50:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomerates.com/blogs/my-saturday-points-vs-credits-war-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender dumped three shiny quotes into my inbox, each offer mixed points, credits, and lock periods differently. I am the spreadsheet-loving member of our household, so I spent a full Saturday turning those quotes into a points-vs-credits war room. The goal was simple: understand the true cost of each structure before locking, then explain the decision to my spouse and financial coach without jargon. Here is the framework that worked and how you can plug in your numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Built a Rate Lock Ladder Before Choosing a Lender</title><link>https://conforminghomerates.com/blogs/i-built-a-rate-lock-ladder-before-choosing-a-lender/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomerates.com/blogs/i-built-a-rate-lock-ladder-before-choosing-a-lender/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I used to assume the lowest quoted rate wins. Then I watched a lender reprice three times in one week, wiping out every savings estimate I had shared with my spouse. I promised our family I would never stumble through rate shopping again. This fall, I built a rate lock ladder—a structured quick-hit process that let me compare five conforming lenders, assign lock windows, and negotiate with facts instead of adrenaline. Here is how the 48-hour sprint unfolded and how you can copy it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>