<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FHA Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/fha-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FHA Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/fha-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conventional vs. FHA Mortgages - Texas Homebuyer Comparison Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mortgagebrokerstx/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-mortgages-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mortgagebrokerstx/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-mortgages-texas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;conventional-vs-fha-mortgages---texas-homebuyer-comparison-guide&#34;&gt;Conventional vs. FHA Mortgages - Texas Homebuyer Comparison Guide&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Texas homebuyers typically choose between conventional mortgages and FHA loans. Each loan type has different down payment requirements, credit score minimums, interest rates, and insurance costs. Understanding the differences helps you select the right loan program with your mortgage broker.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conventional-mortgages-lower-rates-for-qualified-borrowers&#34;&gt;Conventional Mortgages: Lower Rates for Qualified Borrowers&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conventional mortgages are loans that conform to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac standards—not government-insured like FHA, VA, or USDA loans. Conventional mortgages typically offer lower interest rates when borrowers have strong credit, larger down payments, and steady income.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs Conventional Loans in Florida: Choosing the Right Program for Your Situation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-in-florida-choosing-the-right-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-in-florida-choosing-the-right-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing between FHA and conventional loans in Florida significantly impacts your monthly payment, total costs, and qualification path. Understanding key differences helps you select the program that best fits your financial situation and long-term goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fha-loans-overview&#34;&gt;FHA Loans: Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What FHA Loans Are:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;FHA (Federal Housing Administration) insured loans are backed by the federal government, meaning the government guarantees the lender against losses if you default.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who FHA Loans Serve:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First-time homebuyers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Borrowers with lower credit scores (down to 580)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Buyers with limited down payment savings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Borrowers recovering from past credit issues&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conventional-loans-overview&#34;&gt;Conventional Loans: Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Conventional Loans Are:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Conventional loans are NOT government-backed. The lender holds all risk and must sell loans to Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac to recover capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA 203(k) Renovation Loans 2025: Finance Purchase and Repairs in One Government-Backed Mortgage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-203k-renovation-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-203k-renovation-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most first-time buyers don&amp;rsquo;t realize: you can buy a house that doesn&amp;rsquo;t qualify for standard financing, get money to fix it up, and finance everything in a single FHA-insured mortgage with just 3.5% down. The FHA 203(k) renovation loan is one of the most powerful yet underutilized tools for building wealth through real estate—especially for buyers with middle credit scores who can&amp;rsquo;t access conventional renovation financing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me show you exactly how 203(k) loans work, what renovations qualify, and how to use them strategically to buy properties other buyers can&amp;rsquo;t touch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs. Subprime Conventional Loans: Which Is Better for Bad Credit in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/fha-vs-subprime-conventional-loans-bad-credit-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/fha-vs-subprime-conventional-loans-bad-credit-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Borrowers with bad credit (580-660 scores) face a choice between FHA loans and subprime conventional financing. FHA allows lower credit scores (500+) and smaller down payments (3.5-10%), but requires mortgage insurance for the life of the loan on 3.5% down purchases. Subprime conventional loans start at 620 credit scores and require larger down payments (10-20%), but mortgage insurance can be removed once you reach 20% equity. Understanding which option costs less over time and fits your financial situation determines whether you save or waste thousands of dollars in unnecessary fees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Long After Bankruptcy Can You Get a Mortgage? 2025 Waiting Periods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/how-long-after-bankruptcy-can-you-get-mortgage-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/how-long-after-bankruptcy-can-you-get-mortgage-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bankruptcy devastates your credit score and makes traditional mortgage approval impossible immediately after discharge. However, waiting periods are shorter than most people realize—FHA requires only 2 years after Chapter 7 bankruptcy, and some non-QM lenders approve as soon as 12 months post-discharge with compensating factors. Understanding the specific waiting periods for each loan type, how to rebuild credit strategically during the waiting period, and which lenders approve post-bankruptcy borrowers helps you return to homeownership faster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA Loan Down Payment Requirements 2025: 3.5% Minimum, Gift Funds, and Smart Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-down-payment-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-down-payment-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what makes FHA loans revolutionary for first-time buyers: you can become a homeowner with just 3.5% down payment if your credit score is 580 or higher. But there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to the story—understanding down payment sources, gift fund rules, and strategic planning can help you buy even sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me walk you through everything you need to know about FHA down payments, from minimum requirements to creative strategies that minimize your out-of-pocket costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manual Underwriting Explained: How Bad Credit Borrowers Get Approved</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/manual-underwriting-explained-bad-credit-approval-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/manual-underwriting-explained-bad-credit-approval-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Automated underwriting systems like Desktop Underwriter (Fannie Mae) and Loan Prospector (Freddie Mac) reject most bad credit applications instantly based on credit scores alone. Manual underwriting removes the automated system and assigns a human underwriter to review your full financial profile—income stability, payment history, compensating factors, and reasons for past credit issues. This process allows approval for borrowers automated systems deny, making it the primary path to homeownership for consumers with credit scores below 620.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA Mortgage Insurance Explained: Costs, Removal Options, and When It&#39;s Worth Paying</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-mortgage-insurance-explained-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-mortgage-insurance-explained-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the elephant in the room with FHA loans: mortgage insurance. It&amp;rsquo;s the cost that makes borrowers nervous and the reason some people avoid FHA financing altogether. But here&amp;rsquo;s what most people miss—understanding how FHA mortgage insurance actually works can help you decide if it&amp;rsquo;s a smart trade-off for accessing homeownership years earlier than conventional financing would allow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll break down exactly what you pay, when it can be removed, and how to calculate whether FHA insurance costs make sense for your situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should You Pay Off Collections Before Applying for a Mortgage?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/should-you-pay-off-collections-before-mortgage-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/should-you-pay-off-collections-before-mortgage-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Collections on your credit report can tank your score and complicate mortgage approval, but paying them off is not always the right move. In some cases, paying old collections actually lowers your credit score temporarily by resetting the &amp;ldquo;date of last activity,&amp;rdquo; making the negative item look recent instead of aged. Understanding FHA collection rules, how different lenders treat collections, and when strategic non-payment makes sense can mean the difference between approval and denial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs Conventional Loans for First-Time Buyers 2025: Which Saves You More Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-first-time-buyers-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-first-time-buyers-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fha-vs-conventional-loans-the-ultimate-first-time-buyer-decision-guide&#34;&gt;FHA vs Conventional Loans: The Ultimate First-Time Buyer Decision Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask ten first-time buyers which loan type they should choose, and eight will guess wrong. That&amp;rsquo;s because the FHA versus conventional decision isn&amp;rsquo;t about which is universally better—it&amp;rsquo;s about which costs less money over your specific ownership period given your credit score, down payment amount, and how long you plan to keep the loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most buyers make this choice based on down payment requirements alone, completely ignoring mortgage insurance costs that can differ by $30,000-$50,000 over the loan life. Let me show you exactly how to analyze both options so you choose the loan type that maximizes your financial position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA Loan Credit Score Requirements 2025: Complete Guide to Minimum Scores and Approval Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-credit-score-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-credit-score-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most first-time buyers don&amp;rsquo;t realize: FHA loans accept credit scores that would get you laughed out of a conventional lender&amp;rsquo;s office. But there&amp;rsquo;s a catch—understanding the difference between official FHA minimums and actual lender requirements can mean the difference between approval and rejection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me break down exactly how credit scores work with FHA financing, what minimums really matter, and proven strategies to maximize your approval odds even with credit challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Mortgage with a 500-579 Credit Score in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/how-to-get-mortgage-with-500-579-credit-score-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/how-to-get-mortgage-with-500-579-credit-score-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 500-579 credit score puts you in the &amp;ldquo;very poor&amp;rdquo; credit range according to FICO standards, and most lenders will reject your mortgage application automatically. However, FHA loans allow 500-579 scores with a 10% down payment and manual underwriting—meaning human review of your full financial picture instead of automated rejection. Thousands of borrowers with scores in this range get approved every year by working with bad credit specialists who know which FHA lenders accept manual underwriting and how to present compensating factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide 2025: From 0% to 20% and Everything Between</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-time-homebuyer-down-payment-guide-how-much-you-really-need-to-buy&#34;&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide: How Much You Really Need to Buy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest myth keeping renters from becoming homeowners? The belief that you need 20% down to buy a house. Here&amp;rsquo;s reality: over 70% of first-time buyers put down less than 10%, and many successful buyers put down as little as 0-3.5%. Understanding your real down payment options—and how to maximize them—can help you buy years sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer Credit Score Requirements 2025: Minimum Scores for Every Loan Type</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-credit-score-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-credit-score-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-time-homebuyer-credit-score-requirements-what-you-really-need-to-qualify&#34;&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Credit Score Requirements: What You Really Need to Qualify&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what stops most first-time buyers from even trying: they assume perfect credit is required to buy a home. The truth? You can qualify for a government-backed mortgage with a credit score that would get you rejected for a decent credit card. But understanding the difference between official minimums and real-world lender requirements is crucial for setting realistic timelines and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. FHA Loans in 2025: Key Differences, Credit Requirements, and Loan Limits Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When comparing &lt;strong&gt;conforming loans&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;FHA loans&lt;/strong&gt; in 2025, the biggest differences come down to credit requirements, down payment flexibility, loan limits, and long-term costs. Conforming loans (backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac) offer better rates and lower lifetime costs for borrowers with strong credit, while FHA loans (insured by the Federal Housing Administration) provide easier qualification for borrowers with lower credit scores and smaller down payments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding which loan type fits your financial profile helps you save money, qualify faster, and avoid unnecessary costs over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional vs. FHA Loans: Which One Actually Saves You Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-loans-cost-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-loans-cost-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re deciding between a conventional loan and an FHA loan, most people focus on the down payment requirement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conventional: 3-5% down&lt;br&gt;&#xA;FHA: 3.5% down&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They look pretty similar, right? So why not just go with FHA since it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;easier to qualify&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not so fast. The down payment is just one piece of the puzzle. When you factor in mortgage insurance, credit score impacts, and long-term costs, conventional loans often come out ahead—even for borrowers with less-than-perfect credit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Waited 4 Months to Improve My Credit 38 Points - Saved $4,200 on My First Home Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started seriously looking at homes in March 2024, I was ready to apply for a mortgage immediately. I had saved $18,000 for down payment on a $285,000 home, my debt-to-income ratio was solid at 38%, and I assumed my credit score would be &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I checked my actual middle credit score through my lender&amp;rsquo;s pre-qualification: 657. Not terrible, but my loan officer explained I was sitting right at the edge between two different rate tiers—and waiting a few months to improve my credit could save me thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA 3.5% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Ran the Numbers for My $310,000 Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/fha-3-5-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/fha-3-5-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent three months comparing FHA and conventional loan options before purchasing my first home in August 2024. Every article I read said &amp;ldquo;FHA is for low credit, conventional is for high credit,&amp;rdquo; but with 668 credit score, I qualified for both programs—and the decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the actual math I ran on my $310,000 home purchase, comparing FHA 3.5% down versus conventional 5% down, including all the hidden costs nobody talks about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Got Denied for Conventional at 652 Credit - FHA Approved Me in 6 Days with Same Income</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-got-denied-for-conventional-at-652-credit-fha-approved-me-in-6-days-with-same-income/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-got-denied-for-conventional-at-652-credit-fha-approved-me-in-6-days-with-same-income/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got my first mortgage denial letter on a Tuesday afternoon in June 2024. After three weeks of document submission, income verification, and waiting for underwriting review, the conventional lender denied my application for a $295,000 purchase loan citing &amp;ldquo;insufficient credit history and credit score below minimum threshold for program guidelines.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had 652 credit, $32,000 saved for down payment (10% down plus closing costs), stable $72,000 annual income, and debt-to-income ratio under 35%. On paper, I thought I was a strong borrower. The denial was crushing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Used My Parents&#39; Gift Funds for 100% of My Down Payment - Here&#39;s the Documentation Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-used-my-parents-gift-funds-for-100-percent-of-my-down-payment-heres-the-documentation-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-used-my-parents-gift-funds-for-100-percent-of-my-down-payment-heres-the-documentation-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I closed on my first home in October 2024 using gift funds from my parents for 100% of my down payment and most of my closing costs. Total gift amount: $14,500. My personal cash contribution: $1,200.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I first told my loan officer I planned to use gift funds, she said &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s fine, we just need a gift letter.&amp;rdquo; I thought it would be simple—my parents write a letter saying they&amp;rsquo;re giving me money, transfer the funds, and we&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional 3% Down with PMI vs. FHA 3.5% Down - I Chose Conventional and Saved $8,400</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/conventional-3-percent-down-with-pmi-vs-fha-3-5-percent-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/conventional-3-percent-down-with-pmi-vs-fha-3-5-percent-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my home search in April 2024, I assumed FHA was my only option for minimal down payment. I had saved $11,500 and wanted to buy a $325,000 home—which meant 3.5% down ($11,375) would barely work with FHA, leaving me just $125 for closing costs and emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then my loan officer mentioned conventional 3% down programs. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even realized conventional allowed less than 5% down. After running the numbers comparing FHA 3.5% versus conventional 3%, I chose conventional despite it costing $64 more per month initially—because PMI removal in year 6 would save me $8,400 over 6-10 years compared to FHA&amp;rsquo;s permanent mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
