<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refinance Rates on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/refinance-rates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refinance Rates on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/refinance-rates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Get the Best Refinance Rates in 2025: Insider Strategies to Save Thousands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refinanceloanofficers/blogs/best-refinance-rates-strategies-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refinanceloanofficers/blogs/best-refinance-rates-strategies-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the secret lenders don&amp;rsquo;t want you to know: advertised refinance rates mean almost nothing for your actual cost. Two borrowers refinancing identical loan amounts on the same day can get rates that differ by 0.5-1%, costing one of them $30,000-60,000 more over the loan life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The difference? One borrower understood how refinance pricing works and used that knowledge to negotiate ruthlessly. The other accepted the first offer from their current lender without shopping around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mortgage Brokers Find Better Refinance Rates Than Banks in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/how-brokers-find-better-refinance-rates-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/how-brokers-find-better-refinance-rates-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most homeowners refinancing their mortgage don&amp;rsquo;t realize: the bank offering you 6.5% would give a mortgage broker 6.125% on the exact same loan. That 0.375% difference costs you over $20,000 on a $300,000 refinance over 30 years—money that stays in your pocket when you use a broker instead of going direct.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason for this pricing gap is simple: brokers access wholesale lender channels that offer better rates than retail bank divisions. Let me show you exactly how this works and why refinancing through a broker beats going direct to your bank in almost every scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
