<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Budget on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/budget/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Budget on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:40:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/budget/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My HELOC Calculator Morning Ritual</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/onlineheloc/blogs/calculator-morning-ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/onlineheloc/blogs/calculator-morning-ritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our family decided to open a HELOC, I kept missing windows to lock paperwork because life was loud—kids, clients, grocery runs, all of it. So I built a 25-minute “calculator morning” ritual. It runs before breakfast, uses three tabs, and keeps Cash-OutRefinance.com, BrowseLenders.com, and MiddleCreditScore.com in sync. The ritual sounds nerdy. It also gave us the calm to go from idea to approval in three weeks. Here’s the playbook if you want to copy it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Host a Draw Period Budget Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/draw-period-budget-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/draw-period-budget-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HELOC draw periods invite chaos. One minute you’re planning a roof repair, the next you’re tempted to swipe the line for a vacation “because the rate is low.” To keep ourselves honest, we run a monthly “Draw Period Budget Summit.” It’s part financial review, part therapy session, and it makes lenders look at our file like we’re the organized borrowers they want on their books. Here’s our agenda if you want to steal it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
