<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Equity Calculators on Cash-Out Refinance Calculators</title><link>https://cashoutrefinancecalculators.com/tags/equity-calculators/</link><description>Recent content in Equity Calculators on Cash-Out Refinance Calculators</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cashoutrefinancecalculators.com/tags/equity-calculators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Ran 4 Equity Release Simulations Before Locking—Here’s the Checklist</title><link>https://cashoutrefinancecalculators.com/blogs/i-ran-4-equity-release-simulations-before-lockingheres-the-checklist/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashoutrefinancecalculators.com/blogs/i-ran-4-equity-release-simulations-before-lockingheres-the-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When my contractor handed me a $112,000 estimate for structural repairs and a kitchen rebuild, I refused to sign anything until I understood how the project would impact my mortgage. Instead of guessing, I ran four equity release simulations that exposed every variable—available funds, payment jump, breakeven timeline, and reinvestment options. The numbers kept me calm when interest rates moved and let me negotiate with lenders like a pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-equity-availability-starts-with-realistic-valuation"&gt;1. Equity availability starts with realistic valuation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many borrowers plug the Zestimate into a calculator and call it a day. I pulled comparable sales on my block, averaged the last three closings, and applied a conservative 3% haircut in case the appraiser flagged my unfinished basement. My existing balance sat at $398,200. The cash-out calculator confirmed I could take the loan to 80% of the projected $710,000 value, yielding a gross loan amount of $568,000. After subtracting payoff, closing costs, and two months of reserves, I was left with $148,500 in net proceeds—more than enough for construction plus contingency. The calculator also flagged that the appraised value needed to land above $692,000 to keep the plan intact, which informed my staging budget.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>