<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conventional Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/conventional-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conventional Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/conventional-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conventional vs. FHA Mortgages - Texas Homebuyer Comparison Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mortgagebrokerstx/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-mortgages-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mortgagebrokerstx/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-mortgages-texas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;conventional-vs-fha-mortgages---texas-homebuyer-comparison-guide&#34;&gt;Conventional vs. FHA Mortgages - Texas Homebuyer Comparison Guide&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Texas homebuyers typically choose between conventional mortgages and FHA loans. Each loan type has different down payment requirements, credit score minimums, interest rates, and insurance costs. Understanding the differences helps you select the right loan program with your mortgage broker.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conventional-mortgages-lower-rates-for-qualified-borrowers&#34;&gt;Conventional Mortgages: Lower Rates for Qualified Borrowers&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conventional mortgages are loans that conform to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac standards—not government-insured like FHA, VA, or USDA loans. Conventional mortgages typically offer lower interest rates when borrowers have strong credit, larger down payments, and steady income.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs Conventional Loans in Florida: Choosing the Right Program for Your Situation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-in-florida-choosing-the-right-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-in-florida-choosing-the-right-program/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing between FHA and conventional loans in Florida significantly impacts your monthly payment, total costs, and qualification path. Understanding key differences helps you select the program that best fits your financial situation and long-term goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fha-loans-overview&#34;&gt;FHA Loans: Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What FHA Loans Are:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;FHA (Federal Housing Administration) insured loans are backed by the federal government, meaning the government guarantees the lender against losses if you default.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who FHA Loans Serve:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First-time homebuyers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Borrowers with lower credit scores (down to 580)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Buyers with limited down payment savings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Borrowers recovering from past credit issues&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conventional-loans-overview&#34;&gt;Conventional Loans: Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Conventional Loans Are:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Conventional loans are NOT government-backed. The lender holds all risk and must sell loans to Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac to recover capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refinancing with a Mortgage Broker: When It Makes Sense in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/refinancing-with-broker-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/refinancing-with-broker-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Refinancing your conventional mortgage through a broker instead of your current lender can save tens of thousands—but only if you understand when broker value outweighs convenience. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to decide whether to refinance with a broker in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-refinance-through-a-broker-vs-your-current-lender&#34;&gt;Why Refinance Through a Broker vs. Your Current Lender?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your current lender wants to keep your business. They&amp;rsquo;ll make refinancing easy—but &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean &amp;ldquo;cheapest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current lender advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Streamlined process (they already have your information)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fast approvals (no new appraisal required in some cases)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relationship discounts (maybe)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current lender disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional Loan Pre-Approval: How Brokers Get You Approved Faster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/fast-pre-approval-brokers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/fast-pre-approval-brokers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In competitive housing markets, pre-approval speed determines whether you win or lose bidding wars. Mortgage brokers accelerate pre-approvals through lender relationships, documentation expertise, and underwriting knowledge that direct lenders can&amp;rsquo;t match.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-qualification-vs-pre-approval-critical-difference&#34;&gt;Pre-Qualification vs. Pre-Approval: Critical Difference&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-qualification&lt;/strong&gt;: Informal estimate based on self-reported information. Carries no weight with sellers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-approval&lt;/strong&gt;: Verified income, assets, and credit with conditional lender commitment. Sellers take these seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broker advantage&lt;/strong&gt;: Brokers issue pre-approvals backed by actual lender underwriting, not informal estimates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Costs of Going Direct vs. Using a Mortgage Broker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/hidden-costs-direct-vs-broker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/hidden-costs-direct-vs-broker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why pay a broker when I can go directly to my bank?&amp;rdquo; This common question overlooks hidden costs that often make direct lending more expensive. Here&amp;rsquo;s what borrowers don&amp;rsquo;t see when they bypass mortgage brokers for conventional loans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hidden-cost-1-retail-rate-markup&#34;&gt;Hidden Cost #1: Retail Rate Markup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Direct lenders add markup to base rates to cover branch overhead, advertising budgets, and shareholder profits. You&amp;rsquo;re paying for:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Physical branch locations nationwide&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TV and digital advertising campaigns&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Customer service call centers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Corporate profit margins&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markup range&lt;/strong&gt;: 0.125% to 0.375% above wholesale pricing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Credit Scores Impact Broker-Negotiated Mortgage Rates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/credit-score-broker-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/credit-score-broker-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your credit score determines more than approval—it directly impacts the interest rate your mortgage broker can negotiate. Understanding credit tier pricing helps you maximize broker value and potentially save tens of thousands on conventional loans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;credit-tier-breakdown-what-brokers-see&#34;&gt;Credit Tier Breakdown: What Brokers See&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mortgage brokers receive rate sheets from lenders showing pricing adjustments based on credit score bands. These aren&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary—they reflect default risk statistics compiled over decades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typical conventional loan credit tiers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Employed? Why You Need a Mortgage Broker for Conventional Loans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/self-employed-mortgage-brokers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/self-employed-mortgage-brokers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Self-employed borrowers know the frustration: great income on paper, but mortgage applications that confuse traditional lenders. You&amp;rsquo;re not alone—30%+ of mortgage applicants are self-employed, and standard bank underwriting often fails them. Here&amp;rsquo;s why mortgage brokers are essential for freelancers, contractors, and business owners seeking conventional loans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-self-employed-mortgage-challenge&#34;&gt;The Self-Employed Mortgage Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditional lenders use W-2 income for qualification. Self-employed income involves tax returns with write-offs, business expenses, and fluctuating revenue—documentation that confuses automated underwriting systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs. Subprime Conventional Loans: Which Is Better for Bad Credit in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/fha-vs-subprime-conventional-loans-bad-credit-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/fha-vs-subprime-conventional-loans-bad-credit-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Borrowers with bad credit (580-660 scores) face a choice between FHA loans and subprime conventional financing. FHA allows lower credit scores (500+) and smaller down payments (3.5-10%), but requires mortgage insurance for the life of the loan on 3.5% down purchases. Subprime conventional loans start at 620 credit scores and require larger down payments (10-20%), but mortgage insurance can be removed once you reach 20% equity. Understanding which option costs less over time and fits your financial situation determines whether you save or waste thousands of dollars in unnecessary fees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Your Middle Credit Score Impacts Conventional Mortgage Rates in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/middle-credit-score-rate-impact-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/middle-credit-score-rate-impact-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your credit score is the single most influential factor in determining your conventional mortgage rate, and understanding how middle credit scores (620-679) affect pricing can save you tens of thousands of dollars over your loan&amp;rsquo;s lifetime. This comprehensive analysis reveals the exact impact of middle credit scores on 2025 conventional mortgage rates and strategies to optimize your position.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-credit-score-rate-pricing&#34;&gt;Understanding Credit Score Rate Pricing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-credit-score-pricing-matrix&#34;&gt;The Credit Score Pricing Matrix&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conventional mortgages use risk-based pricing where your credit score directly correlates to your interest rate. Here&amp;rsquo;s how middle credit scores stack up in 2025:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Negotiation Tactics Mortgage Brokers Use to Lower Your Rate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-negotiation-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-negotiation-tactics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mortgage brokers don&amp;rsquo;t just compare lenders—they actively negotiate on your behalf to secure lower rates and reduce fees. Here are five insider tactics experienced brokers use to save you thousands on conventional loans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tactic-1-volume-based-rate-discounts&#34;&gt;Tactic 1: Volume-Based Rate Discounts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brokers who close dozens of loans monthly with the same lenders earn preferred pricing tiers. Lenders offer rate discounts to high-volume brokers because they bring consistent business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it works:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Standard broker: 7.0% rate, 1.5% origination&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High-volume broker: 6.75% rate, 1.0% origination&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your savings on $400,000 loan&lt;/strong&gt;: $12,000 over 5 years plus $2,000 lower closing costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer&#39;s Guide to Working with Mortgage Brokers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/first-time-buyer-broker-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/first-time-buyer-broker-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying your first home is overwhelming enough without navigating complex mortgage options alone. Mortgage brokers simplify the process by comparing lenders, explaining loan terms, and securing competitive rates on your behalf. Here&amp;rsquo;s everything first-time buyers need to know about working with brokers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-a-mortgage-broker-actually-do&#34;&gt;What Does a Mortgage Broker Actually Do?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of a mortgage broker as your personal loan shopping assistant. Instead of you applying to five banks individually (each pulling your credit), your broker submits one application and receives competing offers from their network of 20-50 lenders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Questions to Ask Your Mortgage Broker Before Choosing One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/mortgage-broker-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/mortgage-broker-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not all mortgage brokers offer the same value, expertise, or lender access. Asking the right questions upfront ensures you partner with a broker who delivers competitive rates, transparent service, and expert guidance. Here are 10 essential questions every homebuyer should ask.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-how-many-lenders-do-you-work-with&#34;&gt;1. How Many Lenders Do You Work With?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters&lt;/strong&gt;: More lender relationships mean more rate options. A broker with 10 lenders can&amp;rsquo;t compete with one who has 40+.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs Conventional Loans for First-Time Buyers 2025: Which Saves You More Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-first-time-buyers-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-first-time-buyers-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fha-vs-conventional-loans-the-ultimate-first-time-buyer-decision-guide&#34;&gt;FHA vs Conventional Loans: The Ultimate First-Time Buyer Decision Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask ten first-time buyers which loan type they should choose, and eight will guess wrong. That&amp;rsquo;s because the FHA versus conventional decision isn&amp;rsquo;t about which is universally better—it&amp;rsquo;s about which costs less money over your specific ownership period given your credit score, down payment amount, and how long you plan to keep the loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most buyers make this choice based on down payment requirements alone, completely ignoring mortgage insurance costs that can differ by $30,000-$50,000 over the loan life. Let me show you exactly how to analyze both options so you choose the loan type that maximizes your financial position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage Broker vs. Direct Lender: Which Saves You More Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-vs-direct-lender/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-vs-direct-lender/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Should you work with a mortgage broker or apply directly to a bank? This decision impacts your interest rate, closing costs, and overall borrowing experience. Let&amp;rsquo;s break down the facts so you can choose the right path for your conventional loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-mortgage-broker&#34;&gt;What Is a Mortgage Broker?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A mortgage broker is a licensed professional who acts as an intermediary between you and multiple lenders. Brokers don&amp;rsquo;t lend money themselves—they compare loan offers from their network of banks, credit unions, and mortgage companies to find your best match.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mortgage Brokers Save You Money: 5 Ways Brokers Cut Costs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/how-mortgage-brokers-save-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/how-mortgage-brokers-save-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Licensed mortgage brokers aren&amp;rsquo;t just intermediaries—they&amp;rsquo;re financial advocates who can save you thousands on your conventional mortgage. Here&amp;rsquo;s exactly how brokers deliver real cost savings that direct lenders simply can&amp;rsquo;t match.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-multi-lender-rate-comparison&#34;&gt;1. Multi-Lender Rate Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mortgage brokers access wholesale rate sheets from dozens of lenders simultaneously. Instead of applying to three banks individually (triggering multiple credit pulls), your broker submits one application and receives competing offers. This competition drives rates down—often by 0.125% to 0.375%, saving $15,000-$45,000 over a 30-year loan on a $400,000 mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer Credit Score Requirements 2025: Minimum Scores for Every Loan Type</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-credit-score-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-credit-score-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-time-homebuyer-credit-score-requirements-what-you-really-need-to-qualify&#34;&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Credit Score Requirements: What You Really Need to Qualify&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what stops most first-time buyers from even trying: they assume perfect credit is required to buy a home. The truth? You can qualify for a government-backed mortgage with a credit score that would get you rejected for a decent credit card. But understanding the difference between official minimums and real-world lender requirements is crucial for setting realistic timelines and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Credit Score Do I Actually Need for a Conventional Loan in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/what-credit-score-do-i-need-for-conventional-loan-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/what-credit-score-do-i-need-for-conventional-loan-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about buying a home or refinancing with a conventional loan, one of the first questions you&amp;rsquo;ll ask is: &amp;ldquo;What credit score do I need?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The quick answer most lenders will give you is 620. But that&amp;rsquo;s only part of the story, and understanding the full picture could save you thousands of dollars over the life of your loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-minimum-isnt-the-goal&#34;&gt;The Minimum Isn&amp;rsquo;t the Goal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, 620 is typically the minimum credit score for conventional loan approval. But here&amp;rsquo;s what most people don&amp;rsquo;t realize: qualifying at 620 and getting approved with favorable terms are two very different things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 High-Balance Conventional Loans: County Map, Qualifying Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-high-balance-conventional-loans-county-map-qualifying-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-high-balance-conventional-loans-county-map-qualifying-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-balance conventional loans&lt;/strong&gt; are conforming loans that exceed the baseline FHFA limit ($766,550 for 2025) but stay within the higher limits designated for high-cost counties—up to $1,149,825 for single-family homes. These loans meet Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac underwriting standards but require slightly stricter qualification than baseline conforming loans, including higher credit scores, additional reserves, and sometimes larger down payments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re buying in expensive metro areas like San Francisco, Seattle, New York City, or Honolulu, understanding high-balance loan limits and qualification rules is essential for accessing competitive rates without jumping to jumbo financing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional Loan Limits 2025: How New Conforming Caps Shape Affordability and Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-how-new-conforming-caps-shape-affordability-and-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-how-new-conforming-caps-shape-affordability-and-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 conventional loan limits—set annually by the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA)—determine the maximum loan amounts that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac will purchase from lenders. For 2025, the &lt;strong&gt;baseline conforming limit is $766,550&lt;/strong&gt; for single-family homes in most counties, with &lt;strong&gt;high-cost areas reaching up to $1,149,825&lt;/strong&gt;. These limits directly impact how much you can borrow at conforming rates, what homes you can afford, and whether you&amp;rsquo;ll need jumbo financing to complete your purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should You Put 20% Down on a Conventional Loan? Let&#39;s Do the Math</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/should-you-put-20-percent-down-conventional-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/should-you-put-20-percent-down-conventional-loan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need 20% down to buy a house.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I had a dollar for every time I heard someone repeat this myth, I could probably make a down payment myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the truth: you don&amp;rsquo;t need 20% down for a conventional loan. You can buy a home with as little as 3% down if you&amp;rsquo;re a first-time buyer, or 5% if you&amp;rsquo;re a repeat buyer. But whether you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; put down less than 20% depends on your financial situation, goals, and what else you could do with that money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Buyers and Conventional Loans: Credit, Down Payments, and Rate Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First-time homebuyers&lt;/strong&gt; often assume they need FHA loans or 20% down payments to buy a home—but conventional loans offer some of the best financing options for first-time buyers in 2025, including &lt;strong&gt;3% down payment programs&lt;/strong&gt;, competitive rates for borrowers with 620+ credit scores, and access to conforming loan limits up to $766,550 (or $1,149,825 in high-cost areas). Understanding how conventional loans work, what credit and income requirements you need to meet, and how to avoid common mistakes helps you qualify faster and save money over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Should You Actually Refinance Your Conventional Loan?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/when-should-you-refinance-conventional-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/when-should-you-refinance-conventional-loan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Refinance when rates drop 1%.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard this rule before. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, memorable, and completely oversimplified.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reality is more nuanced. Sometimes refinancing with a 0.5% rate drop makes perfect sense. Other times, even a 1.5% drop isn&amp;rsquo;t worth the hassle and cost.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about when refinancing your conventional loan actually makes financial sense—and when you&amp;rsquo;re better off staying put.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-break-even-point-is-everything&#34;&gt;The Break-Even Point Is Everything&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forget the 1% rule. What really matters is your break-even point: how long it takes to recoup your closing costs through the monthly payment savings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Home Buyer? Here&#39;s What Conventional Loan Officers Wish You Knew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/first-time-home-buyer-conventional-loan-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/first-time-home-buyer-conventional-loan-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with hundreds of first-time home buyers over the years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed the same misconceptions come up over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s clear the air. Here&amp;rsquo;s what loan officers actually wish first-time buyers knew before they started the home buying process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-dont-need-perfect-credit&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Need Perfect Credit&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First-time buyers often think they need an 800 credit score to get approved. Not even close.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For conventional loans, 620 is the minimum, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get competitive rates starting around 680-700. Yes, a 750+ score gets you better terms, but don&amp;rsquo;t let a 690 score stop you from applying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Remove PMI from Your Conventional Loan (Without Refinancing)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/how-to-remove-pmi-conventional-loan-without-refinancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/how-to-remove-pmi-conventional-loan-without-refinancing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re paying Private Mortgage Insurance (PMI) on your conventional loan, you&amp;rsquo;re probably throwing away $100 to $500 per month depending on your loan amount and down payment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The good news? PMI isn&amp;rsquo;t permanent. Once you reach 20% equity in your home, you can get rid of it—and you don&amp;rsquo;t always need to refinance to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me show you exactly how to remove PMI and keep that money in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional vs. FHA Loans: Which One Actually Saves You Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-loans-cost-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-vs-fha-loans-cost-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re deciding between a conventional loan and an FHA loan, most people focus on the down payment requirement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conventional: 3-5% down&lt;br&gt;&#xA;FHA: 3.5% down&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They look pretty similar, right? So why not just go with FHA since it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;easier to qualify&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not so fast. The down payment is just one piece of the puzzle. When you factor in mortgage insurance, credit score impacts, and long-term costs, conventional loans often come out ahead—even for borrowers with less-than-perfect credit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Waited 4 Months to Improve My Credit 38 Points - Saved $4,200 on My First Home Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started seriously looking at homes in March 2024, I was ready to apply for a mortgage immediately. I had saved $18,000 for down payment on a $285,000 home, my debt-to-income ratio was solid at 38%, and I assumed my credit score would be &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I checked my actual middle credit score through my lender&amp;rsquo;s pre-qualification: 657. Not terrible, but my loan officer explained I was sitting right at the edge between two different rate tiers—and waiting a few months to improve my credit could save me thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA 3.5% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Ran the Numbers for My $310,000 Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/fha-3-5-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/fha-3-5-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent three months comparing FHA and conventional loan options before purchasing my first home in August 2024. Every article I read said &amp;ldquo;FHA is for low credit, conventional is for high credit,&amp;rdquo; but with 668 credit score, I qualified for both programs—and the decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the actual math I ran on my $310,000 home purchase, comparing FHA 3.5% down versus conventional 5% down, including all the hidden costs nobody talks about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA 0% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Compared Both for My $340,000 Military Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/va-0-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-compared-both-for-my-340000-military-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/va-0-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-compared-both-for-my-340000-military-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m active duty Air Force with 8 years of service, and when I started house hunting in September 2024, I assumed my VA loan benefit was automatically the best option. Zero down payment, no PMI, favorable rates for military—what could be better than that?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I ran the actual numbers comparing VA 0% down versus conventional 5% down for my $340,000 home purchase in San Antonio, and the results surprised me. VA saved me money in some scenarios but not others, depending on how long I planned to keep the home and whether I factored in opportunity cost of the down payment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional 3% Down with PMI vs. FHA 3.5% Down - I Chose Conventional and Saved $8,400</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/conventional-3-percent-down-with-pmi-vs-fha-3-5-percent-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/conventional-3-percent-down-with-pmi-vs-fha-3-5-percent-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my home search in April 2024, I assumed FHA was my only option for minimal down payment. I had saved $11,500 and wanted to buy a $325,000 home—which meant 3.5% down ($11,375) would barely work with FHA, leaving me just $125 for closing costs and emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then my loan officer mentioned conventional 3% down programs. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even realized conventional allowed less than 5% down. After running the numbers comparing FHA 3.5% versus conventional 3%, I chose conventional despite it costing $64 more per month initially—because PMI removal in year 6 would save me $8,400 over 6-10 years compared to FHA&amp;rsquo;s permanent mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 43% DTI Got Approved for $385,000 Purchase - But 46% Was Denied, Here&#39;s Why</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/my-43-percent-dti-got-approved-for-385000-purchase-but-46-percent-was-denied-heres-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/my-43-percent-dti-got-approved-for-385000-purchase-but-46-percent-was-denied-heres-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I applied for a conventional purchase mortgage in September 2024 with $92,000 annual income, 708 credit score, and 10% down payment on a $385,000 home. My debt-to-income ratio was 46.2%. I was confident I would be approved—my income was strong, my credit was above the 700 threshold, and I had substantial down payment saved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The underwriter denied my application citing &amp;ldquo;debt-to-income ratio exceeds maximum allowable threshold for program guidelines without sufficient compensating factors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
