<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VA Lenders on Veterans Loan Officers</title><link>https://www.veteransloanofficers.com/tags/va-lenders/</link><description>Recent content in VA Lenders on Veterans Loan Officers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.veteransloanofficers.com/tags/va-lenders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finding VA Lenders for Deployed Service Members: Tips &amp; Best Practices</title><link>https://www.veteransloanofficers.com/blogs/finding-va-lenders-for-deployed-service-members-tips-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.veteransloanofficers.com/blogs/finding-va-lenders-for-deployed-service-members-tips-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a home while deployed or stationed overseas presents unique challenges—time zone differences, limited communication access, deployment income documentation, and power of attorney requirements. However, thousands of active-duty service members successfully close on VA loans each year while serving abroad, and understanding which lenders specialize in deployment scenarios makes the process significantly smoother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right VA lender understands how to verify BAH (Basic Allowance for Housing), handle overseas power of attorney, process remote document signing, and work around communication blackouts during training exercises or combat deployments. This guide explains how deployed service members can find VA lenders who specialize in military lending and avoid the delays and frustrations that come from working with lenders unfamiliar with deployment challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VA Cash-Out Refinance for Veterans: Options, Limits &amp; Best Practices</title><link>https://www.veteransloanofficers.com/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-for-veterans-options-limits-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.veteransloanofficers.com/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-for-veterans-options-limits-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;VA cash-out refinancing lets veterans and active-duty service members convert home equity into cash while maintaining VA loan benefits—no private mortgage insurance, competitive rates, and funding fee exemptions for disabled veterans. Unlike conventional cash-out refinances that cap loan-to-value at 80%, VA cash-out allows up to &lt;strong&gt;90% LTV&lt;/strong&gt; in most cases, and up to &lt;strong&gt;100% LTV&lt;/strong&gt; with certain lenders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means you can access significantly more equity than conventional or FHA cash-out options while keeping favorable VA loan terms. However, VA cash-out refinancing comes with a 2.15%-3.3% funding fee (waived for disabled veterans), and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to meet credit, income, and residual income requirements. Understanding when VA cash-out makes sense—and when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t—helps you make the right financial decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>