<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Down Payment on Conforming Loan Officers</title><link>https://conformingloanofficers.com/tags/down-payment/</link><description>Recent content in Down Payment on Conforming Loan Officers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conformingloanofficers.com/tags/down-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Conforming vs. FHA Loans in 2025: Key Differences, Credit Requirements, and Loan Limits Explained</title><link>https://conformingloanofficers.com/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conformingloanofficers.com/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When comparing &lt;strong&gt;conforming loans&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;FHA loans&lt;/strong&gt; in 2025, the biggest differences come down to credit requirements, down payment flexibility, loan limits, and long-term costs. Conforming loans (backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac) offer better rates and lower lifetime costs for borrowers with strong credit, while FHA loans (insured by the Federal Housing Administration) provide easier qualification for borrowers with lower credit scores and smaller down payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding which loan type fits your financial profile helps you save money, qualify faster, and avoid unnecessary costs over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First-Time Buyers and Conventional Loans: Credit, Down Payments, and Rate Strategies for 2025</title><link>https://conformingloanofficers.com/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conformingloanofficers.com/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First-time homebuyers&lt;/strong&gt; often assume they need FHA loans or 20% down payments to buy a home—but conventional loans offer some of the best financing options for first-time buyers in 2025, including &lt;strong&gt;3% down payment programs&lt;/strong&gt;, competitive rates for borrowers with 620+ credit scores, and access to conforming loan limits up to $766,550 (or $1,149,825 in high-cost areas). Understanding how conventional loans work, what credit and income requirements you need to meet, and how to avoid common mistakes helps you qualify faster and save money over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>