<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2025 on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/2025/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2025 on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refinancing with a Mortgage Broker: When It Makes Sense in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/refinancing-with-broker-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/refinancing-with-broker-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Refinancing your conventional mortgage through a broker instead of your current lender can save tens of thousands—but only if you understand when broker value outweighs convenience. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to decide whether to refinance with a broker in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-refinance-through-a-broker-vs-your-current-lender&#34;&gt;Why Refinance Through a Broker vs. Your Current Lender?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your current lender wants to keep your business. They&amp;rsquo;ll make refinancing easy—but &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean &amp;ldquo;cheapest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current lender advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Streamlined process (they already have your information)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fast approvals (no new appraisal required in some cases)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relationship discounts (maybe)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current lender disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits: What Middle Credit Score Borrowers Need to Know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) has announced the 2025 conforming loan limits, bringing exciting opportunities for middle credit score borrowers seeking safe, government-backed financing through Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-conforming-loan-limits&#34;&gt;What Are Conforming Loan Limits?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conforming loan limits represent the maximum amount you can borrow through Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac programs while maintaining government-sponsored enterprise (GSE) backing. These limits ensure loans remain within the &amp;ldquo;conforming&amp;rdquo; category, offering borrowers enhanced security and standardized terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
