<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reserves on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/reserves/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reserves on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/reserves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Texas Jumbo Reserve Requirements: 6–12 Month PITI Rules Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-jumbo-lenders-demand-substantial-reserves&#34;&gt;Why Jumbo Lenders Demand Substantial Reserves&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jumbo loans carry higher default risk than conforming loans—larger balances, less standardized underwriting, and portfolio retention instead of agency sale. To offset this risk, jumbo lenders require 6–12 months of &lt;strong&gt;PITI reserves&lt;/strong&gt; (principal, interest, taxes, insurance) in liquid or semi-liquid assets. The higher your loan amount, LTV, or complexity, the more reserves you&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reserve requirements aren&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary—they prove you can weather income disruption (job loss, business downturn, market crash) without defaulting. Lenders calculate reserves using &lt;strong&gt;post-closing liquid assets&lt;/strong&gt;: checking, savings, money market, brokerage accounts (with discounting), and sometimes retirement accounts (60%–70% haircut). Real estate equity, business assets, and restricted stock usually don&amp;rsquo;t count.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Asset Depletion Sprint Before Rate Sheets Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/asset-depletion-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/asset-depletion-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asset depletion loans sound simple—show enough money, get approved—but every underwriter asks the same questions about seasoning, withdrawals, and exit plans. After watching a rate sheet worsen while we hunted for a missing statement, we built a five-day sprint that keeps the entire asset story tidy. Here is how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-inventory-and-intent&#34;&gt;Day 1: Inventory and intent&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We start with a whiteboard session listing every account we plan to use: brokerage, retirement, trust, and cash-value insurance. For each line we note ownership, recent large deposits, and whether withdrawals trigger penalties. Then we mirror that list in the overlay spreadsheet from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.browselenders.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BrowseLenders.com&lt;/a&gt;. The sheet forces us to record which lenders accept each account type and what percentage of the balance they use for qualifying income. That clarity prevents arguments later when someone insists, “But Bank X counted the whole thing last year.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How We Kept Our Jumbo Underwriting Review Calm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/jumboloanofficers/blogs/jumbo-underwriting-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/jumboloanofficers/blogs/jumbo-underwriting-calibration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jumbo underwriting reviews are famous for derailing strong borrowers. Between reserve requirements, concentrated stock positions, and appraisal scrutiny, even well-paid households can feel shaky. My partner and I recently closed on a $2.8 million primary residence while juggling IPO lockups and relocation reimbursements. We promised ourselves the review would stay calm, so we reverse engineered the process into six checkpoints. Use our notes to shorten your own stress cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-rebuild-the-financial-narrative&#34;&gt;1. Rebuild the financial narrative&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We stopped thinking in terms of “documents” and started thinking in terms of chapters. Chapter one covered base salary, bonuses, and deferred comp. Chapter two summarized equity: RSUs, ESPP holdings, and privately held shares. Chapter three captured passive income from rentals and syndications. Each chapter opened with a one-page narrative that gave the underwriter context before they flipped through PDFs. The clarity alone removed three rounds of questions because our officer always had a cheat sheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
