<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calculators on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/calculators/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calculators on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/calculators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refinance Break-Even Calculator: When Refinancing Actually Saves Money (Real Math)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refinanceloanofficers/blogs/refinance-break-even-calculator-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refinanceloanofficers/blogs/refinance-break-even-calculator-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most homeowners make refinancing decisions based on monthly payment comparisons alone—completely ignoring the single most important metric that determines whether refinancing saves or costs money: &lt;strong&gt;break-even period&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen countless borrowers refinance based on $200/month savings without realizing they will sell their home in 18 months—before they recoup $7,000 in closing costs. They &amp;ldquo;saved&amp;rdquo; money by losing $3,400.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The break-even calculation is not complicated, but most lenders conveniently avoid explaining it because it would talk people out of some refinances. Let me show you exactly how to calculate true break-even, factor in hidden costs that most calculators ignore, and determine whether refinancing makes financial sense for your specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Calculate Your Available Cash-Out Refinance Amount</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cashoutmortgagerefinance/blogs/calculate-cashout-amount/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 14:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cashoutmortgagerefinance/blogs/calculate-cashout-amount/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding how much cash you can access through refinancing requires more than just knowing your home&amp;rsquo;s value. The calculation involves multiple factors including loan-to-value ratios, lender requirements, and your specific loan type. Learning this process helps you set realistic expectations before starting your refinance application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-with-your-homes-current-value&#34;&gt;Starting With Your Home&amp;rsquo;s Current Value&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The foundation of any cash-out calculation begins with an accurate assessment of your property&amp;rsquo;s current market value. While online estimates from sites like Zillow or Redfin provide starting points, lenders require professional appraisals to determine your home&amp;rsquo;s worth officially. Market conditions, recent comparable sales, and property improvements all influence the final appraisal value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
