<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FHA 203(k) on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/fha-203k/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FHA 203(k) on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/fha-203k/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My FHA 203(k) Inspector Ride-Alongs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/inspector-ride-along/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/inspector-ride-along/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before my FHA 203(k) closed, I promised my HUD consultant I would never hover during inspections. By the second draw, curiosity won. I asked if I could quietly tag along, and he laughed: “Please do—borrowers who show up make my paperwork easier.” Riding along became one of the smartest decisions I made. It turned draw days from mystery events into collaborative checkpoints that impressed my lender, inspired my contractor, and kept change orders grounded in reality. Here is what those visits taught me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Paired Credit Moves With Every FHA 203(k) Draw</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/credit-synced-draws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/credit-synced-draws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) file almost derailed before demo day because I underestimated how every trip to the hardware store would show up on my credit reports. I had the cash to cover purchases, but lenders only see balances—if utilization spikes between draws, approvals wobble. I avoided disaster by aligning each credit move with the draw schedule, then documenting it inside MiddleCreditScore.com so the lender could see my logic. Here is the playbook that kept my middle score steady while the rehab charged forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 48-Hour Contractor Interview Sprint That Saved My FHA 203(k) Timeline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/contractor-interview-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/contractor-interview-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I assumed lining up contractors for my FHA 203(k) was the easy part—send a scope, collect a few bids, pick the friendliest voice. Then my HUD consultant reminded me that every subcontractor would be vetted by the lender, that every change would ripple through the draw schedule, and that the clock on my purchase contract did not care about anyone’s backlog. Instead of stretching the interviews across weeks, I ran an intentional 48-hour sprint. By Monday morning, I had three rehab-ready bids, a synced timeline, and a lender who called the prep “shockingly organized.” Here is the playbook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the Rehab Appraisal Brief That Won Over My Lender</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/rehab-appraisal-brief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/rehab-appraisal-brief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the underwriter asked for “more comfort” around my after-improved value (ARV), I realized my file still looked like a pile of emails instead of a story. I spent one long Sunday building what I now call the Rehab Appraisal Brief—a single PDF that combined comps, scope clarification, contractor proof, and credit-ready milestones. By Monday afternoon the lender cleared the valuation condition without asking another question. Here is the step-by-step walkthrough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Bought a Fixer-Upper with an FHA 203(k) Loan: Here&#39;s What Nobody Told Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/i-bought-a-fixer-upper-with-an-fha-203k-loan-here-is-what-nobody-told-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/i-bought-a-fixer-upper-with-an-fha-203k-loan-here-is-what-nobody-told-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I found a 1970s ranch house listed at &lt;strong&gt;$215,000&lt;/strong&gt; in a great neighborhood (where comparable updated homes sold for $320,000+), we knew it was a diamond in the rough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The house needed &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;: new kitchen, both bathrooms gutted, flooring throughout, updated electrical, new HVAC, and cosmetic work in every room.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t have $100,000 sitting around for renovations. Traditional financing wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work—no bank will give you a mortgage on a house with a non-functioning kitchen and electrical code violations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding a Contractor for My 203(k) Renovation: 3 Months, 18 Calls, 1 Success Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/finding-a-contractor-for-my-203k-renovation-3-months-18-calls-1-success-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/finding-a-contractor-for-my-203k-renovation-3-months-18-calls-1-success-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought finding a contractor for my FHA 203(k) renovation would be easy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The house needed $52,000 in work—kitchen, bathroom, flooring, electrical, HVAC. It&amp;rsquo;s a decent-sized job. Contractors should be lining up, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I contacted &lt;strong&gt;18 contractors&lt;/strong&gt; over 3 months. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it went:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 contractors&lt;/strong&gt; never called me back&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 contractors&lt;/strong&gt; said they &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t do 203(k) loans&amp;rdquo;**&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 contractors&lt;/strong&gt; gave me bids 50-80% over budget&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 contractors&lt;/strong&gt; agreed to the job but had major red flags&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 contractors&lt;/strong&gt; were legitimate, experienced, and FHA-approved&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of those two was perfect. The other was booked for 9 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
