<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>First-Time Buyer on Purchase Mortgage Loans</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/tags/first-time-buyer/</link><description>Recent content in First-Time Buyer on Purchase Mortgage Loans</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://purchasemortgageloans.com/tags/first-time-buyer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Waited 4 Months to Improve My Credit 38 Points - Saved $4,200 on My First Home Purchase</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started seriously looking at homes in March 2024, I was ready to apply for a mortgage immediately. I had saved $18,000 for down payment on a $285,000 home, my debt-to-income ratio was solid at 38%, and I assumed my credit score would be &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I checked my actual middle credit score through my lender&amp;rsquo;s pre-qualification: 657. Not terrible, but my loan officer explained I was sitting right at the edge between two different rate tiers—and waiting a few months to improve my credit could save me thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Got Denied for Conventional at 652 Credit - FHA Approved Me in 6 Days with Same Income</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-got-denied-for-conventional-at-652-credit-fha-approved-me-in-6-days-with-same-income/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-got-denied-for-conventional-at-652-credit-fha-approved-me-in-6-days-with-same-income/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I got my first mortgage denial letter on a Tuesday afternoon in June 2024. After three weeks of document submission, income verification, and waiting for underwriting review, the conventional lender denied my application for a $295,000 purchase loan citing &amp;ldquo;insufficient credit history and credit score below minimum threshold for program guidelines.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had 652 credit, $32,000 saved for down payment (10% down plus closing costs), stable $72,000 annual income, and debt-to-income ratio under 35%. On paper, I thought I was a strong borrower. The denial was crushing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Used My Parents' Gift Funds for 100% of My Down Payment - Here's the Documentation Process</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-used-my-parents-gift-funds-for-100-of-my-down-payment-heres-the-documentation-process/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-used-my-parents-gift-funds-for-100-of-my-down-payment-heres-the-documentation-process/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I closed on my first home in October 2024 using gift funds from my parents for 100% of my down payment and most of my closing costs. Total gift amount: $14,500. My personal cash contribution: $1,200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first told my loan officer I planned to use gift funds, she said &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s fine, we just need a gift letter.&amp;rdquo; I thought it would be simple—my parents write a letter saying they&amp;rsquo;re giving me money, transfer the funds, and we&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conventional 3% Down with PMI vs. FHA 3.5% Down - I Chose Conventional and Saved $8,400</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/conventional-3-down-with-pmi-vs.-fha-3.5-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/conventional-3-down-with-pmi-vs.-fha-3.5-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my home search in April 2024, I assumed FHA was my only option for minimal down payment. I had saved $11,500 and wanted to buy a $325,000 home—which meant 3.5% down ($11,375) would barely work with FHA, leaving me just $125 for closing costs and emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then my loan officer mentioned conventional 3% down programs. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even realized conventional allowed less than 5% down. After running the numbers comparing FHA 3.5% versus conventional 3%, I chose conventional despite it costing $64 more per month initially—because PMI removal in year 6 would save me $8,400 over 6-10 years compared to FHA&amp;rsquo;s permanent mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>