<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>High-Balance Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/high-balance-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in High-Balance Loans on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/high-balance-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jumbo Loans vs. Conforming: I Compared Both for My $825K Home Purchase and Here&#39;s What I Learned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/jumbo-loans-vs-conforming-i-compared-both-for-my-825k-home-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/jumbo-loans-vs-conforming-i-compared-both-for-my-825k-home-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started house hunting in Orange County, California in early 2024, I quickly learned that $825,000 was the baseline for single-family homes in decent neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first question:&lt;/strong&gt; Is that a jumbo loan or conforming loan?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The answer:&lt;/strong&gt; In Orange County, the 2024 conforming loan limit is $1,089,300—so my $825,000 purchase qualified as conforming, not jumbo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-2024-conforming-loan-limits&#34;&gt;Understanding the 2024 Conforming Loan Limits&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;standard-vs-high-cost-area-limits&#34;&gt;Standard vs. High-Cost Area Limits&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard conforming limit (2024):&lt;/strong&gt; $766,550 in most U.S. counties&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 High-Balance Conventional Loans: County Map, Qualifying Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-high-balance-conventional-loans-county-map-qualifying-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-high-balance-conventional-loans-county-map-qualifying-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-balance conventional loans&lt;/strong&gt; are conforming loans that exceed the baseline FHFA limit ($766,550 for 2025) but stay within the higher limits designated for high-cost counties—up to $1,149,825 for single-family homes. These loans meet Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac underwriting standards but require slightly stricter qualification than baseline conforming loans, including higher credit scores, additional reserves, and sometimes larger down payments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re buying in expensive metro areas like San Francisco, Seattle, New York City, or Honolulu, understanding high-balance loan limits and qualification rules is essential for accessing competitive rates without jumping to jumbo financing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conventional Loan Limits 2025: What You Need to Know Before You Shop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-complete-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/conventional-loan-limits-2025-complete-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) announces new conforming loan limits for conventional mortgages. These limits determine the maximum amount you can borrow with a standard conventional loan before you cross into jumbo loan territory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 2025, the baseline conforming loan limit is &lt;strong&gt;$806,500&lt;/strong&gt; for single-family homes in most of the U.S.—up from $766,550 in 2024. But if you&amp;rsquo;re buying in a high-cost area, your limit could be significantly higher.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
