<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freddie Mac on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/freddie-mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freddie Mac on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/freddie-mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conforming Loan Down Payment Options: 3% Down Programs and Smart Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-down-payment-options-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-down-payment-options-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest misconceptions about conforming loans is that you need a 20% down payment to qualify. The reality? Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac offer multiple pathways to homeownership with down payments as low as 3%—and understanding these options can help you buy sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-down-payment-size-matters&#34;&gt;Why Down Payment Size Matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your down payment affects three critical factors: loan approval odds, monthly payment amounts, and whether you&amp;rsquo;ll pay private mortgage insurance (PMI). But here&amp;rsquo;s what many borrowers miss: a smaller down payment doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean worse terms if you&amp;rsquo;re using a conforming loan backed by government-sponsored enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-nonconforming-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-nonconforming-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the difference between conforming and non-conforming loans is crucial for making the right mortgage decision in 2025. With updated FHFA loan limits and evolving market conditions, borrowers must navigate an increasingly complex landscape to secure the best financing for their specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-conforming-vs-non-conforming-loans&#34;&gt;Defining Conforming vs. Non-Conforming Loans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conforming-loans-government-backed-security&#34;&gt;Conforming Loans: Government-Backed Security&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conforming loans meet specific criteria established by the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) and are eligible for purchase by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle Credit Score Requirements for Conforming Mortgages: 2025 Complete Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/middle-credit-score-conforming-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/middle-credit-score-conforming-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding credit requirements for conforming mortgages is crucial for middle credit score borrowers seeking the safety and security of Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac financing. This comprehensive guide breaks down exactly what you need to know about qualifying with a middle-range credit score.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-constitutes-a-middle-credit-score&#34;&gt;What Constitutes a &amp;ldquo;Middle Credit Score&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;credit-score-ranges-defined&#34;&gt;Credit Score Ranges Defined&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excellent&lt;/strong&gt;: 740+ (Premium conforming loan treatment)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt;: 680-739 (Strong conforming loan candidates)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Middle&lt;/strong&gt;: 620-679 (Our specialty - conforming loan eligible)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fair&lt;/strong&gt;: 580-619 (Limited conforming options)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poor&lt;/strong&gt;: Below 580 (Non-conforming alternatives needed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;middle-credit-score-sweet-spot-620-679&#34;&gt;Middle Credit Score Sweet Spot: 620-679&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This range represents the majority of American borrowers and offers substantial conforming loan opportunities with proper preparation and lender selection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits: What Middle Credit Score Borrowers Need to Know</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) has announced the 2025 conforming loan limits, bringing exciting opportunities for middle credit score borrowers seeking safe, government-backed financing through Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-conforming-loan-limits&#34;&gt;What Are Conforming Loan Limits?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conforming loan limits represent the maximum amount you can borrow through Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac programs while maintaining government-sponsored enterprise (GSE) backing. These limits ensure loans remain within the &amp;ldquo;conforming&amp;rdquo; category, offering borrowers enhanced security and standardized terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
