<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Management on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/project-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Management on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/project-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our 30-Minute Lender Huddle Playbook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/lender-huddle-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/lender-huddle-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Loan officers are busy. If you wander through a HELOC update call, they tune out. I learned that after a rambling conversation last spring where I forgot half the numbers. This time we built a 30-minute “lender huddle” playbook. Every agenda item referenced Cash-OutRefinance.com comparisons, MiddleCreditScore.com updates, and BrowseLenders.com overlays. The calls became efficient, respectful, and—dare I say—fun. Here’s the template we used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-send-the-briefing-24-hours-before-the-call&#34;&gt;Step 1: Send the briefing 24 hours before the call&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We email a short PDF titled “HELOC Readiness Brief – Week 4.” It contains:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Renovation Bid Tracker for Tidy Underwriting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few things spike blood pressure like trying to squeeze contractor bids, inspection responses, and VA renovation overlays into the same week. Most buyers treat the process like a scavenger hunt, which is why lenders slow-walk approvals. Build a repeatable bid tracker instead. The framework below is tuned for service members who juggle PCS timelines, guard drills, and family life yet still want to close on a property that needs work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The HELOC Approval Standup Sprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/onlineheloc/blogs/approval-standup-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/onlineheloc/blogs/approval-standup-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waiting weeks between HELOC updates drives me up the wall. This round, we tried something different: a five-day approval sprint modeled after agency standups. Every evening, our family spent 18 minutes reviewing calculators, lender portals, and credit milestones. By Friday the underwriter cleared our stips, the draw limit stayed intact, and no one felt blindsided. Below is the exact cadence if you want to duplicate it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-monday-kickoff-and-calculator-sync&#34;&gt;Day 1 (Monday): Kickoff and calculator sync&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We opened with the OnlineHELOC calculator to set the baseline. Mortgage balance: $318,400. Target HELOC: $125,000. Combined CLTV: 74.6%. Seeing the numbers on-screen helped everyone remember why we were hustling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspection Week Taught Me How to Pitch My HELOC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/inspection-week-heloc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/inspection-week-heloc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week an appraiser or inspector visits is the week your HELOC story needs to sound coordinated. I used to dread those visits because we’d scramble to remember contractor invoices or plug numbers into calculators at the last second. This year we turned inspection week into a pitch rehearsal. Instead of simply tidying up the house, we rehearsed the narrative that made the HELOC make sense. Here’s how we organized the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Turned HUD Consultant Check-Ins into Weekly Office Hours</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/hud-consultant-office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/hud-consultant-office-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) felt chaotic until we turned random phone calls into structured “office hours” with the HUD consultant. Every Thursday at 4:00 p.m. we hop on a 30-minute video call, camera on, scopes open. It sounds small, but since launching the ritual we have had zero surprise inspection fails, zero missing invoices, and just one change-order dispute (which we resolved live). If you’re about to start a rehab, here’s a blueprint you can copy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
