<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspection on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/inspection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspection on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/inspection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VA Renovation Bid Tracker for Tidy Underwriting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few things spike blood pressure like trying to squeeze contractor bids, inspection responses, and VA renovation overlays into the same week. Most buyers treat the process like a scavenger hunt, which is why lenders slow-walk approvals. Build a repeatable bid tracker instead. The framework below is tuned for service members who juggle PCS timelines, guard drills, and family life yet still want to close on a property that needs work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating VA Appraisals and Tidewater Like a Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-appraisal-tidewater-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-appraisal-tidewater-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you ask veterans what keeps them up at night during a home purchase, Tidewater notices rank near the top. The VA appraisal process is designed to protect you, but the extra communication can feel like a pop quiz. The antidote is preparation. When you expect Tidewater, plan for it, and rehearse the response, the notice becomes a predictable fork in the road rather than a dead end. Here is how we coach buyers and agents to stay ahead of the valuation curve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 30-Day Punch-List Week Checklist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/punchlist-week-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/punchlist-week-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most stressful part of my FHA 203(k) rehab wasn’t demolition or framing—it was the final 30 days, when every punch-list item mattered and the final draw dangled over our heads. I wrote a “Punch-List Week Checklist” to keep myself sane. Instead of guessing what to do each day, I followed this cadence and shared it with my contractor, HUD consultant, and loan officer. We hit every inspection on plan, kept the budget balanced, and unlocked the last disbursement without scrambling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
