<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>APR on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/apr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in APR on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/apr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interest Rate vs. APR: What Florida Borrowers Need to Know to Compare Lenders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridahomerates/blogs/interest-rate-vs-apr-florida-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridahomerates/blogs/interest-rate-vs-apr-florida-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lender A offers 6.50%. Lender B offers 6.625%. You pick Lender A because the rate is lower. Then you see total costs at closing and realize you made the wrong choice. Here&amp;rsquo;s why APR matters more than rate—and how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-interest-rate-actually-means&#34;&gt;What Interest Rate Actually Means&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your interest rate is the percentage the lender charges to borrow money. It determines your monthly principal and interest payment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$300,000 loan at 6.50% = $1,896/month (P&amp;amp;I)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$300,000 loan at 6.625% = $1,920/month (P&amp;amp;I)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 6.50% rate saves you $24/month. Seems like an easy choice, right? Not so fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APR vs. Rate in Texas: Why You&#39;re Probably Overpaying</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texashomerates/blogs/apr-vs-rate-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texashomerates/blogs/apr-vs-rate-texas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;apr-vs-rate-in-texas-why-youre-probably-overpaying&#34;&gt;APR vs. Rate in Texas: Why You&amp;rsquo;re Probably Overpaying&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Walk into any Texas mortgage lender and ask for their &amp;ldquo;best rate.&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;ll hear: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;5.875% conventional!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; Sounds great—until you see the Loan Estimate and realize the APR is 6.45%. What happened?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You just got hit with the oldest trick in the mortgage playbook: &lt;strong&gt;rate vs. APR confusion&lt;/strong&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to spot it, avoid it, and save thousands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-the-difference-between-rate-and-apr&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the Difference Between Rate and APR?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest Rate&lt;/strong&gt; = the percentage you pay on the loan balance annually&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;APR (Annual Percentage Rate)&lt;/strong&gt; = the &lt;strong&gt;true cost&lt;/strong&gt; of borrowing, including rate + fees&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Brokers Win Rate Battles: The Power Shopping Playbook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/brokerstx/blogs/how-brokers-win-rate-battles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/brokerstx/blogs/how-brokers-win-rate-battles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-brokers-win-rate-battles-the-power-shopping-playbook&#34;&gt;How Brokers Win Rate Battles: The Power Shopping Playbook&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you work with a mortgage broker, you&amp;rsquo;re not just getting one loan officer—you&amp;rsquo;re getting access to a lender network that brokers leverage every day to win rate concessions. Understanding how brokers shop is the first power key to better pricing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rate-battle-starts-with-a-single-pulldown&#34;&gt;The Rate Battle Starts With a Single Pulldown&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A key advantage brokers have is &lt;strong&gt;one credit pull for unlimited lender quotes&lt;/strong&gt;. When you apply directly to banks, each application triggers a hard inquiry that dings your credit. Brokers submit one pull that counts as a single inquiry (if all quotes happen within 14–45 days, scoring models treat it as one rate-shopping event).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Saturday Points-vs-Credits War Room</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/points-vs-credits-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/points-vs-credits-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender dumped three shiny quotes into my inbox, each offer mixed points, credits, and lock periods differently. I am the spreadsheet-loving member of our household, so I spent a full Saturday turning those quotes into a points-vs-credits war room. The goal was simple: understand the true cost of each structure before locking, then explain the decision to my spouse and financial coach without jargon. Here is the framework that worked and how you can plug in your numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Mortgage Rates in 2025: Why Your Rate Isn&#39;t Actually &#39;The Rate&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/understanding-mortgage-rates-in-2025-why-your-rate-isn-t-actually-the-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/understanding-mortgage-rates-in-2025-why-your-rate-isn-t-actually-the-rate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started shopping for a mortgage last year, I called five different lenders on the same day to compare rates. Every single one gave me a different &amp;ldquo;rate&amp;rdquo;—ranging from 6.25% to 7.125%.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was confused. Why would one lender offer me 6.25% while another quoted 7.125% for the exact same loan amount on the exact same day?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer is that &amp;ldquo;the rate&amp;rdquo; you see advertised or quoted isn&amp;rsquo;t actually the full story. Understanding how mortgage rates really work—APR vs interest rate, points, credits, rate locks, and pricing adjustments—is the difference between overpaying and getting the best deal possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shopping Multiple Lenders Saved Me $47,000—Here&#39;s How to Do It Right</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/shopping-multiple-lenders-saved-me-47000-here-s-how-to-do-it-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/shopping-multiple-lenders-saved-me-47000-here-s-how-to-do-it-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started shopping for a mortgage, I made the mistake most first-time buyers make: I went with the first lender who pre-approved me without comparing other options.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six months later, a coworker casually mentioned he got a 6.25% rate with $1,800 in lender fees on a similar loan. My rate? 6.875% with $4,200 in lender fees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did the math and nearly threw up. My &amp;ldquo;convenient&amp;rdquo; decision to go with my bank without shopping around was going to cost me &lt;strong&gt;$47,000 over the life of the loan&lt;/strong&gt;—$230 per month in unnecessary interest and fees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
