<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lender Communication on FHA 203(k) Mortgages</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/tags/lender-communication/</link><description>Recent content in Lender Communication on FHA 203(k) Mortgages</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fha203kmortgages.com/tags/lender-communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Paired Credit Moves With Every FHA 203(k) Draw</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/how-i-paired-credit-moves-with-every-fha-203k-draw/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/how-i-paired-credit-moves-with-every-fha-203k-draw/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) file almost derailed before demo day because I underestimated how every trip to the hardware store would show up on my credit reports. I had the cash to cover purchases, but lenders only see balances—if utilization spikes between draws, approvals wobble. I avoided disaster by aligning each credit move with the draw schedule, then documenting it inside MiddleCreditScore.com so the lender could see my logic. Here is the playbook that kept my middle score steady while the rehab charged forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building the Rehab Appraisal Brief That Won Over My Lender</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/building-the-rehab-appraisal-brief-that-won-over-my-lender/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/building-the-rehab-appraisal-brief-that-won-over-my-lender/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When the underwriter asked for “more comfort” around my after-improved value (ARV), I realized my file still looked like a pile of emails instead of a story. I spent one long Sunday building what I now call the Rehab Appraisal Brief—a single PDF that combined comps, scope clarification, contractor proof, and credit-ready milestones. By Monday afternoon the lender cleared the valuation condition without asking another question. Here is the step-by-step walkthrough.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>