<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Credit Scores on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/credit-scores/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Credit Scores on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/credit-scores/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Credit Scores Affect Florida Mortgage Rates: Tiers, Pricing, and Optimization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridahomerates/blogs/credit-score-impact-florida-mortgage-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridahomerates/blogs/credit-score-impact-florida-mortgage-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 780 credit score gets 6.50%. A 680 credit score gets 7.25%. Same borrower, same down payment, same property—0.75% difference just from credit. Here&amp;rsquo;s how credit scores affect Florida mortgage rates and what you can do about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-credit-scores-affect-rates&#34;&gt;Why Credit Scores Affect Rates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lenders price risk. Lower credit score = higher risk of default = higher interest rate to compensate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not personal—it&amp;rsquo;s actuarial. Statistically, borrowers with 640 credit default more often than borrowers with 740 credit. Lenders charge more to offset that risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Credit Scores Impact Broker-Negotiated Mortgage Rates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/credit-score-broker-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagebrokers/blogs/credit-score-broker-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your credit score determines more than approval—it directly impacts the interest rate your mortgage broker can negotiate. Understanding credit tier pricing helps you maximize broker value and potentially save tens of thousands on conventional loans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;credit-tier-breakdown-what-brokers-see&#34;&gt;Credit Tier Breakdown: What Brokers See&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mortgage brokers receive rate sheets from lenders showing pricing adjustments based on credit score bands. These aren&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary—they reflect default risk statistics compiled over decades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typical conventional loan credit tiers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA Loan Credit Score Requirements 2025: Complete Guide to Minimum Scores and Approval Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-credit-score-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-credit-score-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most first-time buyers don&amp;rsquo;t realize: FHA loans accept credit scores that would get you laughed out of a conventional lender&amp;rsquo;s office. But there&amp;rsquo;s a catch—understanding the difference between official FHA minimums and actual lender requirements can mean the difference between approval and rejection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me break down exactly how credit scores work with FHA financing, what minimums really matter, and proven strategies to maximize your approval odds even with credit challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Credit Score Do You Really Need for a Mortgage in 2025? Lender-by-Lender Breakdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A borrower called me frustrated last week: &amp;ldquo;I have a 665 credit score. Fannie Mae says they approve 620 and above for conventional loans, so why did three banks deny my application?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the credit score confusion that costs thousands of borrowers their dream homes every year. There&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;strong&gt;program minimum&lt;/strong&gt; (what Fannie Mae, FHA, or VA requires) and then there&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;strong&gt;lender minimum&lt;/strong&gt; (what each bank or broker actually approves). These two numbers can be 40-60 points apart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Credit Score Do I Actually Need for a Conventional Loan in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/what-credit-score-do-i-need-for-conventional-loan-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/what-credit-score-do-i-need-for-conventional-loan-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about buying a home or refinancing with a conventional loan, one of the first questions you&amp;rsquo;ll ask is: &amp;ldquo;What credit score do I need?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The quick answer most lenders will give you is 620. But that&amp;rsquo;s only part of the story, and understanding the full picture could save you thousands of dollars over the life of your loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-minimum-isnt-the-goal&#34;&gt;The Minimum Isn&amp;rsquo;t the Goal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, 620 is typically the minimum credit score for conventional loan approval. But here&amp;rsquo;s what most people don&amp;rsquo;t realize: qualifying at 620 and getting approved with favorable terms are two very different things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
