<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rate Caps on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/rate-caps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rate Caps on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/rate-caps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How HELOC Rates Work in Florida: Prime Rate, Margins, and Rate Caps Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/helocfl/blogs/how-heloc-rates-work-florida-prime-margin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/helocfl/blogs/how-heloc-rates-work-florida-prime-margin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You see &amp;ldquo;HELOC rates starting at 7.99%!&amp;rdquo; on a bank website. Then you apply and get quoted Prime + 2.25%. What happened? HELOC rates work differently than mortgage rates—they&amp;rsquo;re variable, tied to the Prime Rate, and adjust automatically when the Federal Reserve moves. Here&amp;rsquo;s how HELOC pricing actually works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-heloc-rate-formula-prime--margin--your-rate&#34;&gt;The HELOC Rate Formula: Prime + Margin = Your Rate&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HELOC rates aren&amp;rsquo;t set by lenders. They&amp;rsquo;re calculated by a simple formula:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HELOC Rates 2025: Current Trends, Predictions, and Rate Lock Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/helocloanofficers/blogs/heloc-rates-2025-trends-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/helocloanofficers/blogs/heloc-rates-2025-trends-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HELOC rates in 2025 are navigating a complex landscape shaped by Federal Reserve policy, inflation trends, and lender competition. Understanding current rate environments and future predictions helps homeowners time their equity extraction strategically and protect themselves from rate volatility through proper rate cap evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-heloc-rate-environment-in-2025&#34;&gt;Current HELOC Rate Environment in 2025&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of November 2025, HELOC rates typically range from 8.5% to 11.5% depending on credit profiles, combined loan-to-value ratios, and lender type. Unlike fixed-rate home equity loans, HELOCs carry variable rates tied to the Prime Rate, which moves with Federal Reserve policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
