<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refinance on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/refinance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refinance on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/refinance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Sunday Recast Dry Run That Keeps Our Conventional Refi Honest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/sunday-recast-dry-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/sunday-recast-dry-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recast sounds glamorous until you actually have to wire the lump sum and prove you understand the math. Our lender asks for a “recast readiness summary” once a quarter, so we turned the request into a standing Sunday ritual. The dry run forces us to document payments, rehearse how we would explain the cash source, and show we have a plan if markets shift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-pull-the-latest-amortization-snapshot&#34;&gt;Step 1: Pull the latest amortization snapshot&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We open the amortization tab in our scenario lab spreadsheet and download the current balance, next payment, and unpaid principal portion. Then we duplicate the sheet and drop in our target principal curtailment. Watching the payment change—even slightly—makes the future recast feel real. It also arms us with a slide that shows exactly how much faster the loan would pay off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Rate-Lock Fire Drill: Points vs Par In One Evening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender texts “I’d lock by tonight,” we default to a playbook we nicknamed the rate-lock fire drill. The protocol keeps us from panic-deciding whether to pay points, float, or pivot to a shorter lock. Within two hours we have updated pricing tests, fresh credit notes, and talking points for the entire decision chain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-define-the-window-and-the-stakes&#34;&gt;Step 1: Define the window and the stakes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first voice memo goes into the family chat explaining what is happening and why tonight matters. Then we confirm the real deadline. Sometimes “lock tonight” is code for “rates are trending up but you likely have until noon tomorrow.” We pin the actual cut-off to the top of our shared task board. At the same time we confirm the property status: appraisal done, title clear, insurance quote ready. If one of those is missing, we can’t justify an expensive lock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Refinance Broker Fees and Lender Costs in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/compare-broker-fees-refinance-costs-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/compare-broker-fees-refinance-costs-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A homeowner called me after signing her refinance papers: &amp;ldquo;The broker charged me $4,500 in fees plus the lender charged $3,200. I thought brokers were supposed to save me money—did I get ripped off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I reviewed her Closing Disclosure. The &amp;ldquo;$4,500 broker fee&amp;rdquo; was actually $1,200 to the broker plus $3,300 in title, appraisal, and other third-party costs that every refinance has regardless of who you use. The $3,200 &amp;ldquo;lender fees&amp;rdquo; were mostly prepaid taxes and insurance that go into escrow, not lender profit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wholesale vs Retail Mortgage Rates: Why Brokers Beat Banks on Refinancing Costs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/wholesale-vs-retail-mortgage-rates-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/wholesale-vs-retail-mortgage-rates-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;wholesale-vs-retail-mortgage-rates-the-pricing-gap-costing-you-thousands&#34;&gt;Wholesale vs. Retail Mortgage Rates: The Pricing Gap Costing You Thousands&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your bank will refinance your mortgage at 6.25%. A mortgage broker can get you 5.875% from the same bank&amp;rsquo;s wholesale division. Same lender, same borrower, same property—but a 0.375% rate difference worth $68 per month or $24,480 over the life of a $300,000 loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This wholesale versus retail pricing gap exists in almost every refinance scenario and is the primary reason brokers consistently beat banks on total refinance costs. Yet most homeowners have no idea this two-tier pricing structure even exists—much less how to access the better wholesale rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage Broker Rate Lock Strategies for Refinancing in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-rate-lock-strategies-refinancing-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-rate-lock-strategies-refinancing-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched a homeowner lock his refinance rate at 6.25% on Monday. By Friday, rates had dropped to 5.875%. He was stuck with the higher rate and lost $63 per month ($22,680 over the loan life) because he locked too early without understanding market timing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, another borrower floated her rate for two weeks waiting for a better entry point. Rates jumped 0.5% during that time. She ended up locking at 6.75% when she could have had 6.25%—costing her $91 monthly ($32,760 over life).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refinance Rate Shopping Guide 2025: Comparing Brokers vs Banks vs Credit Unions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/refinance-rate-shopping-brokers-vs-banks-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/refinance-rate-shopping-brokers-vs-banks-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten homeowners where they refinanced and you will get ten different answers: their current bank, a big national lender, a local credit union, an online broker, their neighbor&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. But here&amp;rsquo;s what almost none of them did: systematically compare rates across ALL these lender types to find which actually delivered the lowest total cost.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people refinance with whoever makes the process easiest, assuming rates are &amp;ldquo;pretty similar&amp;rdquo; across lenders. That assumption costs tens of thousands of dollars because refinance rates can vary by 0.25-0.75% between lender types—and even more within each category based on your specific credit, property, and loan characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mortgage Brokers Find Better Refinance Rates Than Banks in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/how-brokers-find-better-refinance-rates-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/how-brokers-find-better-refinance-rates-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most homeowners refinancing their mortgage don&amp;rsquo;t realize: the bank offering you 6.5% would give a mortgage broker 6.125% on the exact same loan. That 0.375% difference costs you over $20,000 on a $300,000 refinance over 30 years—money that stays in your pocket when you use a broker instead of going direct.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason for this pricing gap is simple: brokers access wholesale lender channels that offer better rates than retail bank divisions. Let me show you exactly how this works and why refinancing through a broker beats going direct to your bank in almost every scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Cash-Out Refinance for Veterans: Options, Limits &amp; Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-for-veterans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-for-veterans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VA cash-out refinancing lets veterans and active-duty service members convert home equity into cash while maintaining VA loan benefits—no private mortgage insurance, competitive rates, and funding fee exemptions for disabled veterans. Unlike conventional cash-out refinances that cap loan-to-value at 80%, VA cash-out allows up to &lt;strong&gt;90% LTV&lt;/strong&gt; in most cases, and up to &lt;strong&gt;100% LTV&lt;/strong&gt; with certain lenders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means you can access significantly more equity than conventional or FHA cash-out options while keeping favorable VA loan terms. However, VA cash-out refinancing comes with a 2.15%-3.3% funding fee (waived for disabled veterans), and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to meet credit, income, and residual income requirements. Understanding when VA cash-out makes sense—and when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t—helps you make the right financial decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
