<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funding Fee on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/funding-fee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funding Fee on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/funding-fee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funding Fee Waiver Playbook for VA Buyers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten veterans how the funding fee works and you will hear legends, half-truths, and rumors about mysterious VA decisions. The fee funds the program, which means lenders scrutinize every waiver request and every dollar collected. Instead of waiting for the underwriter to tell you what is missing, build a playbook that covers entitlement math, disability documentation, and what to do if the waiver is not yet on your Certificate of Eligibility (COE). Here is the same structure we walk through during BrowseLenders coaching calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VA Cash-Out Refinance: How I Accessed 100% LTV with Zero Down Payment History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancemortgages/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-how-i-accessed-100-percent-ltv-with-zero-down-payment-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancemortgages/blogs/va-cash-out-refinance-how-i-accessed-100-percent-ltv-with-zero-down-payment-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a Navy veteran who bought my home in 2019 with a VA loan and zero down payment, I always knew the VA loan benefit was valuable. What I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize was that the VA cash-out refinance program would let me access up to 90-100% of my home&amp;rsquo;s value—even though I never put a penny down originally.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last year, I used VA cash-out refinance to pull out $68,000 at 90% LTV to pay off high-interest debt and fund home improvements. Here&amp;rsquo;s exactly how it works and why it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best-kept secrets in the veteran community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Claim VA Funding Fee Exemptions: A Step-by-Step Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/how-to-claim-funding-fee-exemption-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/how-to-claim-funding-fee-exemption-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The VA funding fee costs between 1.4% and 3.6% of your loan amount depending on your down payment, loan type, and whether it&amp;rsquo;s your first VA loan use. For a $400,000 purchase with zero down, that&amp;rsquo;s $5,600 to $14,400—a substantial upfront cost that gets rolled into your loan balance and increases your monthly payment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, veterans with service-connected disabilities rated at 10% or higher are &lt;strong&gt;completely exempt&lt;/strong&gt; from the VA funding fee. Surviving spouses of veterans who died in service or from service-connected conditions are also exempt. These exemptions can save thousands of dollars, yet many eligible veterans miss out because they don&amp;rsquo;t know how to claim the exemption or fail to provide the correct documentation to lenders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
