<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assets on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/assets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assets on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:55:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/assets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our Asset Depletion Sprint Before Rate Sheets Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/asset-depletion-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/asset-depletion-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asset depletion loans sound simple—show enough money, get approved—but every underwriter asks the same questions about seasoning, withdrawals, and exit plans. After watching a rate sheet worsen while we hunted for a missing statement, we built a five-day sprint that keeps the entire asset story tidy. Here is how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-inventory-and-intent&#34;&gt;Day 1: Inventory and intent&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We start with a whiteboard session listing every account we plan to use: brokerage, retirement, trust, and cash-value insurance. For each line we note ownership, recent large deposits, and whether withdrawals trigger penalties. Then we mirror that list in the overlay spreadsheet from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.browselenders.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BrowseLenders.com&lt;/a&gt;. The sheet forces us to record which lenders accept each account type and what percentage of the balance they use for qualifying income. That clarity prevents arguments later when someone insists, “But Bank X counted the whole thing last year.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
