<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VA Strategy on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/va-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VA Strategy on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/va-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funding Fee Waiver Playbook for VA Buyers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten veterans how the funding fee works and you will hear legends, half-truths, and rumors about mysterious VA decisions. The fee funds the program, which means lenders scrutinize every waiver request and every dollar collected. Instead of waiting for the underwriter to tell you what is missing, build a playbook that covers entitlement math, disability documentation, and what to do if the waiver is not yet on your Certificate of Eligibility (COE). Here is the same structure we walk through during BrowseLenders coaching calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BAH Budget War-Gaming Before You Write a VA Offer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/bah-offer-budget-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/bah-offer-budget-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BAH is more than a monthly deposit. It is a living constraint that either keeps your VA offer disciplined or sets you up for payment regret. Most of the budget panic we see happens because buyers stare at the BAH line in MyPay without modeling how that allowance collides with utilities, temporary lodging, or life during a PCS. Use this field manual to war-game your numbers before you fall for a listing that quietly outpaces your cash flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
