<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conforming Home Loan Education on Conforming Home Loans</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/</link><description>Recent content in Conforming Home Loan Education on Conforming Home Loans</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conforminghomeloan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits: How to Plan Before Listing or Locking</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/2025-conforming-loan-limits-how-to-plan-before-listing-or-locking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/2025-conforming-loan-limits-how-to-plan-before-listing-or-locking/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Homeowners, builders, and real estate agents love the headline every fall: “FHFA raises conforming loan limits again.” The increase always feels like free money, yet the borrowers who actually benefit are the ones who run the math long before a purchase offer or refinance lock. This guide breaks down the 2025 conforming loan limit change, shows how high-balance thresholds really work, and shares the preparation steps that keep you in control when lenders start quoting rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Middle Credit Score Roadmap to a Conforming Loan Approval</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/my-middle-credit-score-roadmap-to-a-conforming-loan-approval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/my-middle-credit-score-roadmap-to-a-conforming-loan-approval/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When my lender told me my “middle score” was 671, I felt blindsided. I monitor my credit through two different consumer apps, and both said I was in the low 700s. What followed was an eight-week sprint to learn how middle credit scores really work, fix the items dragging mine down, and earn the rate I wanted on a conforming loan. This isn’t theory—it’s the exact roadmap I used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="week-1-request-the-same-data-lenders-see"&gt;Week 1: Request the same data lenders see&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auto-scores, VantageScores, and bank-provided updates are directional, not definitive. My loan officer suggested I pull a tri-merge report through a mortgage-preferred vendor so I could see every bureau line item the underwriter would analyze. The $60 fee hurt less than paying a higher rate for 30 years. Once the report arrived, I created a spreadsheet with three columns—Equifax, Experian, TransUnion—and highlighted the differences. Two medical collections showed on one bureau while the others marked them as paid. Utilization appeared at 54% on a travel card because the statement cut before my payment hit. With the real data in hand, I was able to set priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Compared Three Conforming Lenders Before Locking—Here’s the Checklist</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/i-compared-three-conforming-lenders-before-lockingheres-the-checklist/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/i-compared-three-conforming-lenders-before-lockingheres-the-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Mortgage advice often falls into two camps: “Shop at least three lenders” or “Loyalty matters more than rate.” The truth sits in the middle. When I shopped for a conforming loan this summer, I wanted the transparency of multiple quotes without turning my phone into a call-center hotline. Below is the checklist I used to compare three lenders—and the lessons that helped me pick the right partner without drowning in spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Desktop Underwriter vs. Loan Product Advisor: Navigating AUS Findings Like a Pro</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/desktop-underwriter-vs.-loan-product-advisor-navigating-aus-findings-like-a-pro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/desktop-underwriter-vs.-loan-product-advisor-navigating-aus-findings-like-a-pro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Conforming loans live and die by automated underwriting systems (AUS). You can submit the same borrower profile to Fannie Mae’s Desktop Underwriter (DU) and Freddie Mac’s Loan Product Advisor (LPA) and receive two very different findings. Understanding why those responses diverge—and how to answer them—turns AUS from a mysterious gatekeeper into a predictable guide. Here’s the playbook we share with borrowers before their files ever reach an underwriter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="du-and-lpa-look-at-the-same-inputs-differently"&gt;DU and LPA look at the same inputs differently&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both systems analyze the “four Cs”: credit, capacity, collateral, and capital. DU tends to reward longer credit histories and higher reserves, while LPA occasionally gives more flexibility on debt-to-income ratios when compensating factors exist. Before you run either system, verify that the tri-merge credit report is accurate and that income documents align with the numbers in your loan application (Form 1003). AUS findings only know what you feed them—garbage in, garbage out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conforming Cash-Out vs. Second Lien: Six Calculations I Won’t Skip Again</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/conforming-cash-out-vs.-second-lien-six-calculations-i-wont-skip-again/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/conforming-cash-out-vs.-second-lien-six-calculations-i-wont-skip-again/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When my kitchen remodel estimate landed at $78,000, I had two options: refinance my entire first mortgage with a conforming cash-out loan or leave the low-rate first alone and open a second lien. The obsession with “never touch a low rate” is popular on social media, but real math told a different story. Here are the six calculations that guided my decision—and the lessons any homeowner can apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-blended-rate-comparison"&gt;1. Blended rate comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by writing down the current balance and rate on my first mortgage ($452,000 at 3.125%) and the quotes for potential second liens (9.5% HELOC, 10.25% home equity loan). Then I calculated the blended rate: ((First balance x first rate) + (Second balance x second rate)) / Combined balance. Keeping the first mortgage and adding a HELOC produced an effective rate of 4.62%. The conforming cash-out refinance quote landed at 6.125% for the entire balance. On the surface, keeping the first mortgage looked cheaper, but blended rates only tell part of the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How We Bought with 5% Down and Still Won a Multiple-Offer Battle</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/how-we-bought-with-5-down-and-still-won-a-multiple-offer-battle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/how-we-bought-with-5-down-and-still-won-a-multiple-offer-battle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When my partner and I decided to buy our first home, saving 20% felt impossible. We live in a high-cost market where starter homes hover near $720,000, and we didn’t want to spend another three years renting while prices climbed. Instead, we built a 5% down conforming strategy that won a multiple-offer situation and sailed through underwriting. Here’s how we did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="step-1-budget-backwards-from-the-payment"&gt;Step 1: Budget backwards from the payment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than picking a list price and hoping the payment worked, we opened a spreadsheet and reverse-engineered affordability. We entered the loan amount (95% of projected prices), current conforming rates, and estimated PMI premiums. We added taxes, insurance, HOA dues, and a buffer for maintenance. The target payment number told us the true maximum purchase price we could tolerate. That discipline prevented us from chasing homes that would have made every month feel tight.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Our HR Team Added a Conforming Loan Wellness Benefit</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/why-our-hr-team-added-a-conforming-loan-wellness-benefit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/why-our-hr-team-added-a-conforming-loan-wellness-benefit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When our company refreshed its financial wellness program, the HR team asked employees what stressed them most. The top answer wasn’t retirement or student loans—it was figuring out how to qualify for a mortgage without getting ripped off. That insight led us to pilot a conforming loan education benefit. After six months, here’s what we learned, what employees loved, and how we measured success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="step-1-define-the-problem-accurately"&gt;Step 1: Define the problem accurately&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employees didn’t just want a “mortgage calculator.” They wanted unbiased guidance on conforming loan limits, debt-to-income ratios, middle credit scores, and when to refinance. We surveyed staff anonymously and discovered three themes:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>