<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Plan on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/project-plan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Plan on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:10:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/project-plan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our Three-Meeting HELOC Strategy Sprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/homeequityloanspecialist/blogs/heloc-strategy-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/homeequityloanspecialist/blogs/heloc-strategy-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We treat big borrowing decisions the same way we handle product launches: short sprints, clear owners, and a doc that captures every loose thread. When it came time to draw on our home equity, we scheduled three focused meetings over one weekend. By Sunday night we knew how much to request, which debts to fold in, and how to present the story to our loan officer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-1-clarify-the-intention-statement&#34;&gt;Meeting 1: Clarify the intention statement&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We opened the sprint with a simple question—why are we touching equity now? The answers ranged from finishing a half-completed kitchen to wiping out a pair of high-rate cards. Once we listed every motivation, we prioritized them by impact on monthly cash flow. That exercise forced us to hold the renovation plan loosely and commit to debt reduction first. A quick screen share of payoff projections from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cash-outrefinance.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cash-OutRefinance.com&lt;/a&gt; helped everyone see how a blended cash-out plus HELOC path compared to the line-only option. We logged the pros and cons in our sprint doc so the reasoning would still make sense months later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
