<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cost Analysis on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/cost-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cost Analysis on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/cost-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Refinance Broker Fees and Lender Costs in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/compare-broker-fees-refinance-costs-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/compare-broker-fees-refinance-costs-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A homeowner called me after signing her refinance papers: &amp;ldquo;The broker charged me $4,500 in fees plus the lender charged $3,200. I thought brokers were supposed to save me money—did I get ripped off?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I reviewed her Closing Disclosure. The &amp;ldquo;$4,500 broker fee&amp;rdquo; was actually $1,200 to the broker plus $3,300 in title, appraisal, and other third-party costs that every refinance has regardless of who you use. The $3,200 &amp;ldquo;lender fees&amp;rdquo; were mostly prepaid taxes and insurance that go into escrow, not lender profit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage Brokers vs Banks vs Credit Unions: Which Lender Type Saves You the Most Money in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/mortgage-brokers-vs-banks-vs-credit-unions-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/mortgage-brokers-vs-banks-vs-credit-unions-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My sister-in-law refinanced her mortgage three times in the past decade. The first time, she used Wells Fargo (her bank) and got 4.25% when the market average was 3.875%. The second time, she used a credit union and got 3.125% when the market was 3.25%—a great deal. The third time, she used a mortgage broker and got 2.625% when the market was 2.75%—the best deal of all three.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same borrower, similar market conditions, but three completely different experiences and outcomes. The lender type mattered more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
