<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>High-Cost Areas on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/high-cost-areas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in High-Cost Areas on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/high-cost-areas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Saved $42,000 by Understanding My County&#39;s $1.09M Conforming Limit: Jumbo vs. High-Balance Conforming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/i-saved-42000-by-understanding-my-countys-conforming-limit-jumbo-vs-high-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/i-saved-42000-by-understanding-my-countys-conforming-limit-jumbo-vs-high-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my husband and I were transferred to Seattle for work in early 2024, we started looking at homes in the Eastside suburbs—Bellevue, Redmond, Sammamish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sticker shock was real:&lt;/strong&gt; Entry-level 3-bedroom homes started at $900,000.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming from Ohio where we&amp;rsquo;d owned a nice 4-bedroom home for $320,000, we assumed a $950,000 mortgage would require jumbo financing with all the associated costs—higher rates, larger down payment, deeper reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-non-conforming-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-non-conforming-2025/</guid>
      <description>A clear guide to conforming vs. non-conforming mortgages in 2025: loan limits, pricing differences, and strategies to qualify — with resources from Middle Credit Score® and Browse Lenders®.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits by State – Updated FHFA Guidelines, High-Cost Areas, and Borrowing Insights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-conforming-loan-limits-by-state-updated-fhfa-guidelines-high-cost-areas-and-borrowing-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-conforming-loan-limits-by-state-updated-fhfa-guidelines-high-cost-areas-and-borrowing-insights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) announces new conforming loan limits—the maximum loan amounts that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac will purchase from lenders. For 2025, the baseline conforming loan limit is &lt;strong&gt;$766,550&lt;/strong&gt; for single-family homes in most counties, with high-cost areas reaching up to &lt;strong&gt;$1,149,825&lt;/strong&gt;. Understanding these limits by state and county is essential for determining whether you need conforming, high-balance conforming, or jumbo financing—and how your loan amount affects rate eligibility and approval odds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 High-Balance Conventional Loans: County Map, Qualifying Rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-high-balance-conventional-loans-county-map-qualifying-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-high-balance-conventional-loans-county-map-qualifying-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-balance conventional loans&lt;/strong&gt; are conforming loans that exceed the baseline FHFA limit ($766,550 for 2025) but stay within the higher limits designated for high-cost counties—up to $1,149,825 for single-family homes. These loans meet Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac underwriting standards but require slightly stricter qualification than baseline conforming loans, including higher credit scores, additional reserves, and sometimes larger down payments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re buying in expensive metro areas like San Francisco, Seattle, New York City, or Honolulu, understanding high-balance loan limits and qualification rules is essential for accessing competitive rates without jumping to jumbo financing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
