<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loan Approval on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/loan-approval/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Loan Approval on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/loan-approval/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FHA Loan Credit Score Requirements 2025: Complete Guide to Minimum Scores and Approval Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-credit-score-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-credit-score-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most first-time buyers don&amp;rsquo;t realize: FHA loans accept credit scores that would get you laughed out of a conventional lender&amp;rsquo;s office. But there&amp;rsquo;s a catch—understanding the difference between official FHA minimums and actual lender requirements can mean the difference between approval and rejection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me break down exactly how credit scores work with FHA financing, what minimums really matter, and proven strategies to maximize your approval odds even with credit challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Credit Score Do You Really Need for a Mortgage in 2025? Lender-by-Lender Breakdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A borrower called me frustrated last week: &amp;ldquo;I have a 665 credit score. Fannie Mae says they approve 620 and above for conventional loans, so why did three banks deny my application?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the credit score confusion that costs thousands of borrowers their dream homes every year. There&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;strong&gt;program minimum&lt;/strong&gt; (what Fannie Mae, FHA, or VA requires) and then there&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;strong&gt;lender minimum&lt;/strong&gt; (what each bank or broker actually approves). These two numbers can be 40-60 points apart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 43% DTI Got Approved for $385,000 Purchase - But 46% Was Denied, Here&#39;s Why</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/my-43-percent-dti-got-approved-for-385000-purchase-but-46-percent-was-denied-heres-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/my-43-percent-dti-got-approved-for-385000-purchase-but-46-percent-was-denied-heres-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I applied for a conventional purchase mortgage in September 2024 with $92,000 annual income, 708 credit score, and 10% down payment on a $385,000 home. My debt-to-income ratio was 46.2%. I was confident I would be approved—my income was strong, my credit was above the 700 threshold, and I had substantial down payment saved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The underwriter denied my application citing &amp;ldquo;debt-to-income ratio exceeds maximum allowable threshold for program guidelines without sufficient compensating factors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
