<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Manual Underwriting on Bad Credit Loan Specialist</title><link>https://www.badcreditloanspecialist.com/tags/manual-underwriting/</link><description>Recent content in Manual Underwriting on Bad Credit Loan Specialist</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.badcreditloanspecialist.com/tags/manual-underwriting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manual Underwriting Explained: How Bad Credit Borrowers Get Approved</title><link>https://www.badcreditloanspecialist.com/blogs/manual-underwriting-explained-how-bad-credit-borrowers-get-approved/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.badcreditloanspecialist.com/blogs/manual-underwriting-explained-how-bad-credit-borrowers-get-approved/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Automated underwriting systems like Desktop Underwriter (Fannie Mae) and Loan Prospector (Freddie Mac) reject most bad credit applications instantly based on credit scores alone. Manual underwriting removes the automated system and assigns a human underwriter to review your full financial profile—income stability, payment history, compensating factors, and reasons for past credit issues. This process allows approval for borrowers automated systems deny, making it the primary path to homeownership for consumers with credit scores below 620.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Get a Mortgage with a 500-579 Credit Score in 2025</title><link>https://www.badcreditloanspecialist.com/blogs/how-to-get-a-mortgage-with-a-500-579-credit-score-in-2025/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.badcreditloanspecialist.com/blogs/how-to-get-a-mortgage-with-a-500-579-credit-score-in-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A 500-579 credit score puts you in the &amp;ldquo;very poor&amp;rdquo; credit range according to FICO standards, and most lenders will reject your mortgage application automatically. However, FHA loans allow 500-579 scores with a 10% down payment and manual underwriting—meaning human review of your full financial picture instead of automated rejection. Thousands of borrowers with scores in this range get approved every year by working with bad credit specialists who know which FHA lenders accept manual underwriting and how to present compensating factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>