<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home Equity on HELOC Loan Officers</title><link>https://helocloanofficers.com/tags/home-equity/</link><description>Recent content in Home Equity on HELOC Loan Officers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://helocloanofficers.com/tags/home-equity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HELOC Draw Period vs Repayment Period: What Every Homeowner Must Know</title><link>https://helocloanofficers.com/blogs/heloc-draw-period-vs-repayment-period-what-every-homeowner-must-know/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://helocloanofficers.com/blogs/heloc-draw-period-vs-repayment-period-what-every-homeowner-must-know/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake HELOC borrowers make is not understanding how payments change between the draw period and repayment period. This two-phase structure creates payment shock for unprepared homeowners—but strategic planning turns HELOC flexibility into a powerful financial tool rather than a payment burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-a-heloc-draw-period"&gt;What is a HELOC Draw Period?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The draw period is the initial phase of your HELOC when you can borrow against your approved credit limit, repay, and borrow again—similar to a credit card but secured by your home equity. Draw periods typically last 10 years, though some lenders offer 5-year or 15-year options.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HELOC Requirements 2025: Credit Score, Income, and Equity Guidelines by Lender Type</title><link>https://helocloanofficers.com/blogs/heloc-requirements-2025-credit-score-income-and-equity-guidelines-by-lender-type/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://helocloanofficers.com/blogs/heloc-requirements-2025-credit-score-income-and-equity-guidelines-by-lender-type/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;HELOC approval isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as having home equity—lenders evaluate credit scores, debt-to-income ratios, combined loan-to-value limits, income stability, and payment history through structured underwriting guidelines that vary significantly by lender type. Understanding these requirements before applying helps borrowers strengthen weak areas, choose appropriate lenders, and avoid unnecessary credit inquiries from lenders who won&amp;rsquo;t approve their profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="minimum-credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type"&gt;Minimum Credit Score Requirements by Lender Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit score minimums for HELOC approval vary widely depending on whether you apply through big banks, credit unions, online lenders, or portfolio lenders. Each lender type serves different credit tiers with corresponding rate and term adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HELOC Basics: A Complete Guide for Homeowners</title><link>https://helocloanofficers.com/blogs/heloc-basics-a-complete-guide-for-homeowners/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://helocloanofficers.com/blogs/heloc-basics-a-complete-guide-for-homeowners/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) is a flexible financing option that allows homeowners to borrow against the equity in their homes. Understanding how HELOCs work can help you make informed financial decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-a-heloc"&gt;What is a HELOC?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A HELOC is a revolving line of credit secured by your home. Unlike a traditional loan where you receive a lump sum, a HELOC provides access to funds as needed during the draw period.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>