<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mortgage Education on First Time Buyer Options</title><link>https://www.firsttimebuyeroptions.com/categories/mortgage-education/</link><description>Recent content in Mortgage Education on First Time Buyer Options</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.firsttimebuyeroptions.com/categories/mortgage-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FHA vs Conventional Loans for First-Time Buyers 2025: Which Saves You More Money?</title><link>https://www.firsttimebuyeroptions.com/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-for-first-time-buyers-2025-which-saves-you-more-money/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.firsttimebuyeroptions.com/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-for-first-time-buyers-2025-which-saves-you-more-money/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fha-vs-conventional-loans-the-ultimate-first-time-buyer-decision-guide"&gt;FHA vs Conventional Loans: The Ultimate First-Time Buyer Decision Guide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask ten first-time buyers which loan type they should choose, and eight will guess wrong. That&amp;rsquo;s because the FHA versus conventional decision isn&amp;rsquo;t about which is universally better—it&amp;rsquo;s about which costs less money over your specific ownership period given your credit score, down payment amount, and how long you plan to keep the loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most buyers make this choice based on down payment requirements alone, completely ignoring mortgage insurance costs that can differ by $30,000-$50,000 over the loan life. Let me show you exactly how to analyze both options so you choose the loan type that maximizes your financial position.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First-Time Homebuyer Credit Score Requirements 2025: Minimum Scores for Every Loan Type</title><link>https://www.firsttimebuyeroptions.com/blogs/first-time-homebuyer-credit-score-requirements-2025-minimum-scores-for-every-loan-type/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.firsttimebuyeroptions.com/blogs/first-time-homebuyer-credit-score-requirements-2025-minimum-scores-for-every-loan-type/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="first-time-homebuyer-credit-score-requirements-what-you-really-need-to-qualify"&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Credit Score Requirements: What You Really Need to Qualify&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what stops most first-time buyers from even trying: they assume perfect credit is required to buy a home. The truth? You can qualify for a government-backed mortgage with a credit score that would get you rejected for a decent credit card. But understanding the difference between official minimums and real-world lender requirements is crucial for setting realistic timelines and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>