<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Residual Income on Veteran Mortgage Lenders</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/tags/residual-income/</link><description>Recent content in Residual Income on Veteran Mortgage Lenders</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:05:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/tags/residual-income/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PCS Overlap Cash-Flow Map for VA Buyers</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/pcs-overlap-cash-flow-map-for-va-buyers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:05:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/pcs-overlap-cash-flow-map-for-va-buyers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every VA buyer secretly fears the same thing: getting pinned between two sets of housing costs while PCS orders march forward. Cash gets trapped in deposits, pay periods bounce, and suddenly the underwriting call feels more stressful than deployment prep. The antidote is a cash-flow map that treats overlap months like a temporary campaign, not a chaotic surprise. Grab a whiteboard, your favorite spreadsheet, and this guide—we will walk through the same framework we coach service members on every week.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BAH Budget War-Gaming Before You Write a VA Offer</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/bah-budget-war-gaming-before-you-write-a-va-offer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/bah-budget-war-gaming-before-you-write-a-va-offer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;BAH is more than a monthly deposit. It is a living constraint that either keeps your VA offer disciplined or sets you up for payment regret. Most of the budget panic we see happens because buyers stare at the BAH line in MyPay without modeling how that allowance collides with utilities, temporary lodging, or life during a PCS. Use this field manual to war-game your numbers before you fall for a listing that quietly outpaces your cash flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>