<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escrow on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/escrow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Escrow on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/escrow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VA Renovation Bid Tracker for Tidy Underwriting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few things spike blood pressure like trying to squeeze contractor bids, inspection responses, and VA renovation overlays into the same week. Most buyers treat the process like a scavenger hunt, which is why lenders slow-walk approvals. Build a repeatable bid tracker instead. The framework below is tuned for service members who juggle PCS timelines, guard drills, and family life yet still want to close on a property that needs work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 90-Day Payment Transition Roadmap After a Cash-Out Refi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancecalculators/blogs/payment-transition-roadmap-90-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancecalculators/blogs/payment-transition-roadmap-90-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our cash-out refinance closed, the monthly payment climbed by $532. Rather than absorb the shock haphazardly, I used the payment transition calculator to build a 90-day roadmap. The plan combined automation, side-income pacing, and escrow tracking so the new payment felt normalized by the third month. Here’s how the roadmap worked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;days-1-10-snapshot-the-new-obligation&#34;&gt;Days 1-10: Snapshot the new obligation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the first payment was due, I exported the calculator report showing principal, interest, taxes, insurance, and HOA line items. I compared each component to the old payment and highlighted the differences. Escrow alone accounted for $217 of the increase because the lender projected higher property taxes after the renovation. Knowing that breakdown helped me explain the changes to my spouse and prevented sticker shock when the first statement arrived. I also created a dedicated savings sub-account titled “Mortgage Buffer” and funded it with one extra payment using part of the refinance proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
