<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Down Payment on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/down-payment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Down Payment on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/down-payment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Home Buyer Guide for Florida: Documentation, Credit, and Loan Officer Selection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/first-time-home-buyer-guide-for-florida-documentation-credit-loan-officer-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/first-time-home-buyer-guide-for-florida-documentation-credit-loan-officer-selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying your first home in Florida is a significant financial decision. Understanding documentation requirements, credit expectations, down payment options, and how loan officers evaluate your application helps you approach the process with confidence and avoid surprises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-down-payment-requirements-for-first-time-buyers&#34;&gt;Understanding Down Payment Requirements for First-Time Buyers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimum Down Payments by Program:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conventional Loans:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3% down (with mortgage insurance)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5% down (less mortgage insurance)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10-20% down (minimal or no mortgage insurance)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FHA Loans (Popular for First-Time Buyers):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3% Down vs 20% Down: Which Home Purchase Strategy Actually Saves You Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/3-percent-down-vs-20-percent-down-which-home-purchase-strategy-actually-saves-you-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/3-percent-down-vs-20-percent-down-which-home-purchase-strategy-actually-saves-you-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years, the conventional wisdom was simple: save 20% down to avoid PMI and get the best mortgage terms. But here&amp;rsquo;s what nobody tells you—waiting five extra years to save 20% down might cost you more money than just buying now with 3% down and paying PMI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I learned this lesson the hard way when I spent three years religiously saving for a 20% down payment while home prices in my market rose 8% annually. By the time I had my 20% saved, the homes I was looking at cost $80,000 more—and my &amp;ldquo;savings&amp;rdquo; on PMI was wiped out by appreciation I missed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming Loan Down Payment Options: 3% Down Programs and Smart Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-down-payment-options-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-down-payment-options-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest misconceptions about conforming loans is that you need a 20% down payment to qualify. The reality? Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac offer multiple pathways to homeownership with down payments as low as 3%—and understanding these options can help you buy sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-down-payment-size-matters&#34;&gt;Why Down Payment Size Matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your down payment affects three critical factors: loan approval odds, monthly payment amounts, and whether you&amp;rsquo;ll pay private mortgage insurance (PMI). But here&amp;rsquo;s what many borrowers miss: a smaller down payment doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean worse terms if you&amp;rsquo;re using a conforming loan backed by government-sponsored enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide 2025: From 0% to 20% and Everything Between</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-time-homebuyer-down-payment-guide-how-much-you-really-need-to-buy&#34;&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide: How Much You Really Need to Buy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest myth keeping renters from becoming homeowners? The belief that you need 20% down to buy a house. Here&amp;rsquo;s reality: over 70% of first-time buyers put down less than 10%, and many successful buyers put down as little as 0-3.5%. Understanding your real down payment options—and how to maximize them—can help you buy years sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Buyers and Conventional Loans: Credit, Down Payments, and Rate Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/first-time-buyers-conventional-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/first-time-buyers-conventional-2025/</guid>
      <description>Your 2025 roadmap to buying your first home with a conventional mortgage: credit requirements, down payment paths, rate strategy, and PMI tips — with resources from Middle Credit Score® and Browse Lenders®.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. FHA Loans in 2025: Key Differences, Credit Requirements, and Loan Limits Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When comparing &lt;strong&gt;conforming loans&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;FHA loans&lt;/strong&gt; in 2025, the biggest differences come down to credit requirements, down payment flexibility, loan limits, and long-term costs. Conforming loans (backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac) offer better rates and lower lifetime costs for borrowers with strong credit, while FHA loans (insured by the Federal Housing Administration) provide easier qualification for borrowers with lower credit scores and smaller down payments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding which loan type fits your financial profile helps you save money, qualify faster, and avoid unnecessary costs over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should You Put 20% Down on a Conventional Loan? Let&#39;s Do the Math</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/should-you-put-20-percent-down-conventional-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalloanofficers/blogs/should-you-put-20-percent-down-conventional-loan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You need 20% down to buy a house.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I had a dollar for every time I heard someone repeat this myth, I could probably make a down payment myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the truth: you don&amp;rsquo;t need 20% down for a conventional loan. You can buy a home with as little as 3% down if you&amp;rsquo;re a first-time buyer, or 5% if you&amp;rsquo;re a repeat buyer. But whether you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; put down less than 20% depends on your financial situation, goals, and what else you could do with that money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Buyers and Conventional Loans: Credit, Down Payments, and Rate Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First-time homebuyers&lt;/strong&gt; often assume they need FHA loans or 20% down payments to buy a home—but conventional loans offer some of the best financing options for first-time buyers in 2025, including &lt;strong&gt;3% down payment programs&lt;/strong&gt;, competitive rates for borrowers with 620+ credit scores, and access to conforming loan limits up to $766,550 (or $1,149,825 in high-cost areas). Understanding how conventional loans work, what credit and income requirements you need to meet, and how to avoid common mistakes helps you qualify faster and save money over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA 3.5% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Ran the Numbers for My $310,000 Purchase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/fha-3-5-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchasemortgageloans/blogs/fha-3-5-percent-down-vs-conventional-5-percent-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent three months comparing FHA and conventional loan options before purchasing my first home in August 2024. Every article I read said &amp;ldquo;FHA is for low credit, conventional is for high credit,&amp;rdquo; but with 668 credit score, I qualified for both programs—and the decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the actual math I ran on my $310,000 home purchase, comparing FHA 3.5% down versus conventional 5% down, including all the hidden costs nobody talks about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
