<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Market Data on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/market-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market Data on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/market-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2026 Market Watch: Value Benchmarks to Track Each Quarter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/onlinevaluecalculator/blogs/2026-market-watch-value-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/onlinevaluecalculator/blogs/2026-market-watch-value-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2026 housing landscape will reward owners who track value benchmarks like investors. Instead of waiting for headlines, calendar quarterly check-ins now so you can capture shifts before they become obvious to competing buyers or lenders. Each quarter carries a unique set of signals that informs how aggressively you can price, cash out, or negotiate repairs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Q1 is all about inventory velocity. As fresh listings trickle back after the holidays, monitor months of supply and pending-to-active ratios inside your valuation workbook. When absorption sharpens faster than expected, you can confidently raise your top-end pricing assumptions for spring. If inventory lingers, shift focus to interior refreshes and documentation so you stand out even in a slower pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a Buyer-Ready Home Value Packet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/onlinevaluecalculator/blogs/buyer-ready-value-packet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/onlinevaluecalculator/blogs/buyer-ready-value-packet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Serious buyers and soon-to-be sellers share the same secret weapon: a tidy packet of value evidence. It is more than a folder of screenshots. It is a curated story that helps other decision-makers trust your numbers. When inventory is tight or rates are volatile, the buyers who win are the ones who pair verified financing with a compelling explanation of why their price is fair. Building that packet takes a weekend, yet it removes weeks of stress. Here is how to assemble one that mirrors what agents and underwriters want to see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
