<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Draw Schedule on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/draw-schedule/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Draw Schedule on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/draw-schedule/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Paired Credit Moves With Every FHA 203(k) Draw</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/credit-synced-draws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/credit-synced-draws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) file almost derailed before demo day because I underestimated how every trip to the hardware store would show up on my credit reports. I had the cash to cover purchases, but lenders only see balances—if utilization spikes between draws, approvals wobble. I avoided disaster by aligning each credit move with the draw schedule, then documenting it inside MiddleCreditScore.com so the lender could see my logic. Here is the playbook that kept my middle score steady while the rehab charged forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Turned HUD Consultant Check-Ins into Weekly Office Hours</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/hud-consultant-office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fha203kmortgages/blogs/hud-consultant-office-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My FHA 203(k) felt chaotic until we turned random phone calls into structured “office hours” with the HUD consultant. Every Thursday at 4:00 p.m. we hop on a 30-minute video call, camera on, scopes open. It sounds small, but since launching the ritual we have had zero surprise inspection fails, zero missing invoices, and just one change-order dispute (which we resolved live). If you’re about to start a rehab, here’s a blueprint you can copy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Bought a Fixer-Upper with an FHA 203(k) Loan: Here&#39;s What Nobody Told Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/i-bought-a-fixer-upper-with-an-fha-203k-loan-here-is-what-nobody-told-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/i-bought-a-fixer-upper-with-an-fha-203k-loan-here-is-what-nobody-told-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I found a 1970s ranch house listed at &lt;strong&gt;$215,000&lt;/strong&gt; in a great neighborhood (where comparable updated homes sold for $320,000+), we knew it was a diamond in the rough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The house needed &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;: new kitchen, both bathrooms gutted, flooring throughout, updated electrical, new HVAC, and cosmetic work in every room.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t have $100,000 sitting around for renovations. Traditional financing wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work—no bank will give you a mortgage on a house with a non-functioning kitchen and electrical code violations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction Draw Schedule Explained: Understanding the Construction Loan Draw Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/construction-draw-schedule-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/construction-draw-schedule-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve never financed construction before, one of the most confusing aspects of construction loans is the draw schedule—how lenders release money in stages rather than all at once, why you only pay interest on drawn funds during construction, and what happens if your builder needs more money than the approved draw amount for a particular stage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding construction draw schedules is essential before signing builder contracts or finalizing construction financing. The draw process affects your builder&amp;rsquo;s cash flow, determines when you start making loan payments, and creates checkpoints where lender inspections verify your project is progressing as planned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Build Timeline Management: Managing Construction Loan Timelines and Draw Schedules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/custom-build-timeline-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/custom-build-timeline-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building a custom home is one of the most complex financial and logistical projects most people will ever undertake. Unlike buying an existing home where you close and move in within weeks, custom builds span months or even years—requiring you to coordinate builders, subcontractors, inspectors, lenders, and dozens of moving parts while managing a construction loan with draw schedules, interest-only payments, and rate lock expirations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Poor timeline management can derail your construction financing: missed draw deadlines create builder cash flow problems, construction delays push your completion beyond rate lock expiration (forcing expensive extensions or relocks at higher rates), and budget overruns consume contingency funds that were meant to cover unexpected issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
