<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Refinance on Conventional Mortgage</title><link>https://conventionalmtg.com/categories/refinance/</link><description>Recent content in Refinance on Conventional Mortgage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conventionalmtg.com/categories/refinance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sunday Recast Dry Run That Keeps Our Conventional Refi Honest</title><link>https://conventionalmtg.com/blogs/the-sunday-recast-dry-run-that-keeps-our-conventional-refi-honest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conventionalmtg.com/blogs/the-sunday-recast-dry-run-that-keeps-our-conventional-refi-honest/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A recast sounds glamorous until you actually have to wire the lump sum and prove you understand the math. Our lender asks for a “recast readiness summary” once a quarter, so we turned the request into a standing Sunday ritual. The dry run forces us to document payments, rehearse how we would explain the cash source, and show we have a plan if markets shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="step-1-pull-the-latest-amortization-snapshot"&gt;Step 1: Pull the latest amortization snapshot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We open the amortization tab in our scenario lab spreadsheet and download the current balance, next payment, and unpaid principal portion. Then we duplicate the sheet and drop in our target principal curtailment. Watching the payment change—even slightly—makes the future recast feel real. It also arms us with a slide that shows exactly how much faster the loan would pay off.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Our Rate-Lock Fire Drill: Points vs Par In One Evening</title><link>https://conventionalmtg.com/blogs/our-rate-lock-fire-drill-points-vs-par-in-one-evening/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:15:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conventionalmtg.com/blogs/our-rate-lock-fire-drill-points-vs-par-in-one-evening/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender texts “I’d lock by tonight,” we default to a playbook we nicknamed the rate-lock fire drill. The protocol keeps us from panic-deciding whether to pay points, float, or pivot to a shorter lock. Within two hours we have updated pricing tests, fresh credit notes, and talking points for the entire decision chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="step-1-define-the-window-and-the-stakes"&gt;Step 1: Define the window and the stakes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first voice memo goes into the family chat explaining what is happening and why tonight matters. Then we confirm the real deadline. Sometimes “lock tonight” is code for “rates are trending up but you likely have until noon tomorrow.” We pin the actual cut-off to the top of our shared task board. At the same time we confirm the property status: appraisal done, title clear, insurance quote ready. If one of those is missing, we can’t justify an expensive lock.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>