<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jumbo Lending on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/jumbo-lending/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jumbo Lending on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/jumbo-lending/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Texas Jumbo Reserve Requirements: 6–12 Month PITI Rules Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-jumbo-lenders-demand-substantial-reserves&#34;&gt;Why Jumbo Lenders Demand Substantial Reserves&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jumbo loans carry higher default risk than conforming loans—larger balances, less standardized underwriting, and portfolio retention instead of agency sale. To offset this risk, jumbo lenders require 6–12 months of &lt;strong&gt;PITI reserves&lt;/strong&gt; (principal, interest, taxes, insurance) in liquid or semi-liquid assets. The higher your loan amount, LTV, or complexity, the more reserves you&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reserve requirements aren&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary—they prove you can weather income disruption (job loss, business downturn, market crash) without defaulting. Lenders calculate reserves using &lt;strong&gt;post-closing liquid assets&lt;/strong&gt;: checking, savings, money market, brokerage accounts (with discounting), and sometimes retirement accounts (60%–70% haircut). Real estate equity, business assets, and restricted stock usually don&amp;rsquo;t count.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>California High-Balance Conforming: $1,149,825 Limit Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/californiajumbolenders/blogs/california-high-balance-conforming-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/californiajumbolenders/blogs/california-high-balance-conforming-limit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-californias-jumbo-limit-is-different-and-why-it-matters&#34;&gt;Why California&amp;rsquo;s Jumbo Limit Is Different (And Why It Matters)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;California is one of the most expensive housing markets in the U.S.—and Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac (the government-sponsored enterprises that buy most mortgages) recognize this. Instead of the baseline conforming loan limit of &lt;strong&gt;$766,550&lt;/strong&gt; (2025), most California counties get a &lt;strong&gt;high-balance conforming limit of $1,149,825&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a small detail—it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;rate, reserve, and approval advantage&lt;/strong&gt; that saves California buyers thousands annually. Understanding where the conforming limit ends and jumbo begins determines which lenders you shop, how much you&amp;rsquo;ll pay in interest, and whether you need 6 months or 12 months of reserves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Lenders vs. Agency Jumbo: Which Texas Lender Type Wins?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/portfolio-lenders-vs-agency-jumbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/portfolio-lenders-vs-agency-jumbo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jumbo-lending-fork-portfolio-vs-agency&#34;&gt;The Jumbo Lending Fork: Portfolio vs. Agency&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you apply for a Texas jumbo loan (above $766,550 conforming limit), you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter two fundamentally different lender types: &lt;strong&gt;portfolio lenders&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;agency jumbo lenders&lt;/strong&gt;. The difference isn&amp;rsquo;t just branding—it dictates underwriting flexibility, rate pricing, and whether complex income (self-employed, foreign national, asset-based) gets approved or denied.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portfolio lenders&lt;/strong&gt; (credit unions, private banks, regional banks) hold jumbo loans on their balance sheet instead of selling them to Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, or mortgage-backed security investors. This gives them &lt;strong&gt;underwriting freedom&lt;/strong&gt;—manual approval for compensating factors, bank statement income, asset depletion, and non-standard scenarios that agency guidelines would auto-reject.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stock Compensation &amp; California Jumbo Loans: RSU Underwriting Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/californiajumbolenders/blogs/stock-compensation-jumbo-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/californiajumbolenders/blogs/stock-compensation-jumbo-loans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-stock-compensation-complicates-jumbo-approval&#34;&gt;Why Stock Compensation Complicates Jumbo Approval&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bay Area tech workers earn substantial income from &lt;strong&gt;equity compensation&lt;/strong&gt;—RSUs (restricted stock units), stock options, ESPP (employee stock purchase plans), and performance shares. But mortgage underwriters treat stock comp &lt;strong&gt;very differently&lt;/strong&gt; than W-2 salary. Understanding how lenders count (or don&amp;rsquo;t count) equity income and assets is critical for jumbo loan approval in California&amp;rsquo;s expensive markets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The challenge&lt;/strong&gt;: Most jumbo lenders follow &lt;strong&gt;Fannie Mae/Freddie Mac guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; (even for portfolio loans), which require 2+ years of stock comp history and strict vesting schedules. If you&amp;rsquo;re a new hire at a tech company with a 4-year RSU vesting schedule, traditional lenders may &lt;strong&gt;exclude 75% of your stock comp&lt;/strong&gt; from qualifying income—tanking your debt-to-income ratio and killing your approval.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bay Area vs. SoCal Jumbo Rates: Regional Pricing Differences Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/californiajumbolenders/blogs/bay-area-vs-socal-jumbo-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/californiajumbolenders/blogs/bay-area-vs-socal-jumbo-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-jumbo-rates-vary-across-california&#34;&gt;Why Jumbo Rates Vary Across California&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;California isn&amp;rsquo;t one housing market—it&amp;rsquo;s a collection of distinct regional markets with different median prices, lender competition, property types, and risk profiles. A $2M jumbo loan in &lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto&lt;/strong&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t price the same as a $2M loan in &lt;strong&gt;Fresno&lt;/strong&gt;—even with identical borrower credit, LTV, and reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding &lt;strong&gt;regional jumbo pricing factors&lt;/strong&gt; helps you shop lenders strategically, negotiate better rates, and avoid overpaying based on outdated assumptions about California&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;uniform&amp;rdquo; jumbo market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Texas Jumbo Rates Are Priced: LTV, Credit, and Relationship Banking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-rate-pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-rate-pricing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-jumbo-rates-arent-one-size-fits-all&#34;&gt;Why Jumbo Rates Aren&amp;rsquo;t One-Size-Fits-All&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jumbo mortgage pricing is &lt;strong&gt;radically more complex&lt;/strong&gt; than conforming loans. Conforming rates (Fannie/Freddie) follow standardized Loan Level Price Adjustments (LLPAs)—predictable grids based on credit score and LTV. Jumbo rates? Portfolio lenders and private banks price based on:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loan-to-value (LTV)&lt;/strong&gt;: 70%, 75%, 80%, 85%, 90% → each tier changes rate by 0.125%–0.50%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit score tiers&lt;/strong&gt;: 720, 740, 760, 780+ → jumbo pricing is hypersensitive to credit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loan amount&lt;/strong&gt;: $800K, $1.5M, $2.5M → higher balances trigger risk-based pricing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserves&lt;/strong&gt;: 6 months, 9 months, 12+ months PITI → more reserves can lower rate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship banking&lt;/strong&gt;: Deposits, investment accounts, private banking tier → 0.25%–0.75% discounts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property type&lt;/strong&gt;: Primary residence, second home, investment → non-primary adds 0.50%–1.00%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occupancy &amp;amp; citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: U.S. citizen, foreign national, investor → foreign nationals pay 0.75%–1.50% more&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike conforming loans where &amp;ldquo;760 credit + 75% LTV&amp;rdquo; yields a predictable adjustment, &lt;strong&gt;jumbo pricing is negotiable&lt;/strong&gt;—especially at portfolio lenders and private banks. Understanding these levers helps you &lt;strong&gt;shop strategically&lt;/strong&gt; instead of accepting the first quote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Florida Jumbo Loans Demand Higher Credit Scores</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/jumbo-credit-score-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/jumbo-credit-score-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most borrowers understand that jumbo loans carry stricter requirements than conforming mortgages, but they underestimate just how much credit scores drive approval odds and pricing. While conforming lenders might approve buyers with scores in the mid-600s, jumbo specialists in Florida typically draw the line at 700 and offer their best rates to borrowers above 740. This is not arbitrary pickiness. It reflects fundamental risk differences between government-backed lending and portfolio jumbo products that lenders hold on their own books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Coastal Insurance Actually Costs on Florida Waterfront Jumbo Properties</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/coastal-insurance-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/coastal-insurance-costs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most jumbo borrowers shopping for waterfront homes in Florida focus on purchase price, interest rates, and property taxes, then discover too late that insurance costs dwarf their expectations. A two million dollar beachfront home might carry fifteen thousand dollars a year in combined insurance premiums—wind, flood, umbrella, and homeowners—while a comparable inland luxury property costs a third as much. Lenders underwrite these insurance costs carefully because they increase your debt-to-income ratio and raise the risk that you might let coverage lapse if premiums spike after closing. Understanding what coastal insurance actually costs helps you budget accurately and avoid loan denials based on payment shock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Finance Non-Warrantable Condos in South Florida</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/non-warrantable-condo-financing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/non-warrantable-condo-financing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;South Florida&amp;rsquo;s luxury condo market offers some of the most desirable properties in the state, but many high-rise buildings fail to meet Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac warrantability standards. When a condo project falls into non-warrantable status, conventional and conforming lenders will not touch it, leaving buyers scrambling for financing alternatives. Jumbo lenders are not bound by Fannie or Freddie guidelines, but most still avoid non-warrantable condos because the risks mirror those that made conforming lenders reject them in the first place. Understanding why condos lose warrantable status and which portfolio jumbo products can finance them anyway gives you a path forward when traditional jumbo doors close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Florida Jumbo Loan Limits by County: When Your Purchase Triggers High-Balance Financing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/florida-jumbo-loan-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/florida-jumbo-loan-limits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Florida borrowers shopping for luxury properties often misunderstand when their loan amount crosses into jumbo territory. Conforming loan limits vary significantly by county, and what qualifies as jumbo in Miami-Dade differs from what triggers high-balance requirements in Citrus County. Most buyers assume the national baseline conforming limit applies everywhere, then discover mid-transaction that their loan needs jumbo underwriting with stricter credit scores, larger reserves, and different approval timelines. Knowing your county&amp;rsquo;s limit before you start touring homes prevents surprises and positions you to work with the right lenders from day one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Jumbo Financing for Luxury Condo Towers in Miami and Tampa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/luxury-condo-jumbo-financing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/floridajumbolenders/blogs/luxury-condo-jumbo-financing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Luxury condo towers in Miami, Tampa, and Fort Lauderdale attract high-net-worth buyers seeking waterfront views, resort amenities, and maintenance-free living. But financing a million-dollar condo unit involves complexities that single-family jumbo buyers never encounter. Lenders scrutinize the entire building&amp;rsquo;s financial health, rental ratios, insurance coverage, and legal history before approving your individual loan. A pristine credit profile and substantial down payment mean nothing if the condo association fails warrantability tests or carries litigation that spooks underwriters. Understanding how jumbo lenders evaluate luxury condo projects prevents buyers from falling in love with units they cannot finance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
