<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rate Shopping on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/rate-shopping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rate Shopping on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/rate-shopping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Refinance Rate Shopping Guide 2025: Comparing Brokers vs Banks vs Credit Unions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/refinance-rate-shopping-brokers-vs-banks-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/refinance-rate-shopping-brokers-vs-banks-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten homeowners where they refinanced and you will get ten different answers: their current bank, a big national lender, a local credit union, an online broker, their neighbor&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. But here&amp;rsquo;s what almost none of them did: systematically compare rates across ALL these lender types to find which actually delivered the lowest total cost.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people refinance with whoever makes the process easiest, assuming rates are &amp;ldquo;pretty similar&amp;rdquo; across lenders. That assumption costs tens of thousands of dollars because refinance rates can vary by 0.25-0.75% between lender types—and even more within each category based on your specific credit, property, and loan characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mortgage Brokers Find Better Refinance Rates Than Banks in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/how-brokers-find-better-refinance-rates-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/how-brokers-find-better-refinance-rates-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what most homeowners refinancing their mortgage don&amp;rsquo;t realize: the bank offering you 6.5% would give a mortgage broker 6.125% on the exact same loan. That 0.375% difference costs you over $20,000 on a $300,000 refinance over 30 years—money that stays in your pocket when you use a broker instead of going direct.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason for this pricing gap is simple: brokers access wholesale lender channels that offer better rates than retail bank divisions. Let me show you exactly how this works and why refinancing through a broker beats going direct to your bank in almost every scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Mortgage Lenders: Complete 2025 Guide to Finding the Best Rates and Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/how-to-compare-mortgage-lenders-2025-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/how-to-compare-mortgage-lenders-2025-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend called me last week, excited about buying his first home. &amp;ldquo;I got pre-approved!&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;My bank offered 6.625% on a 30-year conventional loan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I asked if he&amp;rsquo;d compared rates with other lenders. Silence. Then: &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I was supposed to. I just figured my bank would give me a good deal since I&amp;rsquo;ve been with them 15 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two days later, after comparing four additional lenders, he had offers ranging from 6.625% (his bank) down to 5.875% (a mortgage broker accessing wholesale pricing). That 0.75% difference saves him $163 per month—$58,680 over the 30-year loan. All because he spent three hours comparing lenders instead of accepting the first offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
