<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Budget on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/budget/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Budget on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/budget/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VA Renovation Bid Tracker for Tidy Underwriting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few things spike blood pressure like trying to squeeze contractor bids, inspection responses, and VA renovation overlays into the same week. Most buyers treat the process like a scavenger hunt, which is why lenders slow-walk approvals. Build a repeatable bid tracker instead. The framework below is tuned for service members who juggle PCS timelines, guard drills, and family life yet still want to close on a property that needs work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kitchen Table DTI Summit We Host Before Every Conventional Offer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/dti-summit-kitchen-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/dti-summit-kitchen-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I call it the Kitchen Table DTI Summit because it sounds fancier than &amp;ldquo;everyone clear your schedules&amp;rdquo;. The ritual started when we lost a home to a buyer who responded faster to underwriting conditions. Now, every time we think about writing a conventional offer, we gather laptops, printed pay stubs, and a bowl of snacks and walk through six checkpoints. By the end of the evening, we know whether our debt-to-income ratio is ready for scrutiny, what documentation needs refreshing, and how to talk about reserves without stumbling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sunday Debt Consolidation Standup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/homeequityloanspecialist/blogs/debt-consolidation-standup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/homeequityloanspecialist/blogs/debt-consolidation-standup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Home equity can be an incredible lever for debt consolidation, but only if the people using it stay disciplined. Our family built a Sunday evening standup to keep progress visible and reduce the chance that the new credit line simply becomes a more expensive credit card. The ritual takes 30 minutes, involves whoever is attached to the debts, and relies on a living spreadsheet that we update together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-pair-intentions-with-hard-numbers&#34;&gt;Step 1: Pair intentions with hard numbers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We start every standup by opening the payoff tracker that lives next to our interest-rate comparisons from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cash-outrefinance.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cash-OutRefinance.com&lt;/a&gt;. The tracker lists every balance we rolled into the HELOC, the original APR, and the promised payoff date. Seeing the math this way keeps emotions in check. If someone is tempted to swipe a card for a nonessential purchase, they can immediately see how much longer we would carry that balance. We log any new spending ideas in a &amp;ldquo;parking lot&amp;rdquo; column so the thought is captured without derailing the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much House Can You Really Afford? The 28/36 Rule Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/how-much-house-can-you-really-afford-the-28-36-rule-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/how-much-house-can-you-really-afford-the-28-36-rule-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I got pre-approved for a mortgage, my lender told me I qualified for a $450,000 home. I was thrilled—until I sat down with a spreadsheet and realized that buying a $450,000 home would leave me with $300 per month for groceries, gas, and everything else after paying my mortgage, car loan, student loans, and utilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was approved for way more house than I could comfortably afford.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is where the &lt;strong&gt;28/36 rule&lt;/strong&gt; comes in—a simple guideline that helps you figure out what you can actually afford based on your income and debts, not just what a lender will approve you for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
