<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VA Loan on Veteran Mortgage Lenders</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/categories/va-loan/</link><description>Recent content in VA Loan on Veteran Mortgage Lenders</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/categories/va-loan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The VA Loan Intake Briefing Checklist</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/the-va-loan-intake-briefing-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/the-va-loan-intake-briefing-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to calm VA mortgage anxiety is to treat the first lender conversation like an intake briefing. You are the officer in command of your own file. The lender wants clear orders, not scattered uploads. Below is the same checklist we run through with coaching clients before they ever click &amp;ldquo;apply.&amp;rdquo; Use it as a living document, revise it weekly, and share it with any spouse or co-borrower so the whole household rows in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A 90-Day Middle Credit Score Timeline for VA Buyers</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/a-90-day-middle-credit-score-timeline-for-va-buyers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/a-90-day-middle-credit-score-timeline-for-va-buyers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten VA buyers what a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; middle credit score is and you will hear ten nervous guesses. The truth is simpler: you need a score that supports the payment you want, the funding fee tier you prefer, and the concessions you expect to negotiate. The path there rarely requires heroic sacrifices—just consistent behavior mapped over 90 days. Below is the timeline we use with service members who need a predictable plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Navigating VA Appraisals and Tidewater Like a Pro</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/navigating-va-appraisals-and-tidewater-like-a-pro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/navigating-va-appraisals-and-tidewater-like-a-pro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you ask veterans what keeps them up at night during a home purchase, Tidewater notices rank near the top. The VA appraisal process is designed to protect you, but the extra communication can feel like a pop quiz. The antidote is preparation. When you expect Tidewater, plan for it, and rehearse the response, the notice becomes a predictable fork in the road rather than a dead end. Here is how we coach buyers and agents to stay ahead of the valuation curve.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>