<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Texas Jumbo Lenders – Portfolio Lenders for Luxury Homes on Texas Jumbo Lenders</title><link>https://texasjumbolenders.com/</link><description>Recent content in Texas Jumbo Lenders – Portfolio Lenders for Luxury Homes on Texas Jumbo Lenders</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://texasjumbolenders.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Texas Jumbo Reserve Requirements: 6–12 Month PITI Rules Explained</title><link>https://texasjumbolenders.com/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements-612-month-piti-rules-explained/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://texasjumbolenders.com/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements-612-month-piti-rules-explained/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-jumbo-lenders-demand-substantial-reserves"&gt;Why Jumbo Lenders Demand Substantial Reserves&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumbo loans carry higher default risk than conforming loans—larger balances, less standardized underwriting, and portfolio retention instead of agency sale. To offset this risk, jumbo lenders require 6–12 months of &lt;strong&gt;PITI reserves&lt;/strong&gt; (principal, interest, taxes, insurance) in liquid or semi-liquid assets. The higher your loan amount, LTV, or complexity, the more reserves you&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reserve requirements aren&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary—they prove you can weather income disruption (job loss, business downturn, market crash) without defaulting. Lenders calculate reserves using &lt;strong&gt;post-closing liquid assets&lt;/strong&gt;: checking, savings, money market, brokerage accounts (with discounting), and sometimes retirement accounts (60%–70% haircut). Real estate equity, business assets, and restricted stock usually don&amp;rsquo;t count.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Portfolio Lenders vs. Agency Jumbo: Which Texas Lender Type Wins?</title><link>https://texasjumbolenders.com/blogs/portfolio-lenders-vs.-agency-jumbo-which-texas-lender-type-wins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://texasjumbolenders.com/blogs/portfolio-lenders-vs.-agency-jumbo-which-texas-lender-type-wins/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-jumbo-lending-fork-portfolio-vs-agency"&gt;The Jumbo Lending Fork: Portfolio vs. Agency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you apply for a Texas jumbo loan (above $766,550 conforming limit), you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter two fundamentally different lender types: &lt;strong&gt;portfolio lenders&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;agency jumbo lenders&lt;/strong&gt;. The difference isn&amp;rsquo;t just branding—it dictates underwriting flexibility, rate pricing, and whether complex income (self-employed, foreign national, asset-based) gets approved or denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portfolio lenders&lt;/strong&gt; (credit unions, private banks, regional banks) hold jumbo loans on their balance sheet instead of selling them to Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, or mortgage-backed security investors. This gives them &lt;strong&gt;underwriting freedom&lt;/strong&gt;—manual approval for compensating factors, bank statement income, asset depletion, and non-standard scenarios that agency guidelines would auto-reject.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Texas Jumbo Rates Are Priced: LTV, Credit, and Relationship Banking</title><link>https://texasjumbolenders.com/blogs/how-texas-jumbo-rates-are-priced-ltv-credit-and-relationship-banking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://texasjumbolenders.com/blogs/how-texas-jumbo-rates-are-priced-ltv-credit-and-relationship-banking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-jumbo-rates-arent-one-size-fits-all"&gt;Why Jumbo Rates Aren&amp;rsquo;t One-Size-Fits-All&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumbo mortgage pricing is &lt;strong&gt;radically more complex&lt;/strong&gt; than conforming loans. Conforming rates (Fannie/Freddie) follow standardized Loan Level Price Adjustments (LLPAs)—predictable grids based on credit score and LTV. Jumbo rates? Portfolio lenders and private banks price based on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loan-to-value (LTV)&lt;/strong&gt;: 70%, 75%, 80%, 85%, 90% → each tier changes rate by 0.125%–0.50%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit score tiers&lt;/strong&gt;: 720, 740, 760, 780+ → jumbo pricing is hypersensitive to credit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loan amount&lt;/strong&gt;: $800K, $1.5M, $2.5M → higher balances trigger risk-based pricing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserves&lt;/strong&gt;: 6 months, 9 months, 12+ months PITI → more reserves can lower rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship banking&lt;/strong&gt;: Deposits, investment accounts, private banking tier → 0.25%–0.75% discounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Property type&lt;/strong&gt;: Primary residence, second home, investment → non-primary adds 0.50%–1.00%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occupancy &amp;amp; citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: U.S. citizen, foreign national, investor → foreign nationals pay 0.75%–1.50% more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike conforming loans where &amp;ldquo;760 credit + 75% LTV&amp;rdquo; yields a predictable adjustment, &lt;strong&gt;jumbo pricing is negotiable&lt;/strong&gt;—especially at portfolio lenders and private banks. Understanding these levers helps you &lt;strong&gt;shop strategically&lt;/strong&gt; instead of accepting the first quote.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>