<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About MTGLenders on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About MTGLenders on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Costs of Using Your Current Bank for a Mortgage: What They&#39;re Not Telling You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/hidden-costs-using-your-bank-for-mortgage-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/hidden-costs-using-your-bank-for-mortgage-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve been with us for 15 years—of course we&amp;rsquo;ll take care of you on your mortgage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what the banker told my neighbor when she applied for a home loan. She trusted them. She&amp;rsquo;d had checking, savings, a car loan, and two credit cards with them since college. Surely they&amp;rsquo;d reward that loyalty with a great mortgage deal, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They quoted her 6.75% on a conventional loan with $2,900 in lender fees. She accepted it without question because &amp;ldquo;they know me and my finances.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Banks vs Small Lenders vs Mortgage Brokers: Who Actually Offers Better Rates in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/big-banks-vs-small-lenders-vs-brokers-rates-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/big-banks-vs-small-lenders-vs-brokers-rates-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent six years working inside a big bank mortgage division before moving to a regional lender, then eventually consulting for mortgage brokers. That unique perspective showed me something most borrowers never see: the pricing models are so fundamentally different that comparing &amp;ldquo;rates&amp;rdquo; between big banks, small lenders, and brokers is almost meaningless without context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A big bank quoting 6.25% and a mortgage broker quoting 6.0% for the &amp;ldquo;same&amp;rdquo; loan are actually offering completely different products with different cost structures, service models, and long-term implications. Understanding these differences is worth tens of thousands of dollars to you as a borrower—and might change which lender type you choose entirely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Credit Score Do You Really Need for a Mortgage in 2025? Lender-by-Lender Breakdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/credit-score-requirements-by-lender-type-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A borrower called me frustrated last week: &amp;ldquo;I have a 665 credit score. Fannie Mae says they approve 620 and above for conventional loans, so why did three banks deny my application?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the credit score confusion that costs thousands of borrowers their dream homes every year. There&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;strong&gt;program minimum&lt;/strong&gt; (what Fannie Mae, FHA, or VA requires) and then there&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;strong&gt;lender minimum&lt;/strong&gt; (what each bank or broker actually approves). These two numbers can be 40-60 points apart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage Brokers vs Banks vs Credit Unions: Which Lender Type Saves You the Most Money in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/mortgage-brokers-vs-banks-vs-credit-unions-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/mortgage-brokers-vs-banks-vs-credit-unions-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My sister-in-law refinanced her mortgage three times in the past decade. The first time, she used Wells Fargo (her bank) and got 4.25% when the market average was 3.875%. The second time, she used a credit union and got 3.125% when the market was 3.25%—a great deal. The third time, she used a mortgage broker and got 2.625% when the market was 2.75%—the best deal of all three.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Same borrower, similar market conditions, but three completely different experiences and outcomes. The lender type mattered more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Compare Mortgage Lenders: Complete 2025 Guide to Finding the Best Rates and Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/how-to-compare-mortgage-lenders-2025-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/mtglenders/blogs/how-to-compare-mortgage-lenders-2025-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend called me last week, excited about buying his first home. &amp;ldquo;I got pre-approved!&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;My bank offered 6.625% on a 30-year conventional loan.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I asked if he&amp;rsquo;d compared rates with other lenders. Silence. Then: &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I was supposed to. I just figured my bank would give me a good deal since I&amp;rsquo;ve been with them 15 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two days later, after comparing four additional lenders, he had offers ranging from 6.625% (his bank) down to 5.875% (a mortgage broker accessing wholesale pricing). That 0.75% difference saves him $163 per month—$58,680 over the 30-year loan. All because he spent three hours comparing lenders instead of accepting the first offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
