<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Underwriting on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/underwriting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Underwriting on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/underwriting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Texas Jumbo Reserve Requirements: 6–12 Month PITI Rules Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/texasjumbolenders/blogs/texas-jumbo-reserve-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-jumbo-lenders-demand-substantial-reserves&#34;&gt;Why Jumbo Lenders Demand Substantial Reserves&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jumbo loans carry higher default risk than conforming loans—larger balances, less standardized underwriting, and portfolio retention instead of agency sale. To offset this risk, jumbo lenders require 6–12 months of &lt;strong&gt;PITI reserves&lt;/strong&gt; (principal, interest, taxes, insurance) in liquid or semi-liquid assets. The higher your loan amount, LTV, or complexity, the more reserves you&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reserve requirements aren&amp;rsquo;t arbitrary—they prove you can weather income disruption (job loss, business downturn, market crash) without defaulting. Lenders calculate reserves using &lt;strong&gt;post-closing liquid assets&lt;/strong&gt;: checking, savings, money market, brokerage accounts (with discounting), and sometimes retirement accounts (60%–70% haircut). Real estate equity, business assets, and restricted stock usually don&amp;rsquo;t count.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Playbook: How Brokers Clear Conditions Fast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/brokerstx/blogs/documentation-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/brokerstx/blogs/documentation-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;documentation-playbook-how-brokers-clear-conditions-fast&#34;&gt;Documentation Playbook: How Brokers Clear Conditions Fast&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest delays in mortgage closings isn&amp;rsquo;t rate locking or appraisals—it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;conditions&lt;/strong&gt;. Lenders issue conditions when they need more documentation to verify income, assets, employment, or credit. Every condition extends closing by 3–7 days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smart brokers &lt;strong&gt;front-load documentation&lt;/strong&gt; to minimize conditions. Here&amp;rsquo;s how they do it—and how you can help speed your closing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-lenders-issue-conditions&#34;&gt;Why Lenders Issue Conditions&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Underwriters follow a checklist:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Your Prequalification Documents Matter More Than You Think</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/usmortgagespecialist/blogs/prequalification-documents-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/usmortgagespecialist/blogs/prequalification-documents-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most borrowers treat prequalification documents like a bureaucratic chore. You scan some paystubs, forward tax returns, and hope the lender does not ask for more. In reality, the documents you submit during prequalification shape your entire mortgage experience. They determine your approval speed, your final rate, and whether surprises derail you at the finish line. Understanding why lenders request each piece and how to organize them properly gives you a massive advantage. Here is what actually matters and how to get it right the first time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 36-Hour Income Packaging Hackathon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/income-packaging-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/income-packaging-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender floated the phrase “TBD approval,” I pictured a neat checklist followed by a green light. Reality: my file blended salary, quarterly bonuses, RSUs, and freelance invoices. The underwriter came back with a polite essay of conditions that basically said, “Prove every dollar twice.” I could have grumbled about the workload, but our rate lock window was ticking. Instead, I declared a 36-hour income packaging hackathon and treated the entire documentation sprint like a product launch. Here is how that marathon went down—and how you can replicate it without losing sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The VA Loan Intake Briefing Checklist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-loan-intake-briefing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-loan-intake-briefing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to calm VA mortgage anxiety is to treat the first lender conversation like an intake briefing. You are the officer in command of your own file. The lender wants clear orders, not scattered uploads. Below is the same checklist we run through with coaching clients before they ever click &amp;ldquo;apply.&amp;rdquo; Use it as a living document, revise it weekly, and share it with any spouse or co-borrower so the whole household rows in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn Your Condition Tracker into a War Room</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/homeloanpurchase/blogs/condition-tracker-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/homeloanpurchase/blogs/condition-tracker-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every mortgage file eventually runs into conditions—small requests from underwriting that can feel enormous when you are juggling work, family, and the emotions of buying a first home. Most buyers treat those requests reactively. They dig through email threads, forward blurry screenshots, and hope the lender stops asking. Instead, treat conditions like a project sprint. Build a mini war room around them and you will clear each item faster than the processor expects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming Loan DTI Requirements: Understanding Debt-to-Income Ratios for 2025 Approval</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-dti-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-dti-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your debt-to-income ratio (DTI) is one of the most critical factors in conforming loan approval—yet it&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most misunderstood. Many borrowers think they need perfect credit and massive income to qualify, when in reality, Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac accept DTI ratios up to 50% with compensating factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me break down exactly how DTI works, what ratios you need for approval, and proven strategies to optimize your debt picture before applying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
