<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conforming Loan Limits on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/conforming-loan-limits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conforming Loan Limits on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/conforming-loan-limits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits: How to Plan Before Listing or Locking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/conforming-loan-limits-2025-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Homeowners, builders, and real estate agents love the headline every fall: “FHFA raises conforming loan limits again.” The increase always feels like free money, yet the borrowers who actually benefit are the ones who run the math long before a purchase offer or refinance lock. This guide breaks down the 2025 conforming loan limit change, shows how high-balance thresholds really work, and shares the preparation steps that keep you in control when lenders start quoting rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Saved $42,000 by Understanding My County&#39;s $1.09M Conforming Limit: Jumbo vs. High-Balance Conforming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/i-saved-42000-by-understanding-my-countys-conforming-limit-jumbo-vs-high-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/i-saved-42000-by-understanding-my-countys-conforming-limit-jumbo-vs-high-balance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my husband and I were transferred to Seattle for work in early 2024, we started looking at homes in the Eastside suburbs—Bellevue, Redmond, Sammamish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sticker shock was real:&lt;/strong&gt; Entry-level 3-bedroom homes started at $900,000.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming from Ohio where we&amp;rsquo;d owned a nice 4-bedroom home for $320,000, we assumed a $950,000 mortgage would require jumbo financing with all the associated costs—higher rates, larger down payment, deeper reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-non-conforming-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-non-conforming-2025/</guid>
      <description>A clear guide to conforming vs. non-conforming mortgages in 2025: loan limits, pricing differences, and strategies to qualify — with resources from Middle Credit Score® and Browse Lenders®.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Conforming Loan Limits by State – Updated FHFA Guidelines, High-Cost Areas, and Borrowing Insights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-conforming-loan-limits-by-state-updated-fhfa-guidelines-high-cost-areas-and-borrowing-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/2025-conforming-loan-limits-by-state-updated-fhfa-guidelines-high-cost-areas-and-borrowing-insights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) announces new conforming loan limits—the maximum loan amounts that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac will purchase from lenders. For 2025, the baseline conforming loan limit is &lt;strong&gt;$766,550&lt;/strong&gt; for single-family homes in most counties, with high-cost areas reaching up to &lt;strong&gt;$1,149,825&lt;/strong&gt;. Understanding these limits by state and county is essential for determining whether you need conforming, high-balance conforming, or jumbo financing—and how your loan amount affects rate eligibility and approval odds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
