<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BAH on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/bah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BAH on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/bah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BAH Budget War-Gaming Before You Write a VA Offer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/bah-offer-budget-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/bah-offer-budget-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BAH is more than a monthly deposit. It is a living constraint that either keeps your VA offer disciplined or sets you up for payment regret. Most of the budget panic we see happens because buyers stare at the BAH line in MyPay without modeling how that allowance collides with utilities, temporary lodging, or life during a PCS. Use this field manual to war-game your numbers before you fall for a listing that quietly outpaces your cash flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding VA Lenders for Deployed Service Members: Tips &amp; Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/finding-va-lenders-for-deployed-service-members-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteransloanofficers/blogs/finding-va-lenders-for-deployed-service-members-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a home while deployed or stationed overseas presents unique challenges—time zone differences, limited communication access, deployment income documentation, and power of attorney requirements. However, thousands of active-duty service members successfully close on VA loans each year while serving abroad, and understanding which lenders specialize in deployment scenarios makes the process significantly smoother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The right VA lender understands how to verify BAH (Basic Allowance for Housing), handle overseas power of attorney, process remote document signing, and work around communication blackouts during training exercises or combat deployments. This guide explains how deployed service members can find VA lenders who specialize in military lending and avoid the delays and frustrations that come from working with lenders unfamiliar with deployment challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
