<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automated Underwriting on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/automated-underwriting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automated Underwriting on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/automated-underwriting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Underwriter vs. Loan Product Advisor: Navigating AUS Findings Like a Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/navigating-aus-findings-conforming-loans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/navigating-aus-findings-conforming-loans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conforming loans live and die by automated underwriting systems (AUS). You can submit the same borrower profile to Fannie Mae’s Desktop Underwriter (DU) and Freddie Mac’s Loan Product Advisor (LPA) and receive two very different findings. Understanding why those responses diverge—and how to answer them—turns AUS from a mysterious gatekeeper into a predictable guide. Here’s the playbook we share with borrowers before their files ever reach an underwriter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;du-and-lpa-look-at-the-same-inputs-differently&#34;&gt;DU and LPA look at the same inputs differently&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both systems analyze the “four Cs”: credit, capacity, collateral, and capital. DU tends to reward longer credit histories and higher reserves, while LPA occasionally gives more flexibility on debt-to-income ratios when compensating factors exist. Before you run either system, verify that the tri-merge credit report is accurate and that income documents align with the numbers in your loan application (Form 1003). AUS findings only know what you feed them—garbage in, garbage out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
