<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Market Timing on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/market-timing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market Timing on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/market-timing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rate Lock Timing Strategy: When to Lock, When to Float, and Market Signals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/brokerstx/blogs/rate-lock-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/brokerstx/blogs/rate-lock-timing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rate-lock-timing-strategy-when-to-lock-when-to-float-and-market-signals&#34;&gt;Rate Lock Timing Strategy: When to Lock, When to Float, and Market Signals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest decisions in a mortgage closing is &lt;strong&gt;when to lock your rate&lt;/strong&gt;. Lock too early and you might miss a 0.25% drop; float too long and rates spike 0.50% overnight. Brokers who master rate-lock timing save their clients thousands—and speed up closings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding lock vs. float is the power key to controlling your closing cost and stress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Neighborhood Home Values Jumped 28% in 2 Years—When I Knew It Was Time to Refinance for Equity Access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cash-outrefinancing/blogs/neighborhood-home-values-jumped-28-percent-2-years-when-knew-time-refinance-equity-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cash-outrefinancing/blogs/neighborhood-home-values-jumped-28-percent-2-years-when-knew-time-refinance-equity-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My home appreciated $110,000 in just 2 years. I purchased for $395,000 in early 2022, and by early 2024 comparable sales showed $505,000 value—a 28% increase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The question wasn&amp;rsquo;t whether I had equity to access. The question was: &lt;strong&gt;when should I refinance to leverage this appreciation?&lt;/strong&gt; Too early and I miss additional gains. Too late and the market plateaus or declines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I tracked monthly comparable sales for 8 months watching the appreciation trajectory. I identified the optimal refinancing timing window when appreciation was still strong but showing signs of slowing—refinancing before the market peaked but after I&amp;rsquo;d captured most of the gains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage Broker Rate Lock Strategies for Refinancing in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-rate-lock-strategies-refinancing-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refimortgagebrokers/blogs/broker-rate-lock-strategies-refinancing-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched a homeowner lock his refinance rate at 6.25% on Monday. By Friday, rates had dropped to 5.875%. He was stuck with the higher rate and lost $63 per month ($22,680 over the loan life) because he locked too early without understanding market timing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, another borrower floated her rate for two weeks waiting for a better entry point. Rates jumped 0.5% during that time. She ended up locking at 6.75% when she could have had 6.25%—costing her $91 monthly ($32,760 over life).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
