<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Inspection on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/home-inspection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Inspection on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:10:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/home-inspection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Inspection Shock to Closing Day Confidence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/homeloanpurchase/blogs/inspection-to-closing-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/homeloanpurchase/blogs/inspection-to-closing-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Home inspections have a reputation for derailing first-time buyers. A long report lands in your inbox, the clock is ticking, and suddenly every outlet, pipe, and roof tile feels like an emergency. The truth? Most transactions survive inspection when buyers pair calm analysis with disciplined communication. Use this playbook to manage the post-inspection stretch like a pro, even if you have never read a contractor quote before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-prioritize-with-a-scoring-model&#34;&gt;Step 1: Prioritize with a scoring model&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a simple scoring sheet with three columns: safety, structural, and negotiation leverage. Assign each issue from the report a score from one to five in each column. Safety covers items that could harm people (exposed wiring, gas leaks). Structural addresses components that impact the home’s longevity (foundation cracks, roof damage). Negotiation leverage represents how persuasive the issue might be when asking the seller for credits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
