<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loan Comparisons on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/loan-comparisons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Loan Comparisons on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/loan-comparisons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jumbo Loans vs. Conforming: I Compared Both for My $825K Home Purchase and Here&#39;s What I Learned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/jumbo-loans-vs-conforming-i-compared-both-for-my-825k-home-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconforminghomeloans/blogs/jumbo-loans-vs-conforming-i-compared-both-for-my-825k-home-purchase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started house hunting in Orange County, California in early 2024, I quickly learned that $825,000 was the baseline for single-family homes in decent neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first question:&lt;/strong&gt; Is that a jumbo loan or conforming loan?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The answer:&lt;/strong&gt; In Orange County, the 2024 conforming loan limit is $1,089,300—so my $825,000 purchase qualified as conforming, not jumbo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-2024-conforming-loan-limits&#34;&gt;Understanding the 2024 Conforming Loan Limits&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;standard-vs-high-cost-area-limits&#34;&gt;Standard vs. High-Cost Area Limits&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard conforming limit (2024):&lt;/strong&gt; $766,550 in most U.S. counties&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-nonconforming-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-nonconforming-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the difference between conforming and non-conforming loans is crucial for making the right mortgage decision in 2025. With updated FHFA loan limits and evolving market conditions, borrowers must navigate an increasingly complex landscape to secure the best financing for their specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-conforming-vs-non-conforming-loans&#34;&gt;Defining Conforming vs. Non-Conforming Loans&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conforming-loans-government-backed-security&#34;&gt;Conforming Loans: Government-Backed Security&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conforming loans meet specific criteria established by the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) and are eligible for purchase by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs. Conventional Loans 2025: Which Government or Private Mortgage Saves You More?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/fhaloanofficers/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The debate between FHA and conventional loans isn&amp;rsquo;t about which is objectively better—it&amp;rsquo;s about which saves you more money based on your specific credit profile, down payment, and how long you plan to keep the loan. Most borrowers get this decision wrong because they focus solely on down payment requirements instead of analyzing total costs over their actual holding period.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me show you exactly how to compare these loan types so you can make the choice that maximizes your financial position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs Conventional Loans for First-Time Buyers 2025: Which Saves You More Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-first-time-buyers-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/fha-vs-conventional-first-time-buyers-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fha-vs-conventional-loans-the-ultimate-first-time-buyer-decision-guide&#34;&gt;FHA vs Conventional Loans: The Ultimate First-Time Buyer Decision Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ask ten first-time buyers which loan type they should choose, and eight will guess wrong. That&amp;rsquo;s because the FHA versus conventional decision isn&amp;rsquo;t about which is universally better—it&amp;rsquo;s about which costs less money over your specific ownership period given your credit score, down payment amount, and how long you plan to keep the loan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most buyers make this choice based on down payment requirements alone, completely ignoring mortgage insurance costs that can differ by $30,000-$50,000 over the loan life. Let me show you exactly how to analyze both options so you choose the loan type that maximizes your financial position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Jumbo Loans in 2025: Loan Limits, Rates, and Qualification Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-jumbo-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-jumbo-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>A practical 2025 guide comparing conforming and jumbo mortgages—how limits, rates, credit, and DTI shape approvals and total cost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. FHA Loans in 2025: Key Differences, Credit Requirements, and Loan Limits Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-fha-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-fha-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>Conforming vs. FHA Loans in 2025 — learn the major differences in credit, down payment, and loan limits to help you choose the best path to homeownership.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. FHA Loans in 2025: Key Differences, Credit Requirements, and Loan Limits Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-fha-loans-in-2025-key-differences-credit-requirements-and-loan-limits-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When comparing &lt;strong&gt;conforming loans&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;FHA loans&lt;/strong&gt; in 2025, the biggest differences come down to credit requirements, down payment flexibility, loan limits, and long-term costs. Conforming loans (backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac) offer better rates and lower lifetime costs for borrowers with strong credit, while FHA loans (insured by the Federal Housing Administration) provide easier qualification for borrowers with lower credit scores and smaller down payments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding which loan type fits your financial profile helps you save money, qualify faster, and avoid unnecessary costs over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Jumbo Loans in 2025: Loan Limits, Rates, and Qualification Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-jumbo-loans-in-2025-loan-limits-rates-and-qualification-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-jumbo-loans-in-2025-loan-limits-rates-and-qualification-strategies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The difference between &lt;strong&gt;conforming loans&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;jumbo loans&lt;/strong&gt; comes down to loan limits—conforming loans stay within FHFA maximums ($766,550 baseline for 2025, up to $1,149,825 in high-cost areas), while jumbo loans exceed these limits. This distinction affects everything: interest rates, qualification requirements, down payment expectations, and long-term costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For buyers in expensive markets or purchasing high-value properties, understanding the conforming vs jumbo boundary is essential for securing the best possible financing terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Non-Conforming: How 2025 Loan Limits Shape Your Conventional Mortgage Options</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-non-conforming-how-2025-loan-limits-shape-your-conventional-mortgage-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/conforming-vs.-non-conforming-how-2025-loan-limits-shape-your-conventional-mortgage-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The distinction between &lt;strong&gt;conforming&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;non-conforming&lt;/strong&gt; loans is fundamental to understanding conventional mortgage financing. Conforming loans meet Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac standards—including staying within FHFA loan limits ($766,550 baseline for 2025, up to $1,149,825 in high-cost areas)—which allows them to be sold to these government-sponsored enterprises. Non-conforming loans either exceed these limits or fail to meet underwriting standards, requiring portfolio lending with stricter requirements and typically higher rates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding whether your loan is conforming or non-conforming affects everything: interest rates, down payment expectations, qualification requirements, and long-term affordability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
