<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Credit Repair on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/credit-repair/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Credit Repair on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/credit-repair/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Credit Score Improvement While Shopping for Mortgage: Safe Strategies for Bad Credit Borrowers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/credit-score-improvement-while-shopping-mortgage-2026/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/credit-score-improvement-while-shopping-mortgage-2026/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Borrowers with bad credit (500-660 scores) often wonder whether they can improve their credit score during the mortgage shopping process without sabotaging their application. The answer is yes—but only if you avoid common mistakes that tank scores and understand the 45-day mortgage inquiry window. Strategic credit actions during pre-approval can raise your score 20-40 points and unlock better rates, while missteps like paying off collections incorrectly or opening new credit cards can destroy approval chances. This guide shows you exactly what credit moves are safe during mortgage shopping and which ones will get your application denied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should You Pay Off Collections Before Applying for a Mortgage?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/should-you-pay-off-collections-before-mortgage-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/should-you-pay-off-collections-before-mortgage-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Collections on your credit report can tank your score and complicate mortgage approval, but paying them off is not always the right move. In some cases, paying old collections actually lowers your credit score temporarily by resetting the &amp;ldquo;date of last activity,&amp;rdquo; making the negative item look recent instead of aged. Understanding FHA collection rules, how different lenders treat collections, and when strategic non-payment makes sense can mean the difference between approval and denial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Mortgage with a 500-579 Credit Score in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/how-to-get-mortgage-with-500-579-credit-score-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/badcreditloanspecialist/blogs/how-to-get-mortgage-with-500-579-credit-score-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 500-579 credit score puts you in the &amp;ldquo;very poor&amp;rdquo; credit range according to FICO standards, and most lenders will reject your mortgage application automatically. However, FHA loans allow 500-579 scores with a 10% down payment and manual underwriting—meaning human review of your full financial picture instead of automated rejection. Thousands of borrowers with scores in this range get approved every year by working with bad credit specialists who know which FHA lenders accept manual underwriting and how to present compensating factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
