<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Construction on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/new-construction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Construction on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/new-construction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Builder Incentives vs. Independent Lenders: I Chose Wrong and It Cost Me $12,000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/builder-incentives-vs-independent-lenders-i-chose-wrong-and-it-cost-me-12000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/builder-incentives-vs-independent-lenders-i-chose-wrong-and-it-cost-me-12000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I bought my new construction home two years ago, the builder&amp;rsquo;s sales rep made me an offer I thought I couldn&amp;rsquo;t refuse: &lt;strong&gt;$15,000 in closing cost assistance and $5,000 in design center upgrades&lt;/strong&gt; if I financed through their preferred lender.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did the math in my head: &amp;ldquo;$20,000 in free money? I&amp;rsquo;d be crazy to say no!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I signed up with the builder&amp;rsquo;s preferred lender without shopping around. Big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Construction Loan Mistakes That Nearly Cost Me My Dream Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/5-construction-loan-mistakes-that-nearly-cost-me-my-dream-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/5-construction-loan-mistakes-that-nearly-cost-me-my-dream-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building my dream home was supposed to be exciting—and it was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it was also &lt;strong&gt;terrifying&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five times during the process, I made mistakes that nearly derailed the entire project. I&amp;rsquo;m talking &lt;strong&gt;close calls&lt;/strong&gt; that could have cost me tens of thousands of dollars, delayed my closing, or even forced me to walk away from the build entirely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got lucky. I caught these mistakes (or someone else caught them for me) before they became disasters. But looking back, I realize how easily things could have gone wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spec Home Purchase Strategy: Buying Spec Homes vs Custom Builds with Construction Financing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/spec-home-purchase-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/spec-home-purchase-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When most people think about buying new construction, they imagine designing every detail from the ground up—choosing floor plans, selecting finishes, and watching their dream home come to life over months of construction. But there&amp;rsquo;s another path to new construction ownership that&amp;rsquo;s faster, often less expensive, and requires simpler financing: buying a spec home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spec homes (short for &amp;ldquo;speculative&amp;rdquo; homes) are builder-constructed houses built without a specific buyer in mind—usually move-in ready or near completion when you start shopping. Understanding the differences between spec home purchases and custom builds helps you choose the right new construction approach based on your timeline, budget, customization priorities, and financing situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction-to-Permanent Loan Guide: Complete Process from Groundbreaking to Permanent Mortgage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loan-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loan-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building your dream home from the ground up is exciting—but the financing can feel overwhelming if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand how construction-to-permanent loans actually work. Unlike traditional mortgages where you borrow once and start making payments immediately, construction-to-permanent financing structures everything differently: one closing, extended rate locks, draw-based funding, interest-only payments during the build, and automatic conversion to a traditional mortgage when construction is complete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering new construction, understanding this loan type is essential before signing builder contracts or breaking ground. Here&amp;rsquo;s everything you need to know about construction-to-permanent loans—from qualification through final conversion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
