<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Veteran Mortgage Lenders</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/</link><description>Recent content on Veteran Mortgage Lenders</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VA Renovation Bid Tracker for Tidy Underwriting</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker-for-tidy-underwriting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker-for-tidy-underwriting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Few things spike blood pressure like trying to squeeze contractor bids, inspection responses, and VA renovation overlays into the same week. Most buyers treat the process like a scavenger hunt, which is why lenders slow-walk approvals. Build a repeatable bid tracker instead. The framework below is tuned for service members who juggle PCS timelines, guard drills, and family life yet still want to close on a property that needs work.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Funding Fee Waiver Playbook for VA Buyers</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook-for-va-buyers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook-for-va-buyers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten veterans how the funding fee works and you will hear legends, half-truths, and rumors about mysterious VA decisions. The fee funds the program, which means lenders scrutinize every waiver request and every dollar collected. Instead of waiting for the underwriter to tell you what is missing, build a playbook that covers entitlement math, disability documentation, and what to do if the waiver is not yet on your Certificate of Eligibility (COE). Here is the same structure we walk through during BrowseLenders coaching calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VA Condo Approval Recon Checklist</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/va-condo-approval-recon-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:35:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/va-condo-approval-recon-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Condo hunting feels efficient until you learn that “VA approved” is not a guarantee—it is a moving target. Some projects on the VA list have lapsed insurance, outdated budgets, or lingering litigation that can stall your closing. We treat condo shopping like reconnaissance: you gather intel, document risks, and brief your team before you ever submit an offer. Use this recon checklist to stay ahead of the paperwork while your competition wonders why underwriting keeps asking follow-up questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PCS Overlap Cash-Flow Map for VA Buyers</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/pcs-overlap-cash-flow-map-for-va-buyers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:05:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/pcs-overlap-cash-flow-map-for-va-buyers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every VA buyer secretly fears the same thing: getting pinned between two sets of housing costs while PCS orders march forward. Cash gets trapped in deposits, pay periods bounce, and suddenly the underwriting call feels more stressful than deployment prep. The antidote is a cash-flow map that treats overlap months like a temporary campaign, not a chaotic surprise. Grab a whiteboard, your favorite spreadsheet, and this guide—we will walk through the same framework we coach service members on every week.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>BAH Budget War-Gaming Before You Write a VA Offer</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/bah-budget-war-gaming-before-you-write-a-va-offer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/bah-budget-war-gaming-before-you-write-a-va-offer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;BAH is more than a monthly deposit. It is a living constraint that either keeps your VA offer disciplined or sets you up for payment regret. Most of the budget panic we see happens because buyers stare at the BAH line in MyPay without modeling how that allowance collides with utilities, temporary lodging, or life during a PCS. Use this field manual to war-game your numbers before you fall for a listing that quietly outpaces your cash flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The VA Loan Intake Briefing Checklist</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/the-va-loan-intake-briefing-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/the-va-loan-intake-briefing-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to calm VA mortgage anxiety is to treat the first lender conversation like an intake briefing. You are the officer in command of your own file. The lender wants clear orders, not scattered uploads. Below is the same checklist we run through with coaching clients before they ever click &amp;ldquo;apply.&amp;rdquo; Use it as a living document, revise it weekly, and share it with any spouse or co-borrower so the whole household rows in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A 90-Day Middle Credit Score Timeline for VA Buyers</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/a-90-day-middle-credit-score-timeline-for-va-buyers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/a-90-day-middle-credit-score-timeline-for-va-buyers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten VA buyers what a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; middle credit score is and you will hear ten nervous guesses. The truth is simpler: you need a score that supports the payment you want, the funding fee tier you prefer, and the concessions you expect to negotiate. The path there rarely requires heroic sacrifices—just consistent behavior mapped over 90 days. Below is the timeline we use with service members who need a predictable plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Navigating VA Appraisals and Tidewater Like a Pro</title><link>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/navigating-va-appraisals-and-tidewater-like-a-pro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://veteranmortgagelenders.com/blogs/navigating-va-appraisals-and-tidewater-like-a-pro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you ask veterans what keeps them up at night during a home purchase, Tidewater notices rank near the top. The VA appraisal process is designed to protect you, but the extra communication can feel like a pop quiz. The antidote is preparation. When you expect Tidewater, plan for it, and rehearse the response, the notice becomes a predictable fork in the road rather than a dead end. Here is how we coach buyers and agents to stay ahead of the valuation curve.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>