<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conforming on Conforming Mortgage Rates</title><link>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/categories/conforming/</link><description>Recent content in Conforming on Conforming Mortgage Rates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:40:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conformingmortgagerates.com/categories/conforming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Our State Rate Benchmark Summit Works</title><link>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/blogs/how-our-state-rate-benchmark-summit-works/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/blogs/how-our-state-rate-benchmark-summit-works/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Tuesday afternoon we host what we jokingly call the “State Rate Benchmark Summit.” It started as two people swapping lender screenshots and has evolved into a 60-minute production that keeps our entire conforming mortgage pipeline on track. The summit runs on evidence, timestamps, and reusable templates so anyone who misses the call can still follow the decisions. Here is the structure we follow and how you can adapt it for your own team.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inside Our Conforming Reprice Watch Log</title><link>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/blogs/inside-our-conforming-reprice-watch-log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:55:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/blogs/inside-our-conforming-reprice-watch-log/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing spikes blood pressure like a surprise lender reprice. Your phone lights up, borrowers panic, and suddenly every stakeholder wants an update five minutes ago. To keep those moments orderly we maintain a “reprice watch log,” a single document that tracks volatility across all active conforming loans. The log has five columns, a few automation rules, and a playbook that anyone on the team can follow. Here’s how it works.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Credit Pacing Roadshow We Take To Every Stakeholder</title><link>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/blogs/the-credit-pacing-roadshow-we-take-to-every-stakeholder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:05:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conformingmortgagerates.com/blogs/the-credit-pacing-roadshow-we-take-to-every-stakeholder/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When rate volatility peaks, credit discipline becomes the quiet hero of every conforming mortgage approval. We kept explaining the same utilization plans to different stakeholders, so we packaged the talking points into what we call the “Credit Pacing Roadshow.” It is a 45-minute briefing we can run for spouses, business partners, or finance executives to prove we are protecting the pricing tier. Here is how the roadshow runs and why it has become a staple of our process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>