<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Builder Selection on New Construction Mortgage Brokers</title><link>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/tags/builder-selection/</link><description>Recent content in Builder Selection on New Construction Mortgage Brokers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/tags/builder-selection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Builder Reputation Verification Checklist: How to Verify Builder Credentials and Track Record</title><link>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/blogs/builder-reputation-verification-checklist-how-to-verify-builder-credentials-and-track-record/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/blogs/builder-reputation-verification-checklist-how-to-verify-builder-credentials-and-track-record/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right builder is the most important decision you&amp;rsquo;ll make in your construction journey—more important than floor plans, finishes, or even financing. A great builder delivers quality work on time and on budget, communicating proactively and standing behind their work long after you move in. A bad builder creates financial nightmares, timeline disasters, quality failures, and legal battles that can destroy your dream of homeownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet most people spend more time researching kitchen appliances than they do verifying their builder&amp;rsquo;s credentials, track record, and financial stability. They trust charming sales presentations, impressive model homes, or low initial bids without doing basic due diligence—discovering too late that their builder lacks proper licensing, carries insufficient insurance, or has a history of abandoned projects and unhappy clients.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>