<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conforming Approval on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/conforming-approval/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conforming Approval on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/conforming-approval/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Middle Credit Score Roadmap to a Conforming Loan Approval</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/middle-credit-score-roadmap-conforming-approval/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/middle-credit-score-roadmap-conforming-approval/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my lender told me my “middle score” was 671, I felt blindsided. I monitor my credit through two different consumer apps, and both said I was in the low 700s. What followed was an eight-week sprint to learn how middle credit scores really work, fix the items dragging mine down, and earn the rate I wanted on a conforming loan. This isn’t theory—it’s the exact roadmap I used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;week-1-request-the-same-data-lenders-see&#34;&gt;Week 1: Request the same data lenders see&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Auto-scores, VantageScores, and bank-provided updates are directional, not definitive. My loan officer suggested I pull a tri-merge report through a mortgage-preferred vendor so I could see every bureau line item the underwriter would analyze. The $60 fee hurt less than paying a higher rate for 30 years. Once the report arrived, I created a spreadsheet with three columns—Equifax, Experian, TransUnion—and highlighted the differences. Two medical collections showed on one bureau while the others marked them as paid. Utilization appeared at 54% on a travel card because the statement cut before my payment hit. With the real data in hand, I was able to set priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
