<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Refinance MTGs</title><link>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Refinance MTGs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inside My Rate Window War Room</title><link>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/inside-my-rate-window-war-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:20:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/inside-my-rate-window-war-room/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I used to think refinance timing was just about watching headlines. Then I sat through four failed lock attempts in one year and realized I needed a war room, not a group chat. This fall I built one, complete with rate guardrails, debt reshuffle plans, and clear marching orders for everyone involved. The result: a lock that felt boring—in the best way—and a closing table where every dollar already had a job. Here is the play-by-play.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Equity Allocation Blueprint for Cash-Out Funds</title><link>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/my-equity-allocation-blueprint-for-cash-out-funds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:05:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/my-equity-allocation-blueprint-for-cash-out-funds/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cash-out refinancing can feel like standing in front of a firehose. The lender asks where the money is going, you answer with a polite summary, and they still stare like you just confessed to a shopping spree. I wanted to avoid that dynamic, so I created an equity allocation blueprint long before the appraisal even came back. It became the centerpiece of my loan file and the guardrail that kept our household from overspending once cash hit the account. Here’s exactly how I built it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Weekly Debt Restructure Standups That Saved Our Refinance</title><link>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/the-weekly-debt-restructure-standups-that-saved-our-refinance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://refinancemtgs.com/blogs/the-weekly-debt-restructure-standups-that-saved-our-refinance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Refinancing while restructuring debt can feel like conducting an orchestra with three different sets of sheet music. One section wants lower rates, another wants cash-out funds, and the percussionists (a.k.a. the lenders) keep tapping their pencils waiting for documents. After our first attempt fizzled, we implemented weekly standups inspired by project management playbooks. They lasted 20 minutes, used a shared agenda, and completely changed how we operated. Here’s how the ritual worked.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>