<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Construction Loan Conversion on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/construction-loan-conversion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Construction Loan Conversion on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/construction-loan-conversion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Permanent Conversion Timing Optimal: When to Convert Construction Loan to Permanent Mortgage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/permanent-conversion-timing-optimal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/permanent-conversion-timing-optimal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest advantages of construction-to-permanent loans is the seamless conversion from construction financing to permanent mortgage when your home is complete—no second application, no additional closing costs, no refinancing hassle. But this automatic conversion only happens when specific conditions are met, timing is critical, and understanding how the conversion process works prevents surprises that could delay your move-in or increase your costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re financing new construction, understanding permanent conversion timing helps you coordinate with your builder, protect your rate lock, and ensure the transition from interest-only construction payments to principal-and-interest permanent payments happens smoothly when your home is ready for occupancy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
