<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family Systems on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/family-systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family Systems on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:10:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/family-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Sunday Brunch Rate Lab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/brunch-rate-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/brunch-rate-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Sunday we used to argue about chores. Now we run a “rate lab” over brunch and leave the table with HELOC action items instead of crumbs. It sounds quirky, but the ritual keeps our calculators current, our credit on track, and our loan officer impressed. If you want to copy it, here’s how we structure the 60-minute session.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;segment-1-market-pulse-10-minutes&#34;&gt;Segment 1: Market pulse (10 minutes)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We open laptops while the waffles cook and pull up the HELOCLending dashboard. One person reads the latest rate commentary from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cash-outrefinance.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cash-OutRefinance.com&lt;/a&gt;; another updates the HELOC calculator with current balances and estimated home value. We capture three numbers on a whiteboard: CLTV, target line amount, and blended rate if we combined a HELOC with a small cash-out refi. Seeing those numbers weekly prevents us from overreacting when headlines shift midweek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Host a Draw Period Budget Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/draw-period-budget-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/draw-period-budget-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HELOC draw periods invite chaos. One minute you’re planning a roof repair, the next you’re tempted to swipe the line for a vacation “because the rate is low.” To keep ourselves honest, we run a monthly “Draw Period Budget Summit.” It’s part financial review, part therapy session, and it makes lenders look at our file like we’re the organized borrowers they want on their books. Here’s our agenda if you want to steal it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
