<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Second Mortgage on Conforming Home Loans</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/tags/second-mortgage/</link><description>Recent content in Second Mortgage on Conforming Home Loans</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conforminghomeloan.com/tags/second-mortgage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Conforming Cash-Out vs. Second Lien: Six Calculations I Won’t Skip Again</title><link>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/conforming-cash-out-vs.-second-lien-six-calculations-i-wont-skip-again/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conforminghomeloan.com/blogs/conforming-cash-out-vs.-second-lien-six-calculations-i-wont-skip-again/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When my kitchen remodel estimate landed at $78,000, I had two options: refinance my entire first mortgage with a conforming cash-out loan or leave the low-rate first alone and open a second lien. The obsession with “never touch a low rate” is popular on social media, but real math told a different story. Here are the six calculations that guided my decision—and the lessons any homeowner can apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-blended-rate-comparison"&gt;1. Blended rate comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by writing down the current balance and rate on my first mortgage ($452,000 at 3.125%) and the quotes for potential second liens (9.5% HELOC, 10.25% home equity loan). Then I calculated the blended rate: ((First balance x first rate) + (Second balance x second rate)) / Combined balance. Keeping the first mortgage and adding a HELOC produced an effective rate of 4.62%. The conforming cash-out refinance quote landed at 6.125% for the entire balance. On the surface, keeping the first mortgage looked cheaper, but blended rates only tell part of the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>