<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3% Down on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/3-down/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3% Down on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/3-down/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3% Down vs 20% Down: Which Home Purchase Strategy Actually Saves You Money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/3-percent-down-vs-20-percent-down-which-home-purchase-strategy-actually-saves-you-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/3-percent-down-vs-20-percent-down-which-home-purchase-strategy-actually-saves-you-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years, the conventional wisdom was simple: save 20% down to avoid PMI and get the best mortgage terms. But here&amp;rsquo;s what nobody tells you—waiting five extra years to save 20% down might cost you more money than just buying now with 3% down and paying PMI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I learned this lesson the hard way when I spent three years religiously saving for a 20% down payment while home prices in my market rose 8% annually. By the time I had my 20% saved, the homes I was looking at cost $80,000 more—and my &amp;ldquo;savings&amp;rdquo; on PMI was wiped out by appreciation I missed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming Loan Down Payment Options: 3% Down Programs and Smart Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-down-payment-options-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-down-payment-options-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest misconceptions about conforming loans is that you need a 20% down payment to qualify. The reality? Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac offer multiple pathways to homeownership with down payments as low as 3%—and understanding these options can help you buy sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-down-payment-size-matters&#34;&gt;Why Down Payment Size Matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your down payment affects three critical factors: loan approval odds, monthly payment amounts, and whether you&amp;rsquo;ll pay private mortgage insurance (PMI). But here&amp;rsquo;s what many borrowers miss: a smaller down payment doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean worse terms if you&amp;rsquo;re using a conforming loan backed by government-sponsored enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Buyers and Conventional Loans: Credit, Down Payments, and Rate Strategies for 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingloanofficers/blogs/first-time-buyers-and-conventional-loans-credit-down-payments-and-rate-strategies-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First-time homebuyers&lt;/strong&gt; often assume they need FHA loans or 20% down payments to buy a home—but conventional loans offer some of the best financing options for first-time buyers in 2025, including &lt;strong&gt;3% down payment programs&lt;/strong&gt;, competitive rates for borrowers with 620+ credit scores, and access to conforming loan limits up to $766,550 (or $1,149,825 in high-cost areas). Understanding how conventional loans work, what credit and income requirements you need to meet, and how to avoid common mistakes helps you qualify faster and save money over the life of your mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
