<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Construction Loans on New Construction Mortgage Brokers</title><link>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/tags/construction-loans/</link><description>Recent content in Construction Loans on New Construction Mortgage Brokers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/tags/construction-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Builder Financing Requirements: What Lenders Look for in Builder Credentials</title><link>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/blogs/builder-financing-requirements-what-lenders-look-for-in-builder-credentials/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/blogs/builder-financing-requirements-what-lenders-look-for-in-builder-credentials/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When you apply for construction financing, your lender isn&amp;rsquo;t just evaluating you—they&amp;rsquo;re evaluating your builder. Construction loans carry significantly more risk than traditional mortgages because lenders are funding a home that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist yet, relying on your builder to complete the project on time, on budget, and to code. If your builder fails to deliver, the lender&amp;rsquo;s collateral (your partially completed home) could be worth far less than the loan amount.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Construction-to-Permanent Loan Guide: Complete Process from Groundbreaking to Permanent Mortgage</title><link>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loan-guide-complete-process-from-groundbreaking-to-permanent-mortgage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://newconstructionmortgagebrokers.com/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loan-guide-complete-process-from-groundbreaking-to-permanent-mortgage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Building your dream home from the ground up is exciting—but the financing can feel overwhelming if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand how construction-to-permanent loans actually work. Unlike traditional mortgages where you borrow once and start making payments immediately, construction-to-permanent financing structures everything differently: one closing, extended rate locks, draw-based funding, interest-only payments during the build, and automatic conversion to a traditional mortgage when construction is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering new construction, understanding this loan type is essential before signing builder contracts or breaking ground. Here&amp;rsquo;s everything you need to know about construction-to-permanent loans—from qualification through final conversion.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>