<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Process Map on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/process-map/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Process Map on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/process-map/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Transparency Tour For Expanded-Criteria Lenders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingmortgagerates/blogs/expanded-criteria-lender-transparency-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingmortgagerates/blogs/expanded-criteria-lender-transparency-tour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Expanded-criteria lending thrives on clarity. Every stakeholder—borrower, lender, CPA, relocation team—needs to know exactly what is happening, why it matters, and what happens next. We call our process the “transparency tour” because it feels like walking someone through a museum exhibit: each stop has a story, a supporting artifact, and a clear takeaway. When everyone takes the same tour, the odds of a last-minute surprise drop dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-1-intent--context&#34;&gt;Stop 1: Intent + context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We open with a short intent memo. It outlines loan amount, property use, target close, compensation style, liquidity sources, and unique considerations like RSU cliffs or global income. The memo lives inside the same portal where we archive lender receipts, so anyone joining midstream can get oriented in minutes. This single document saves hours of repetition because we no longer re-explain the borrower’s story every time a new underwriter or executive enters the chat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
