<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>5 Percent Down on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/5-percent-down/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 5 Percent Down on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/5-percent-down/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How We Bought with 5% Down and Still Won a Multiple-Offer Battle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/five-percent-down-conforming-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomeloan/blogs/five-percent-down-conforming-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my partner and I decided to buy our first home, saving 20% felt impossible. We live in a high-cost market where starter homes hover near $720,000, and we didn’t want to spend another three years renting while prices climbed. Instead, we built a 5% down conforming strategy that won a multiple-offer situation and sailed through underwriting. Here’s how we did it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-budget-backwards-from-the-payment&#34;&gt;Step 1: Budget backwards from the payment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rather than picking a list price and hoping the payment worked, we opened a spreadsheet and reverse-engineered affordability. We entered the loan amount (95% of projected prices), current conforming rates, and estimated PMI premiums. We added taxes, insurance, HOA dues, and a buffer for maintenance. The target payment number told us the true maximum purchase price we could tolerate. That discipline prevented us from chasing homes that would have made every month feel tight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
