<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planning on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:05:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 7-Day HELOC Prep Checklist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/heloc-prep-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/heloclending/blogs/heloc-prep-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake I made during my first HELOC attempt was assuming I could wing it. The lender asked for CLTV math, I fumbled. They wanted proof of reserves, I rummaged through email. This time around, I built a seven-day prep checklist that aligned calculators, credit steps, and lender communication. By the end of the week I had a shareable packet, a calmer household, and a green light from underwriting. Here’s the day-by-day breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DSCR Rehearsal Night With Our Investor Group</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/dscr-rehearsal-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/dscr-rehearsal-night/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every time we add a property to the portfolio we host what we call DSCR Rehearsal Night. It is part financial review, part theater practice. We gather everyone who touches the file—property manager, bookkeeper, loan officer, and any passive investors—then run through the numbers until we can explain them without glancing at notes. The ritual means our non-QM submissions feel as buttoned up as agency loans, even when the rent rolls are messy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Asset Depletion Sprint Before Rate Sheets Change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/asset-depletion-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/asset-depletion-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asset depletion loans sound simple—show enough money, get approved—but every underwriter asks the same questions about seasoning, withdrawals, and exit plans. After watching a rate sheet worsen while we hunted for a missing statement, we built a five-day sprint that keeps the entire asset story tidy. Here is how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-inventory-and-intent&#34;&gt;Day 1: Inventory and intent&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We start with a whiteboard session listing every account we plan to use: brokerage, retirement, trust, and cash-value insurance. For each line we note ownership, recent large deposits, and whether withdrawals trigger penalties. Then we mirror that list in the overlay spreadsheet from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.browselenders.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BrowseLenders.com&lt;/a&gt;. The sheet forces us to record which lenders accept each account type and what percentage of the balance they use for qualifying income. That clarity prevents arguments later when someone insists, “But Bank X counted the whole thing last year.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kitchen Table DTI Summit We Host Before Every Conventional Offer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/dti-summit-kitchen-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/dti-summit-kitchen-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I call it the Kitchen Table DTI Summit because it sounds fancier than &amp;ldquo;everyone clear your schedules&amp;rdquo;. The ritual started when we lost a home to a buyer who responded faster to underwriting conditions. Now, every time we think about writing a conventional offer, we gather laptops, printed pay stubs, and a bowl of snacks and walk through six checkpoints. By the end of the evening, we know whether our debt-to-income ratio is ready for scrutiny, what documentation needs refreshing, and how to talk about reserves without stumbling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Three-Meeting HELOC Strategy Sprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/homeequityloanspecialist/blogs/heloc-strategy-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/homeequityloanspecialist/blogs/heloc-strategy-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We treat big borrowing decisions the same way we handle product launches: short sprints, clear owners, and a doc that captures every loose thread. When it came time to draw on our home equity, we scheduled three focused meetings over one weekend. By Sunday night we knew how much to request, which debts to fold in, and how to present the story to our loan officer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-1-clarify-the-intention-statement&#34;&gt;Meeting 1: Clarify the intention statement&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We opened the sprint with a simple question—why are we touching equity now? The answers ranged from finishing a half-completed kitchen to wiping out a pair of high-rate cards. Once we listed every motivation, we prioritized them by impact on monthly cash flow. That exercise forced us to hold the renovation plan loosely and commit to debt reduction first. A quick screen share of payoff projections from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cash-outrefinance.com&#34; class=&#34;text-accent hover:underline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cash-OutRefinance.com&lt;/a&gt; helped everyone see how a blended cash-out plus HELOC path compared to the line-only option. We logged the pros and cons in our sprint doc so the reasoning would still make sense months later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Calm-Down Calendar That Tamed My Volatile Rate Week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/calm-volatility-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/calm-volatility-calendar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday, the bond market woke up cranky and my floating conforming rate followed suit. We were two weeks from closing, juggling inspection repairs, and still waiting on the last employment verification. Watching pricing alerts pop up every hour felt like standing on a dock while waves crashed from every direction. Instead of doom-scrolling, I built what I now call my “calm-down calendar”—a living schedule that organized every conversation, document, and decision against the exact thresholds that would trigger a lock. The calendar turned five chaotic days into a manageable sprint. Here is how it unfolded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Ran a 14-Day Jumbo Loan Officer Selection Sprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/jumboloanofficers/blogs/jumbo-officer-selection-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/jumboloanofficers/blogs/jumbo-officer-selection-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most jumbo borrowers assume the right loan officer will magically appear when they email a private bank. I learned the hard way that the selection cycle matters as much as the rate sheet. My household carries income from a tech salary, venture distributions, and vesting stock, so documentation sprawl kills momentum. I decided to run a 14-day sprint to identify an officer who could keep up. Here is what I documented for every step so you can reuse the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Our State Rate Benchmark Summit Works</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgagerates/blogs/state-rate-benchmark-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgagerates/blogs/state-rate-benchmark-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Tuesday afternoon we host what we jokingly call the “State Rate Benchmark Summit.” It started as two people swapping lender screenshots and has evolved into a 60-minute production that keeps our entire conforming mortgage pipeline on track. The summit runs on evidence, timestamps, and reusable templates so anyone who misses the call can still follow the decisions. Here is the structure we follow and how you can adapt it for your own team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How We Kept Our Jumbo Underwriting Review Calm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/jumboloanofficers/blogs/jumbo-underwriting-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/jumboloanofficers/blogs/jumbo-underwriting-calibration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jumbo underwriting reviews are famous for derailing strong borrowers. Between reserve requirements, concentrated stock positions, and appraisal scrutiny, even well-paid households can feel shaky. My partner and I recently closed on a $2.8 million primary residence while juggling IPO lockups and relocation reimbursements. We promised ourselves the review would stay calm, so we reverse engineered the process into six checkpoints. Use our notes to shorten your own stress cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-rebuild-the-financial-narrative&#34;&gt;1. Rebuild the financial narrative&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We stopped thinking in terms of “documents” and started thinking in terms of chapters. Chapter one covered base salary, bonuses, and deferred comp. Chapter two summarized equity: RSUs, ESPP holdings, and privately held shares. Chapter three captured passive income from rentals and syndications. Each chapter opened with a one-page narrative that gave the underwriter context before they flipped through PDFs. The clarity alone removed three rounds of questions because our officer always had a cheat sheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Treated Our Rate Lock Like A Fire Drill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgagerates/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Locking a conventional rate felt less like a quiet paperwork step and more like launching a new product. The headline noise, conflicting advice from friends, and lender portal notifications created paralysis. So we treated the lock as a fire drill: three short sprints, repeatable documentation, and clear rules about who could approve changes. By Monday morning we submitted conditions, negotiated a float-down clause, and still had energy left to eat dinner like normal people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
