<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contractors on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/contractors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contractors on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/contractors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VA Renovation Bid Tracker for Tidy Underwriting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-renovation-bid-tracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few things spike blood pressure like trying to squeeze contractor bids, inspection responses, and VA renovation overlays into the same week. Most buyers treat the process like a scavenger hunt, which is why lenders slow-walk approvals. Build a repeatable bid tracker instead. The framework below is tuned for service members who juggle PCS timelines, guard drills, and family life yet still want to close on a property that needs work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built a Support Team Around My Cash-Out Refi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancecalculators/blogs/support-team-cashout-refi-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancecalculators/blogs/support-team-cashout-refi-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cash-out refinances touch every corner of your financial life—taxes, credit, contractors, and long-term planning. Instead of running the process solo, I assembled a small support team and shared calculator outputs with everyone. Collaboration sped up underwriting, guided the contractor, and kept my CPA ready for tax season. Here’s the playbook you can reuse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-start-with-the-lender&#34;&gt;Step 1: Start with the lender&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I sent the equity availability report to my loan officer before official disclosures. It outlined target loan amount, estimated proceeds, and reserve requirements. Because the report included buffer scenarios, the loan officer knew we could absorb a slightly lower appraisal if necessary. That transparency built trust and kept email threads short.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
