<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cash-Out Refinance on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/cash-out-refinance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cash-Out Refinance on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:05:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/cash-out-refinance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Equity Allocation Blueprint for Cash-Out Funds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refinancemtgs/blogs/equity-allocation-blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refinancemtgs/blogs/equity-allocation-blueprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cash-out refinancing can feel like standing in front of a firehose. The lender asks where the money is going, you answer with a polite summary, and they still stare like you just confessed to a shopping spree. I wanted to avoid that dynamic, so I created an equity allocation blueprint long before the appraisal even came back. It became the centerpiece of my loan file and the guardrail that kept our household from overspending once cash hit the account. Here’s exactly how I built it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Used Cash-Out Refinance for My Kitchen Remodel: Here&#39;s What It Actually Cost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/i-used-cash-out-refinance-for-my-kitchen-remodel-here-is-what-it-actually-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/renovationloanofficers/blogs/i-used-cash-out-refinance-for-my-kitchen-remodel-here-is-what-it-actually-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our kitchen was stuck in 1992. Laminate countertops, oak cabinets with brass hardware, linoleum floors, and fluorescent lighting. After 8 years of living with it, we finally decided: &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s time for a complete renovation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Budget for our dream kitchen: &lt;strong&gt;$62,000&lt;/strong&gt; (new cabinets, quartz countertops, tile backsplash, stainless appliances, hardwood floors, recessed lighting, plumbing and electrical updates).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had three financing options:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1: Home equity line of credit (HELOC)&lt;/strong&gt; – variable rate, currently 8.50%, interest-only payments, 10-year draw period&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Option 2: Personal home improvement loan&lt;/strong&gt; – fixed rate 10.25%, 7-year term, no collateral required&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Option 3: Cash-out refinance&lt;/strong&gt; – replace our existing mortgage, pull out cash for renovations, fixed rate&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
