<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conventional Loans on Purchase Mortgage Loans</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/tags/conventional-loans/</link><description>Recent content in Conventional Loans on Purchase Mortgage Loans</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://purchasemortgageloans.com/tags/conventional-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Waited 4 Months to Improve My Credit 38 Points - Saved $4,200 on My First Home Purchase</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started seriously looking at homes in March 2024, I was ready to apply for a mortgage immediately. I had saved $18,000 for down payment on a $285,000 home, my debt-to-income ratio was solid at 38%, and I assumed my credit score would be &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I checked my actual middle credit score through my lender&amp;rsquo;s pre-qualification: 657. Not terrible, but my loan officer explained I was sitting right at the edge between two different rate tiers—and waiting a few months to improve my credit could save me thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FHA 3.5% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Ran the Numbers for My $310,000 Purchase</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/fha-3.5-down-vs.-conventional-5-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/fha-3.5-down-vs.-conventional-5-down-i-ran-the-numbers-for-my-310000-purchase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I spent three months comparing FHA and conventional loan options before purchasing my first home in August 2024. Every article I read said &amp;ldquo;FHA is for low credit, conventional is for high credit,&amp;rdquo; but with 668 credit score, I qualified for both programs—and the decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the actual math I ran on my $310,000 home purchase, comparing FHA 3.5% down versus conventional 5% down, including all the hidden costs nobody talks about.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VA 0% Down vs. Conventional 5% Down - I Compared Both for My $340,000 Military Purchase</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/va-0-down-vs.-conventional-5-down-i-compared-both-for-my-340000-military-purchase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/va-0-down-vs.-conventional-5-down-i-compared-both-for-my-340000-military-purchase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m active duty Air Force with 8 years of service, and when I started house hunting in September 2024, I assumed my VA loan benefit was automatically the best option. Zero down payment, no PMI, favorable rates for military—what could be better than that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I ran the actual numbers comparing VA 0% down versus conventional 5% down for my $340,000 home purchase in San Antonio, and the results surprised me. VA saved me money in some scenarios but not others, depending on how long I planned to keep the home and whether I factored in opportunity cost of the down payment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conventional 3% Down with PMI vs. FHA 3.5% Down - I Chose Conventional and Saved $8,400</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/conventional-3-down-with-pmi-vs.-fha-3.5-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/conventional-3-down-with-pmi-vs.-fha-3.5-down-i-chose-conventional-and-saved-8400/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my home search in April 2024, I assumed FHA was my only option for minimal down payment. I had saved $11,500 and wanted to buy a $325,000 home—which meant 3.5% down ($11,375) would barely work with FHA, leaving me just $125 for closing costs and emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then my loan officer mentioned conventional 3% down programs. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even realized conventional allowed less than 5% down. After running the numbers comparing FHA 3.5% versus conventional 3%, I chose conventional despite it costing $64 more per month initially—because PMI removal in year 6 would save me $8,400 over 6-10 years compared to FHA&amp;rsquo;s permanent mortgage insurance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My 43% DTI Got Approved for $385,000 Purchase - But 46% Was Denied, Here's Why</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/my-43-dti-got-approved-for-385000-purchase-but-46-was-denied-heres-why/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/my-43-dti-got-approved-for-385000-purchase-but-46-was-denied-heres-why/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I applied for a conventional purchase mortgage in September 2024 with $92,000 annual income, 708 credit score, and 10% down payment on a $385,000 home. My debt-to-income ratio was 46.2%. I was confident I would be approved—my income was strong, my credit was above the 700 threshold, and I had substantial down payment saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underwriter denied my application citing &amp;ldquo;debt-to-income ratio exceeds maximum allowable threshold for program guidelines without sufficient compensating factors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>