<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scenario Planning on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/scenario-planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scenario Planning on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/scenario-planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our Rate-Lock Fire Drill: Points vs Par In One Evening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/rate-lock-fire-drill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender texts “I’d lock by tonight,” we default to a playbook we nicknamed the rate-lock fire drill. The protocol keeps us from panic-deciding whether to pay points, float, or pivot to a shorter lock. Within two hours we have updated pricing tests, fresh credit notes, and talking points for the entire decision chain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-define-the-window-and-the-stakes&#34;&gt;Step 1: Define the window and the stakes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first voice memo goes into the family chat explaining what is happening and why tonight matters. Then we confirm the real deadline. Sometimes “lock tonight” is code for “rates are trending up but you likely have until noon tomorrow.” We pin the actual cut-off to the top of our shared task board. At the same time we confirm the property status: appraisal done, title clear, insurance quote ready. If one of those is missing, we can’t justify an expensive lock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Saturday Points-vs-Credits War Room</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/points-vs-credits-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/points-vs-credits-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender dumped three shiny quotes into my inbox, each offer mixed points, credits, and lock periods differently. I am the spreadsheet-loving member of our household, so I spent a full Saturday turning those quotes into a points-vs-credits war room. The goal was simple: understand the true cost of each structure before locking, then explain the decision to my spouse and financial coach without jargon. Here is the framework that worked and how you can plug in your numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt Payoff vs. Investment: What My Cash-Out Calculator Revealed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancecalculators/blogs/debt-payoff-cashout-strategy-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/cashoutrefinancecalculators/blogs/debt-payoff-cashout-strategy-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I refinanced to pull $85,000 of equity with one goal: eliminate $62,000 of high-interest debt and decide what to do with the remaining cash. Should I invest, or should I accelerate the mortgage payoff? The calculators brought clarity—and a surprisingly balanced plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-consolidation-baseline&#34;&gt;Step 1: Consolidation baseline&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The debt payoff calculator listed every obligation: credit cards averaging 22.4%, a personal loan at 13.9%, and a lingering auto loan at 6.25%. After entering balances and minimum payments, the tool compared current monthly outflows ($1,782) to the projected cash-out mortgage payment ($1,238). Even after adding $214 to cover the higher mortgage, I netted $330 of monthly relief. That data gave me confidence to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
