<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rate Shopping on Conventional Mortgage Rates</title><link>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/tags/rate-shopping/</link><description>Recent content in Rate Shopping on Conventional Mortgage Rates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/tags/rate-shopping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our Sunday Rate Trend Huddle</title><link>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/our-sunday-rate-trend-huddle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/our-sunday-rate-trend-huddle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rates change faster than most of us can refresh our news apps, so we created a weekly “rate trend huddle” to interpret the noise. The huddle happens Sunday evening, lasts 40 minutes, and feeds every decision we make the following week. It has become the calmest part of the mortgage journey because it replaces speculation with receipts and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gather-inputs-before-anyone-joins"&gt;Gather inputs before anyone joins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two hours before the huddle, we drop three items into a shared folder: a digest of headlines with links to primary sources, a spreadsheet of lender pricing pulled from our shortlist, and a clip of the most relevant economic calendar events. For overlays and pricing quirks, we paste annotated screenshots from &lt;a href="https://www.browselenders.com" class="text-accent hover:underline" target="_blank"&gt;BrowseLenders.com&lt;/a&gt; so participants see exactly where the adjustments are hiding. Preparation is non-negotiable; the meeting is for decisions, not reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Lender Fit Scorecard That Saved Our Sanity</title><link>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/the-lender-fit-scorecard-that-saved-our-sanity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/the-lender-fit-scorecard-that-saved-our-sanity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing a lender for a conventional loan can feel like speed dating with spreadsheets. Everyone says they have the best rates, the friendliest processors, and the fastest turn times. We needed a way to cut through the charm and surface the facts, so we built a lender fit scorecard. The scorecard balances quantitative metrics with soft-skill signals and has become the backbone of every referral meeting we host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="build-the-categories-before-filling-in-names"&gt;Build the categories before filling in names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first mistake we made was letting lenders define the agenda. Now we list the categories before the first call: pricing transparency, communication cadence, underwriting philosophy, appraisal management, and closing flexibility. Under pricing transparency we track whether the lender includes all loan-level price adjustments up front or waits until disclosures. For underwriting philosophy we note how comfortable they are handling compensating factors if appraisals come in light.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>