<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Jersey Home Rates</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1400/</link>
    <description>Recent content on New Jersey Home Rates</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1400/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Credit Score Impact on New Jersey Mortgage Rates: Points and Strategy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1400/blogs/credit-score-impact-on-new-jersey-mortgage-rates-points-and-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1400/blogs/credit-score-impact-on-new-jersey-mortgage-rates-points-and-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;credit-score-determines-your-new-jersey-mortgage-rate-tier&#34;&gt;Credit Score Determines Your New Jersey Mortgage Rate Tier&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your credit score isn&amp;rsquo;t just a number lenders glance at—it&amp;rsquo;s the primary driver of the interest rate you&amp;rsquo;ll pay on your New Jersey mortgage. More than property value, down payment, or employment, credit score creates the single largest rate differentiation across lenders. A 60-point credit score difference can change your mortgage rate by 0.5%–1.0%, translating to $100–$250 monthly payment difference on a $750K purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APR vs Interest Rate in New Jersey: What&#39;s the Real Difference?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1400/blogs/apr-vs-interest-rate-in-new-jersey-whats-the-real-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1400/blogs/apr-vs-interest-rate-in-new-jersey-whats-the-real-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rate-vs-apr-the-critical-difference&#34;&gt;Rate vs APR: The Critical Difference&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most misunderstood concepts in mortgage shopping is the difference between interest rate and APR (Annual Percentage Rate). Many New Jersey borrowers focus on rate when they should be analyzing APR—especially when shopping jumbo loans and comparing lenders with dramatically different fee structures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;defining-the-terms&#34;&gt;Defining the Terms&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The percentage you pay yearly on the loan balance. This is the &amp;ldquo;sticker price&amp;rdquo; lenders advertise. A 6.75% rate means you pay 6.75% annually on outstanding balance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How New Jersey Property Tax Impacts Your Mortgage Rate and DTI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1400/blogs/how-new-jersey-property-tax-impacts-your-mortgage-rate-and-dti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1400/blogs/how-new-jersey-property-tax-impacts-your-mortgage-rate-and-dti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-jersey-property-tax-reality&#34;&gt;The New Jersey Property Tax Reality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Jersey has the nation&amp;rsquo;s highest average property tax rate at approximately 2.49% annually—more than &lt;strong&gt;double&lt;/strong&gt; the national average of 1.1%. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a general financial burden; it fundamentally changes how mortgage lenders evaluate your application and what rates they&amp;rsquo;ll offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the relationship between New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s property taxes and your mortgage rate is crucial for any homebuyer in Bergen, Essex, Morris, Hudson, or any other NJ county. Property tax impacts appear in two critical places: directly in your monthly housing payment (PITI calculation) and in debt-to-income (DTI) calculations that determine qualification amounts and rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Jersey County Mortgage Rates: Bergen, Essex, Morris &amp; Hudson Comparison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1400/blogs/new-jersey-county-mortgage-rates-bergen-essex-morris-hudson-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1400/blogs/new-jersey-county-mortgage-rates-bergen-essex-morris-hudson-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-county-rate-differences-across-new-jersey&#34;&gt;Understanding County Rate Differences Across New Jersey&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s mortgage market isn&amp;rsquo;t monolithic—rates and programs vary significantly by county based on lender competition, property values, and market specialization. Bergen County, with its affluent market and strong lender presence, typically shows the most competitive rates, while Essex, Morris, and Hudson Counties have their own rate dynamics based on local demand and specialized lending requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bergen-county-the-competitive-market&#34;&gt;Bergen County: The Competitive Market&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bergen County dominates New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s mortgage market in terms of lender competition and volume. The region&amp;rsquo;s affluent communities—Englewood Cliffs, Tenafly, Fort Lee, and Ridgewood—attract mortgage lenders of all sizes, from national banks to specialized brokers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
