<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Credit Improvement on Purchase Mortgage Loans</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/tags/credit-improvement/</link><description>Recent content in Credit Improvement on Purchase Mortgage Loans</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://purchasemortgageloans.com/tags/credit-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Waited 4 Months to Improve My Credit 38 Points - Saved $4,200 on My First Home Purchase</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-waited-4-months-to-improve-my-credit-38-points-saved-4200-on-my-first-home-purchase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I started seriously looking at homes in March 2024, I was ready to apply for a mortgage immediately. I had saved $18,000 for down payment on a $285,000 home, my debt-to-income ratio was solid at 38%, and I assumed my credit score would be &amp;ldquo;good enough.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I checked my actual middle credit score through my lender&amp;rsquo;s pre-qualification: 657. Not terrible, but my loan officer explained I was sitting right at the edge between two different rate tiers—and waiting a few months to improve my credit could save me thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Bought My Home at 672 Credit Then Refinanced 18 Months Later at 741 - Saved $287 Per Month</title><link>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-bought-my-home-at-672-credit-then-refinanced-18-months-later-at-741-saved-287-per-month/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purchasemortgageloans.com/blogs/i-bought-my-home-at-672-credit-then-refinanced-18-months-later-at-741-saved-287-per-month/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2023, I bought my first home with 672 credit score using an FHA loan at 6.875% interest rate. In September 2024—just 18 months later—I refinanced to conventional loan at 6.125% with 741 credit score, removing my mortgage insurance entirely and dropping my monthly payment by $287.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone told me to &amp;ldquo;wait until your credit improves before buying,&amp;rdquo; but I ran the numbers and realized buying now with suboptimal financing and refinancing later would cost me less than waiting 18 months while my rent increased and home prices continued rising in my market.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>