<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VA Loan on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/va-loan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VA Loan on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/va-loan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funding Fee Waiver Playbook for VA Buyers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/funding-fee-waiver-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ask ten veterans how the funding fee works and you will hear legends, half-truths, and rumors about mysterious VA decisions. The fee funds the program, which means lenders scrutinize every waiver request and every dollar collected. Instead of waiting for the underwriter to tell you what is missing, build a playbook that covers entitlement math, disability documentation, and what to do if the waiver is not yet on your Certificate of Eligibility (COE). Here is the same structure we walk through during BrowseLenders coaching calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PCS Overlap Cash-Flow Map for VA Buyers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/pcs-overlap-cashflow-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/pcs-overlap-cashflow-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every VA buyer secretly fears the same thing: getting pinned between two sets of housing costs while PCS orders march forward. Cash gets trapped in deposits, pay periods bounce, and suddenly the underwriting call feels more stressful than deployment prep. The antidote is a cash-flow map that treats overlap months like a temporary campaign, not a chaotic surprise. Grab a whiteboard, your favorite spreadsheet, and this guide—we will walk through the same framework we coach service members on every week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
