<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HUD Consultant on FHA 203(k) Mortgages</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/tags/hud-consultant/</link><description>Recent content in HUD Consultant on FHA 203(k) Mortgages</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fha203kmortgages.com/tags/hud-consultant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My FHA 203(k) Inspector Ride-Alongs</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/my-fha-203k-inspector-ride-alongs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/my-fha-203k-inspector-ride-alongs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Before my FHA 203(k) closed, I promised my HUD consultant I would never hover during inspections. By the second draw, curiosity won. I asked if I could quietly tag along, and he laughed: “Please do—borrowers who show up make my paperwork easier.” Riding along became one of the smartest decisions I made. It turned draw days from mystery events into collaborative checkpoints that impressed my lender, inspired my contractor, and kept change orders grounded in reality. Here is what those visits taught me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The 48-Hour Contractor Interview Sprint That Saved My FHA 203(k) Timeline</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/the-48-hour-contractor-interview-sprint-that-saved-my-fha-203k-timeline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/the-48-hour-contractor-interview-sprint-that-saved-my-fha-203k-timeline/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I assumed lining up contractors for my FHA 203(k) was the easy part—send a scope, collect a few bids, pick the friendliest voice. Then my HUD consultant reminded me that every subcontractor would be vetted by the lender, that every change would ripple through the draw schedule, and that the clock on my purchase contract did not care about anyone’s backlog. Instead of stretching the interviews across weeks, I ran an intentional 48-hour sprint. By Monday morning, I had three rehab-ready bids, a synced timeline, and a lender who called the prep “shockingly organized.” Here is the playbook.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building the Rehab Appraisal Brief That Won Over My Lender</title><link>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/building-the-rehab-appraisal-brief-that-won-over-my-lender/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://fha203kmortgages.com/blogs/building-the-rehab-appraisal-brief-that-won-over-my-lender/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When the underwriter asked for “more comfort” around my after-improved value (ARV), I realized my file still looked like a pile of emails instead of a story. I spent one long Sunday building what I now call the Rehab Appraisal Brief—a single PDF that combined comps, scope clarification, contractor proof, and credit-ready milestones. By Monday afternoon the lender cleared the valuation condition without asking another question. Here is the step-by-step walkthrough.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>