<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jumbo Lending on California Jumbo Lenders</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1377/categories/jumbo-lending/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jumbo Lending on California Jumbo Lenders</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1377/categories/jumbo-lending/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>California High-Balance Conforming: $1,149,825 Limit Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1377/blogs/california-high-balance-conforming-1149825-limit-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1377/blogs/california-high-balance-conforming-1149825-limit-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-californias-jumbo-limit-is-different-and-why-it-matters&#34;&gt;Why California&amp;rsquo;s Jumbo Limit Is Different (And Why It Matters)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;California is one of the most expensive housing markets in the U.S.—and Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac (the government-sponsored enterprises that buy most mortgages) recognize this. Instead of the baseline conforming loan limit of &lt;strong&gt;$766,550&lt;/strong&gt; (2025), most California counties get a &lt;strong&gt;high-balance conforming limit of $1,149,825&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a small detail—it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;rate, reserve, and approval advantage&lt;/strong&gt; that saves California buyers thousands annually. Understanding where the conforming limit ends and jumbo begins determines which lenders you shop, how much you&amp;rsquo;ll pay in interest, and whether you need 6 months or 12 months of reserves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stock Compensation &amp; California Jumbo Loans: RSU Underwriting Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1377/blogs/stock-compensation-california-jumbo-loans-rsu-underwriting-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1377/blogs/stock-compensation-california-jumbo-loans-rsu-underwriting-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-stock-compensation-complicates-jumbo-approval&#34;&gt;Why Stock Compensation Complicates Jumbo Approval&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bay Area tech workers earn substantial income from &lt;strong&gt;equity compensation&lt;/strong&gt;—RSUs (restricted stock units), stock options, ESPP (employee stock purchase plans), and performance shares. But mortgage underwriters treat stock comp &lt;strong&gt;very differently&lt;/strong&gt; than W-2 salary. Understanding how lenders count (or don&amp;rsquo;t count) equity income and assets is critical for jumbo loan approval in California&amp;rsquo;s expensive markets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The challenge&lt;/strong&gt;: Most jumbo lenders follow &lt;strong&gt;Fannie Mae/Freddie Mac guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; (even for portfolio loans), which require 2+ years of stock comp history and strict vesting schedules. If you&amp;rsquo;re a new hire at a tech company with a 4-year RSU vesting schedule, traditional lenders may &lt;strong&gt;exclude 75% of your stock comp&lt;/strong&gt; from qualifying income—tanking your debt-to-income ratio and killing your approval.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bay Area vs. SoCal Jumbo Rates: Regional Pricing Differences Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1377/blogs/bay-area-vs.-socal-jumbo-rates-regional-pricing-differences-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1377/blogs/bay-area-vs.-socal-jumbo-rates-regional-pricing-differences-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-jumbo-rates-vary-across-california&#34;&gt;Why Jumbo Rates Vary Across California&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;California isn&amp;rsquo;t one housing market—it&amp;rsquo;s a collection of distinct regional markets with different median prices, lender competition, property types, and risk profiles. A $2M jumbo loan in &lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto&lt;/strong&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t price the same as a $2M loan in &lt;strong&gt;Fresno&lt;/strong&gt;—even with identical borrower credit, LTV, and reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding &lt;strong&gt;regional jumbo pricing factors&lt;/strong&gt; helps you shop lenders strategically, negotiate better rates, and avoid overpaying based on outdated assumptions about California&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;uniform&amp;rdquo; jumbo market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
