<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workflow on Conventional Mortgage Rates</title><link>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/tags/workflow/</link><description>Recent content in Workflow on Conventional Mortgage Rates</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:45:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>We Treated Our Rate Lock Like A Fire Drill</title><link>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/we-treated-our-rate-lock-like-a-fire-drill/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/we-treated-our-rate-lock-like-a-fire-drill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Locking a conventional rate felt less like a quiet paperwork step and more like launching a new product. The headline noise, conflicting advice from friends, and lender portal notifications created paralysis. So we treated the lock as a fire drill: three short sprints, repeatable documentation, and clear rules about who could approve changes. By Monday morning we submitted conditions, negotiated a float-down clause, and still had energy left to eat dinner like normal people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Our Sunday Rate Trend Huddle</title><link>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/our-sunday-rate-trend-huddle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://conventionalmortgagerates.com/blogs/our-sunday-rate-trend-huddle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rates change faster than most of us can refresh our news apps, so we created a weekly “rate trend huddle” to interpret the noise. The huddle happens Sunday evening, lasts 40 minutes, and feeds every decision we make the following week. It has become the calmest part of the mortgage journey because it replaces speculation with receipts and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="gather-inputs-before-anyone-joins"&gt;Gather inputs before anyone joins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two hours before the huddle, we drop three items into a shared folder: a digest of headlines with links to primary sources, a spreadsheet of lender pricing pulled from our shortlist, and a clip of the most relevant economic calendar events. For overlays and pricing quirks, we paste annotated screenshots from &lt;a href="https://www.browselenders.com" class="text-accent hover:underline" target="_blank"&gt;BrowseLenders.com&lt;/a&gt; so participants see exactly where the adjustments are hiding. Preparation is non-negotiable; the meeting is for decisions, not reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>