<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Builder Financing on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/builder-financing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Builder Financing on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/builder-financing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Construction-to-Permanent Loans: Everything I Wish I Knew Before Building My Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loans-everything-i-wish-i-knew-before-building-my-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loans-everything-i-wish-i-knew-before-building-my-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I decided to build our dream home three years ago, everyone warned us: &amp;ldquo;Construction is expensive, stressful, and always takes longer than you think.&amp;rdquo; They were right—but what nobody explained was how &lt;strong&gt;construction financing&lt;/strong&gt; actually works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent weeks researching construction loans, getting confused by terms like &amp;ldquo;construction-to-permanent,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;one-time close,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;draw schedules,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;interest-only payments.&amp;rdquo; By the time I figured it out, we were already under contract with a builder and scrambling to find the right financing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Builder Incentives vs. Independent Lenders: I Chose Wrong and It Cost Me $12,000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/builder-incentives-vs-independent-lenders-i-chose-wrong-and-it-cost-me-12000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/builder-incentives-vs-independent-lenders-i-chose-wrong-and-it-cost-me-12000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I bought my new construction home two years ago, the builder&amp;rsquo;s sales rep made me an offer I thought I couldn&amp;rsquo;t refuse: &lt;strong&gt;$15,000 in closing cost assistance and $5,000 in design center upgrades&lt;/strong&gt; if I financed through their preferred lender.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did the math in my head: &amp;ldquo;$20,000 in free money? I&amp;rsquo;d be crazy to say no!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I signed up with the builder&amp;rsquo;s preferred lender without shopping around. Big mistake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spec Home vs. Custom Build: Why I&#39;d Choose Differently Next Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/spec-home-vs-custom-build-why-i-would-choose-differently-next-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/spec-home-vs-custom-build-why-i-would-choose-differently-next-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My wife and I spent months debating: &lt;strong&gt;Should we buy a spec home or custom build?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spec home:&lt;/strong&gt; Move-in ready (or nearly ready), fixed price, traditional financing, close in 30-60 days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom build:&lt;/strong&gt; Choose everything (floor plan, finishes, lot), construction loan complexity, 7-12 month timeline (or longer).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We chose to &lt;strong&gt;custom build&lt;/strong&gt;. We wanted the perfect home, exactly as we envisioned it, with every detail our way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back 18 months later, after going through construction delays, cost overruns, financing complications, and endless decision fatigue—&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d choose a spec home&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Builder Financing Requirements: What Lenders Look for in Builder Credentials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/builder-financing-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/builder-financing-requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you apply for construction financing, your lender isn&amp;rsquo;t just evaluating you—they&amp;rsquo;re evaluating your builder. Construction loans carry significantly more risk than traditional mortgages because lenders are funding a home that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist yet, relying on your builder to complete the project on time, on budget, and to code. If your builder fails to deliver, the lender&amp;rsquo;s collateral (your partially completed home) could be worth far less than the loan amount.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction-to-Permanent Loan Guide: Complete Process from Groundbreaking to Permanent Mortgage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loan-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionmortgagebrokers/blogs/construction-to-permanent-loan-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building your dream home from the ground up is exciting—but the financing can feel overwhelming if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand how construction-to-permanent loans actually work. Unlike traditional mortgages where you borrow once and start making payments immediately, construction-to-permanent financing structures everything differently: one closing, extended rate locks, draw-based funding, interest-only payments during the build, and automatic conversion to a traditional mortgage when construction is complete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering new construction, understanding this loan type is essential before signing builder contracts or breaking ground. Here&amp;rsquo;s everything you need to know about construction-to-permanent loans—from qualification through final conversion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
