<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Budgeting on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/budgeting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Budgeting on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/budgeting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BAH Budget War-Gaming Before You Write a VA Offer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/bah-offer-budget-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/bah-offer-budget-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BAH is more than a monthly deposit. It is a living constraint that either keeps your VA offer disciplined or sets you up for payment regret. Most of the budget panic we see happens because buyers stare at the BAH line in MyPay without modeling how that allowance collides with utilities, temporary lodging, or life during a PCS. Use this field manual to war-game your numbers before you fall for a listing that quietly outpaces your cash flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Saturday Points-vs-Credits War Room</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/points-vs-credits-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conforminghomerates/blogs/points-vs-credits-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When our lender dumped three shiny quotes into my inbox, each offer mixed points, credits, and lock periods differently. I am the spreadsheet-loving member of our household, so I spent a full Saturday turning those quotes into a points-vs-credits war room. The goal was simple: understand the true cost of each structure before locking, then explain the decision to my spouse and financial coach without jargon. Here is the framework that worked and how you can plug in your numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
