<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Buying on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/home-buying/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Buying on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/home-buying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Approval vs Pre-Qualification: Why One Gets You the House and One Doesn&#39;t</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification-why-one-gets-you-the-house-and-one-doesnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/pre-approval-vs-pre-qualification-why-one-gets-you-the-house-and-one-doesnt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started looking for my first home three years ago, I thought getting &amp;ldquo;pre-qualified&amp;rdquo; meant I was ready to make offers. I filled out a five-minute online form, got a number, and started touring homes. Two weeks later, I found the perfect place—and my offer was rejected in favor of a buyer who had &amp;ldquo;pre-approval.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s when I learned the hard lesson: &lt;strong&gt;pre-qualification and pre-approval are not the same thing&lt;/strong&gt;, and in competitive markets, only one of them actually matters to sellers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spec Home vs. Custom Build: Why I&#39;d Choose Differently Next Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/spec-home-vs-custom-build-why-i-would-choose-differently-next-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/newconstructionloanofficers/blogs/spec-home-vs-custom-build-why-i-would-choose-differently-next-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My wife and I spent months debating: &lt;strong&gt;Should we buy a spec home or custom build?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spec home:&lt;/strong&gt; Move-in ready (or nearly ready), fixed price, traditional financing, close in 30-60 days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom build:&lt;/strong&gt; Choose everything (floor plan, finishes, lot), construction loan complexity, 7-12 month timeline (or longer).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We chose to &lt;strong&gt;custom build&lt;/strong&gt;. We wanted the perfect home, exactly as we envisioned it, with every detail our way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back 18 months later, after going through construction delays, cost overruns, financing complications, and endless decision fatigue—&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d choose a spec home&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide 2025: From 0% to 20% and Everything Between</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/firsttimebuyeroptions/blogs/first-time-buyer-down-payment-guide-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-time-homebuyer-down-payment-guide-how-much-you-really-need-to-buy&#34;&gt;First-Time Homebuyer Down Payment Guide: How Much You Really Need to Buy&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest myth keeping renters from becoming homeowners? The belief that you need 20% down to buy a house. Here&amp;rsquo;s reality: over 70% of first-time buyers put down less than 10%, and many successful buyers put down as little as 0-3.5%. Understanding your real down payment options—and how to maximize them—can help you buy years sooner than you thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Nobody Tells You About Closing Costs Until You&#39;re Already Under Contract</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/what-nobody-tells-you-about-closing-costs-until-you-re-already-under-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/purchaseloanofficers/blogs/what-nobody-tells-you-about-closing-costs-until-you-re-already-under-contract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three days before my closing, I got the final Closing Disclosure from my lender. I expected to pay around $8,000 in closing costs based on the Loan Estimate I received weeks earlier. The actual number? &lt;strong&gt;$12,347.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was stunned. Where did the extra $4,347 come from? And why didn&amp;rsquo;t anyone warn me about these costs earlier?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After furiously Googling, calling my lender, and negotiating with vendors, I managed to reduce my closing costs by $2,100—but I still paid more than I expected. Looking back, I realize I could have saved even more if I&amp;rsquo;d known what to look for and what to negotiate from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
