<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DTI on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/tags/dti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DTI on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/tags/dti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debt-to-Income Ratio in Florida: What Loan Officers Actually Calculate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/debt-to-income-ratio-mortgage-qualification-florida-loan-officers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/debt-to-income-ratio-mortgage-qualification-florida-loan-officers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your debt-to-income ratio (DTI) is the gatekeeper for how much home you can buy. Florida loan officers use it to decide whether your payment fits. The good news: you can often improve DTI in weeks with the right moves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-dti-measures-and-the-simple-math&#34;&gt;What DTI measures (and the simple math)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DTI is the share of your gross monthly income that goes to monthly debts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formula:&lt;/strong&gt; (Total monthly debts ÷ Gross monthly income) × 100&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt-to-Income Ratio for Florida Refinance: How DTI Affects Your Qualification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/refifl/blogs/debt-to-income-ratio-florida-refinance-qualification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/refifl/blogs/debt-to-income-ratio-florida-refinance-qualification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your debt-to-income ratio (DTI) determines whether lenders approve your refinance—and it&amp;rsquo;s something you can actually control. Here&amp;rsquo;s how Florida lenders calculate it and what you can do to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-dti-actually-measures&#34;&gt;What DTI Actually Measures&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DTI is simple: &lt;strong&gt;total monthly debt payments ÷ gross monthly income × 100&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lenders want to see how much of your income goes toward debt. Lower DTI = lower risk. Higher DTI = higher risk (or denial).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kitchen Table DTI Summit We Host Before Every Conventional Offer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/dti-summit-kitchen-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmtg/blogs/dti-summit-kitchen-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I call it the Kitchen Table DTI Summit because it sounds fancier than &amp;ldquo;everyone clear your schedules&amp;rdquo;. The ritual started when we lost a home to a buyer who responded faster to underwriting conditions. Now, every time we think about writing a conventional offer, we gather laptops, printed pay stubs, and a bowl of snacks and walk through six checkpoints. By the end of the evening, we know whether our debt-to-income ratio is ready for scrutiny, what documentation needs refreshing, and how to talk about reserves without stumbling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming Loan DTI Requirements: Understanding Debt-to-Income Ratios for 2025 Approval</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-dti-requirements-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conformingmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-loan-dti-requirements-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your debt-to-income ratio (DTI) is one of the most critical factors in conforming loan approval—yet it&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most misunderstood. Many borrowers think they need perfect credit and massive income to qualify, when in reality, Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac accept DTI ratios up to 50% with compensating factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me break down exactly how DTI works, what ratios you need for approval, and proven strategies to optimize your debt picture before applying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conforming vs. Jumbo Loans in 2025: Loan Limits, Rates, and Qualification Strategies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-jumbo-loans-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/conventionalmortgageloans/blogs/conforming-vs-jumbo-loans-2025/</guid>
      <description>A practical 2025 guide comparing conforming and jumbo mortgages—how limits, rates, credit, and DTI shape approvals and total cost.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
