<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentation on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1379/categories/documentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentation on California Home Rates - Compare Mortgage Rates Across CA | Browse Lenders®</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1379/categories/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Florida Mortgage Documentation: What Loan Officers Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/florida-mortgage-documentation-requirements-what-loan-officers-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/loanofficersflorida/blogs/florida-mortgage-documentation-requirements-what-loan-officers-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Applying in Florida? The fastest approvals come from borrowers who show up file-ready. Loan officers are simply proving you can repay, the property fits the program, and disclosures are met. Here is the short list of what matters, why it matters, and how to get it ready without surprises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;income-prove-stability-not-perfection&#34;&gt;Income: Prove stability, not perfection&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loan officers want stable, sourced income that comfortably covers your new payment plus existing debts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W-2 borrowers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Bank Statement War Room Weekend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/bank-statement-war-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/nonconformingloanofficers/blogs/bank-statement-war-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We call it the Bank Statement War Room because it feels like one: laptops everywhere, sticky notes across the wall, and group texts flying between CPAs and loan officers. The weekend before our lender meeting we gathered 24 months of personal and business statements, every 1099, and the latest P&amp;amp;L. By Sunday night we had a single PDF that a non-QM underwriter could digest in minutes. Here is the exact process we ran.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First-Time Buyer Pre-Approval Checklist That Actually Works</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/homeloanpurchase/blogs/first-time-preapproval-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/homeloanpurchase/blogs/first-time-preapproval-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pre-approval should feel like a green light, not a guessing game. Yet most first-time buyers walk into the process without a plan, then scramble when lenders ask for documentation on tight deadlines. This guide lays out the preparation steps that consistently shorten review times and keep loan officers confident about your file. Treat it like an operating manual—update it every few weeks, share it with your agent, and bring it to every buyer strategy call.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organize Renovation Receipts Like an Appraiser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/onlinevaluecalculator/blogs/renovation-receipts-for-appraisal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/onlinevaluecalculator/blogs/renovation-receipts-for-appraisal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Property owners often complete upgrades on weekends, toss receipts in a drawer, and then panic when an appraiser asks for proof that a value bump is justified. Appraisers and underwriters want clean documentation that ties dollars spent to market reaction. Building a renovation packet in real time prevents last-minute scrambles and gives you leverage when you negotiate purchase offers, cash-out terms, or relocation credits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start by logging every project in a single spreadsheet the moment you sign a contract or buy supplies. Include columns for project scope, square footage impacted, contractor contact information, permit numbers, and before/after photos stored in a shared drive. This log becomes your table of contents, guiding anyone who reviews the packet to the right evidence within seconds. Add a notes column that explains whether the improvement was health and safety related, an efficiency upgrade, or a purely aesthetic refresh—lenders weigh those categories differently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The VA Loan Intake Briefing Checklist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-loan-intake-briefing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1379/veteranmortgagelenders/blogs/va-loan-intake-briefing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to calm VA mortgage anxiety is to treat the first lender conversation like an intake briefing. You are the officer in command of your own file. The lender wants clear orders, not scattered uploads. Below is the same checklist we run through with coaching clients before they ever click &amp;ldquo;apply.&amp;rdquo; Use it as a living document, revise it weekly, and share it with any spouse or co-borrower so the whole household rows in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
