<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Appraisal Gap on Jumbo Loan Officers</title><link>https://jumboloanofficers.com/tags/appraisal-gap/</link><description>Recent content in Appraisal Gap on Jumbo Loan Officers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:10:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jumboloanofficers.com/tags/appraisal-gap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Luxury Appraisal Gap Playbook for Seven-Figure Buyers</title><link>https://jumboloanofficers.com/blogs/luxury-appraisal-gap-playbook-for-seven-figure-buyers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:10:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jumboloanofficers.com/blogs/luxury-appraisal-gap-playbook-for-seven-figure-buyers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Appraisal gaps are awkward when you are buying an $800,000 starter home. They become existential when you are negotiating a $3 million estate with a boutique lender watching every dollar of collateral. We recently fought—and won—an appraisal gap dispute that could have derailed our purchase. Here is the playbook we built so other high-balance buyers can walk into valuation week confident instead of reactive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="build-the-valuation-package-before-the-appraiser-is-assigned"&gt;Build the valuation package before the appraiser is assigned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created a 20-page valuation brief the same week we went under contract. It included neighborhood sales, pocket listings, pending transactions, and private sales sourced through our agent’s network. We annotated every comp with adjustments for views, outdoor space, smart-home upgrades, and school zones. When the lender finally assigned an appraiser, we sent the brief through the loan officer so the document became part of the official work file. The appraiser thanked us for saving hours of research and referenced our notes several times in the final report.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>