<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FHA Loans on Bad Credit Loan Specialist</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1330/categories/fha-loans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FHA Loans on Bad Credit Loan Specialist</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1330/categories/fha-loans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FHA vs. Subprime Conventional Loans: Which Is Better for Bad Credit in 2025?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1330/blogs/fha-vs.-subprime-conventional-loans-which-is-better-for-bad-credit-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1330/blogs/fha-vs.-subprime-conventional-loans-which-is-better-for-bad-credit-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Borrowers with bad credit (580-660 scores) face a choice between FHA loans and subprime conventional financing. FHA allows lower credit scores (500+) and smaller down payments (3.5-10%), but requires mortgage insurance for the life of the loan on 3.5% down purchases. Subprime conventional loans start at 620 credit scores and require larger down payments (10-20%), but mortgage insurance can be removed once you reach 20% equity. Understanding which option costs less over time and fits your financial situation determines whether you save or waste thousands of dollars in unnecessary fees.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Mortgage with a 500-579 Credit Score in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1330/blogs/how-to-get-a-mortgage-with-a-500-579-credit-score-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1330/blogs/how-to-get-a-mortgage-with-a-500-579-credit-score-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 500-579 credit score puts you in the &amp;ldquo;very poor&amp;rdquo; credit range according to FICO standards, and most lenders will reject your mortgage application automatically. However, FHA loans allow 500-579 scores with a 10% down payment and manual underwriting—meaning human review of your full financial picture instead of automated rejection. Thousands of borrowers with scores in this range get approved every year by working with bad credit specialists who know which FHA lenders accept manual underwriting and how to present compensating factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
